<?xml version="1.0"?><response><status><![CDATA[200]]></status><status_message><![CDATA[OK]]></status_message><message><![CDATA[OK]]></message><objects><item><event_id><![CDATA[9462]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Alfred Drury And The New Sculpture]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[An exhibition exploring the art and life of Alfred Drury (1856-1944): His influences, his practice and his role in the 'New Sculpture' movement.

The Stanley & Audrey Burton Gallery are excited to be holding an exhibition dedicated to the art of Alfred Drury, one of the leading sculptors of the late Victorian and Edwardian periods, and creator of the much-talked-of bronze nude light standards in City Square, Leeds. The exhibition, curated by art historian Ben Thomas, tours to Leeds from The University of Kent's Studio 3 Gallery.

The exhibition will review the art and life of Alfred Drury RA (1856-1944), addressing the formative influences on his sculptural practice and his role in the New Sculpture movement of the late 19th and early 20th centuries. Included within the exhibition will be some of Drury's most important, smaller-scale, sculptural works, including his most characteristic masterpieces Griselda, The Age of Innocence and Lilith.

Drury was arguably one of the central figures in the New Sculpture movement because he combined in his art the realism of the great French sculptor Aime-Jules Dalou (1838-1902), with whom he had a long professional relationship, and the Michelangelo-esque vision of Alfred Stevens (1818-75), whose art he revered and whose drawings he collected.

Alongside sculptural works by Alfred Drury, the exhibition will display paintings and medals by the artist, and also documents and photographs from the period. The exhibition will also include works by Aime Jules Dalou, Auguste Rodin, Lord Leighton, and Alfred Stevens.

Alfred Drury and the New Sculpture will be on display at The Stanley & Audrey Burton Gallery from Wednesady 15th January to Sunday 13th April 2014. The gallery is open to the public, Monday - Friday, 10am - 5pm. Admission FREE.

This exhibition has been made possible with the kind support of grants from the Paul Mellon Centre for Studies in British Art, the Henry Moore Foundation and the Leeds Art Fund.

The exhibition will be accompanied by a full programme of related events, including the popular Burton Saturdays, free creative activities suitable for all ages. Full details can be found on our events pages.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4854]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Stanley & Audrey Burton Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1403]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Stanley & Audrey Burton Gallery]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[15 Jan 2014 - 12 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9462.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9462.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[3931]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Polychromies: Surface, Light and Colour]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Our refurbished sculpture galleries open with a fascinating display, Polychromies: Surface, Light and Colour, looking particularly atqualities of surface in bronze, marble and stonesculpture, highlighting embedded, applied, andreflected colour.

The Henry Moore Institute curates the Leeds Museums and Galleries' sculpture collection in partnership with Leeds Art Gallery. 

Image: George Meyrick,Maquette for Testing the Systems, 1991-1993. Courtesy of Leeds Museums and Galleries and the artist.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[150]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Art Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[924]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Museums & Galleries]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Nov 2012 - 1 May 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/3931_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/3931_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10099]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Grant Fleming: Hasta La Victoria! ]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[A photographic journey: the struggle for Central America,1988

You could no more describe Grant Fleming simply as "a photographer" any more than you could usefully describe any of the 120 countries he's worked in simply as "a place." If words could do these matters justice, we wouldn't need cameras. Some things resist easy description, as in this case does the person taking the pictures.

'HASTA LA VICTORIA!' is his first major exhibition and showcases images from his first overseas trip with a photographic objective - the upheaval in late 80's Central America via the southern states of the US.

Grant Fleming became politically active in the 80's after fortunately escaping a prison term after a number of collective 'misdemeanours' in his youth. He changed direction and turned to music, tour managing popular punk band Sham 69 at 18, was involved in the Mod Revival in the late 70's, then played bass guitar with the Chords and Lords of The New Church and toured the US until the group split. ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3679]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Outlaws Yacht Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7768]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Outlaws Yacht Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[6 Feb 2014 - 12 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10099.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10099.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10368]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[17th International Contemporary Artists' Book Fair]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The 17th International Contemporary Artists' Book Fair forms the core of PAGES, an ongoing project of interrelated events establishing critical engagement with the medium of the artists' book, encouraging production and awareness and establishing an arena for display and for exchange between audience and maker.

PAGES is pleased to announce its new partnership with The Tetley. With the past use and present structure of the building in mind, a series of exhibitions and installations are also in development alongside the fair, on the themes of archive and office, stationary and document, marginalia and cataloguing, and accumulations and inventories. The event will also incorporate a comprehensive series of discussions, lectures and forums during the Saturday and Sunday, and related exhibitions across the city. 

Highlights will include Image>Archive<Memory, an exhibition by British-Armenian artist Karen Babayan, with performances by London-based dancer Shakeh Major Tchilingirian, and a talk by Research Professor in Curation and Art History, Lynda Morris, at the Artists' Book Fair Dinner. See 'Events' pages for booking details. Stallholders at the Fair will include artists and publishers from around the UK, artists participating in A New Reality at The Tetley, Leeds-based collective Spur and Leeds' finest independent bookstore, Village.

PAGES 2014 Artists' Book Fair Participants

ABC artists book club / Alice Fox / Ambeck Design /AMBruno / Amelia Crouch /AP Books / Are we nearly there yet? / Art & Design, University of Leeds / Artistsbooksonline/ Batley School of Art, Fine Art for Design / Becoming Press / Cafe Royal Books / Camberwell College of Arts, MA Book Arts / Carla Moss / Charlotte Victoria Furness / Chris Taylor / David Barton /Ensixteen Editions /  Essence Press / Fine Art, University of Leeds / Filippa Dobson / Ghosts Publications / Incline Press / Interdisciplinary Art and Design, Leeds College Art / Jane Cradock-Watson / Jane Hyslop / Joan Ainley / Joanna Wilkinson /John Barrett / John McDowall / Karoline Rerrie / Kim Bevan / Kristine Steele / Leeds City College / Leeds College of Art: BA Visual Communication / Louise Atkinson / Mandy Brannan / Mr Smith / New Arcadian Press / Old Bear Press / PagePaperStitch / PAPER / Pat Hodson / Pink Parrot Press / PJB Editions / F. J. Ratchford Ltd. / Roncadora Press / Sandra Whyles / Shaeron Caton-Rose / Sheffield Hallam University MA Fine Art / and Guerrilla Writers / Stef Mitchell / Surrealist Editions / The Caseroom Press / Theresa Easton / Thomas Tomasska / University of Central Lancashire: Drawing and Image Making / Victoria Lucas / Weproductions / whnicPRESS / Wild Pansy Press / A New Reality artists and collaborators  (Joe Gilmore, Aidan Moesby and Nous Vous with Spur, Village Book Store and Catalogue)]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[7775]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Tetley ]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[7 Mar 2014 - 9 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10368_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10368_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[8847]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Rembrandt: Portraits & People]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Etchings from the Collection of Leeds Art Gallery.

This season's Winter/Spring exhibition at Temple Newsam House offers the rare chance to see a selection of prints made by the greatest printmaker the world has ever seen - Rembrandt Harmensz van Rijn (1606 - 1665).  The exhibition will run for nine months and will consist of two displays; the first will examine Rembrandt's portraits and figure studies and the second, will showcase a selection of Rembrandt's biblical prints.

Rembrandt's career as a printmaker ran parallel with his painting, but he rarely treated the same subject in both medium and only on a few occasions did he reproduce his paintings in print.  Indeed for Rembrandt, print was a distinct art form which he pursued as actively as he did his painting; quickly learning the technical skills involved in etching Rembrandt virtually recreated this technique.  His impact and contribution to printmaking is unprecedented and is so significant that it is still reflected in etchings produced today.

Portraits and People brings together Rembrandt's prints of people the first half to this exhibition will focus on his early experimental prints in which Rembrandt developed both his technique and his interest in showing emotion and thought through detailed observations of facial expressions. Highlights include a selection of Rembrandt's iconic self-portraits, etchings of his mother and wife Saskia, a group of Rembrandt's prints of beggars, and a selection of his later and more ambitious prints including 'Faust'. 

Image: Cropped self-portrait in cap and scarf with the face dark: bust, signed and dated Rembrandt f. 1633, Haarlem.  Second state of two, B17. Copyright: Leeds Museums and Galleries and licensed under Creative Commons BY NC SA.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[155]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Temple Newsam House and Estate]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7293]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Museums & Galleries]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[19 Nov 2013 - 30 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/8847.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/8847.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10528]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Jimi Hendrix Experience]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Gered Mankowitz is a British photographer of the rock music scene during the past 40 years. His exhibition - The Jimi Hendrix Experience - will be presented here at White Cloth Gallery during March and April.

Gered's photos were taken at a pivotal point in Jimi Hendrix's short career. These iconic portraits capture the mystery and otherworldliness defining his public image, just as Gered's 1965-67 portraits of the Rolling Stones defined them as the antithesis of the Beatles. This Hendrix exhibition gives a clear insight into the real Jimi relaxing upbeat, smiling and happy.

"Jimi was so positive and excited about what was happening to him. He was easy to work with and a pleasure to be around. Jimi was very shy and retiring, humble and modest. Not starry or assertive and that pretty well remained the case during the time that I knew him. There was a complete contrast between the man on stage and the man in person." Gered Mankowitz]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1544]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[White Cloth Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[6805]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[White Cloth Gallery]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[5 Mar 2014 - 13 May 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10528_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10528_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9979]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Our House]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Village Bookstore & Gallery and SPUR are proud to present OUR HOUSE.

Launching on Thursday 6th February at 6pm OUR HOUSE is a multi disciplinary exhibition curated by SPUR featuring artists from Leeds, London, America and The Netherlands creating a physical intervention that seeks to subliminally take control of the space.

Launching on the same night, SPUR'S second publication 'Collection Of'. The publication includes 13 editioned artist prints, a cassette, and a text based zine, featuring the work of local and international artists.

Artists in OUR HOUSE:
Alex Sickling (Newcastle)
Jeff Baij (Venice, California)
Mark Dorf (Louisville, Kentucky)
Jay Cover (London)
Greg Owen (Epping)
Lucy Sherston (Leeds)
Robert Tatton (Leeds)
Jack Piers Scott (UK)
Joel Coliver (London)
Charlotte Trounce (London)
Helmut Smits (Rotterdam, The Netherlands)
Karl Russel Vickers (Leeds)

Village Bookstore & Gallery is an independent book store and gallery based in Leeds, UK, specialising in self-published zines from artists based both in Yorkshire and worldwide. Spur is a Leeds based arts collective providing artist opportunities for local and international artists.

Balcony Level, The Corn Exchange, Call Lane, Leeds, West Yorkshire LS1 7BR]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[6170]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Village Bookstore]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[3779]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[SPUR]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[6 Feb 2014 - 6 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9979_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9979_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10533]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Her Place]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[For the first time Inkwell Arts has invited artists from around the globe; Australia, New York, the Philippines and the UK.  

Her Place includes art work from nine women artists:  Laura Wills (Au) depicts a woman's life journey of spirituality and belonging in her drawings on maps, Mary Pulford (Au) and Ronna Lara- Bes (Ph) delicately illustrate some of their native wildlife through printmaking and watercolour. Heidi Russell (USA) conveys the feeling of being both resident and tourist through a series of photographs of New York. Amanda Burton's (UK) work reflects her time in her homeland Malaysia, whilst Bridget Riversmith's (USA) work has a more internal response with figurative works, and Maureen Prichard's (AU) beautifully hand coloured photographs connect her with her artist Grandmother.  Julia Bickerstaff (UK) combines art and engineering in her Neon works and film buff Charlotte Brooke (UK) captures the zeitgeist of Hollywood with a series of photo realistic drawings.

The exhibition opening takes place on Saturday 8th March from 6pm - 8pm where you will have the opportunity to buy any of the beautiful artwork on show and meet some of the artists. Complimentary drinks and refreshments will be on offer. The exhibition runs until April 15th.

The special preview launch will be followed by the IWD poetry evening from 8 - 11pm. 

For more information and works from the exhibiting artists please visit their websites listed below.

http://www.maureenprichard.com.au/
www.laurawills.com.au
https://www.facebook.com/mary.pulford
http://ronnalarabes.blogspot.co.uk
http://wiremoon.co.uk/    (Amanda Burton)
http://www.neonunity.co.uk/ (Julia Bickerstaff)
http://www.heidirussell.com/
http://www.riversmithart.wordpress.com]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1614]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Inkwell]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1620]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Inkwell]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[8 Mar 2014 - 15 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10533.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10533.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9797]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Saturday Girl]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Saturday Girl is a series of portraits of young women in Leeds; specifically seen through their hairstyles.

It is an exploration of what hair means culturally and personally to young women and how they experience and use the power inherent in becoming visible as women. 

Saturday Girl is an exhibition and a series of events, including a film screening, talks and performance exploring the idea of beauty, power and visibility in relation to women. 

Full details of the events throughout the exhibition are detailed on our website www.leedsgallery.com]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[839]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[24 Feb 2014 - 31 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9797.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9797.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10360]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Monthly Pop-Up Exhibition]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Focusing on a specific discipline, Arts @ Trinity hosts a new monthly one day event, each culminating with an evening show.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1956]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Holy Trinity Church]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10359]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Arts @ Trinity]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[12 Mar 2014 - 13 Nov 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10360_1.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10360_1.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10336]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Lore Of The North]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[An exhibition by Lord Whitney.

'The moor was still, poised at this hour as if this extraordinary event had dispelled time...'

Lord Whitney's Lore of the North project presented in an exciting publication and exhibition, based on Yorkshire Folklore.

If you've missed the project, catch up here - http://loreofthenorth.tumblr.com/
www.lordwhitney.co.uk

Supported by Grants for the Arts and Leeds Inspired]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1782]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Munro House]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10330]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Lord Whitney]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Mar 2014 - 25 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10336.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10336.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9436]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Creative 10: 3D At Barkston Studios ]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Learn basic skills in drawing, plaster casting and sculpture using a variety of materials. You will look at different artists, who specialise in 3D, to explore your own ideas and take inspiration for creating work.

This course is suitable for beginners or those with some experience. 

Fee information: 
Free - if you are in receipt of any benefits or declare a health related issue
&pound;12 - If you are in receipt of a state pension
&pound;46 - Full course fee

Please get in touch if you would like more information.

If you would like to book a place or have any questions then please get in touch with Lotte on 0113 262 6633 (please leave a message if I'm out of the office) or email lotte@esamail.org.uk]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2510]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Barkston House]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[6932]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[East Street Arts]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[16 Jan 2014 - 27 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9436.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9436.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10162]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Overtime]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[SEIZE Leeds presents: OVERTIME : Art and the Office

Opening Night - Wednesday 26th March 7pm, All Welcome

Situated in Leeds' busy financial district, OVERTIME brings together a diverse group of both emerging and more established practitioners from across the country to explore the differences between the office and the artist's studio.

Often seen as a bureaucratic environment, offices are associated with systemized tasks, the management of data and pro rata salaries, but rarely unregulated creative play. This exhibition seeks to use the unexpected friction generated by placing the work of art in the office to interrogate fixed attitudes towards working practices more generally.

Participating artists & collectives are: 
Lily Ackroyd-Willoughby 
Mike Ainsworth 
Anachron-Gen 
Alice Bradshaw 
Lydia Catterall 
Spike Dennis 
Natalie Drenth 
Emma Hardaker 
Phill Hopkins 
Edward Hurst 
Luc Jones 
Ellie MacGarry 
Bess Martin 
Tom McGinn 
Emma Moody-Smith 
Julia Miorin 
Shanie Mor 
OFFCUT collaborative 
Leo Plumb 
Ned Pooler 
Stanley Quaia 
Alec Shepley 
Will Turner 
Philip Welding 
Matt Wheeldon

SEIZE Leeds is an artist-led organisation that works to engage and support emerging and mid-career artists both regionally and nationally through a programme of ambitious temporary art shows and events. SEIZE works with vacant spaces in-situ to produce exciting and accessible exhibitions that explore ideas relevant to each site and promote talent.

Partners:  &Model Gallery / BasementArtsProject]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[10161]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Wellington Park House]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[9360]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[SEIZE]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[26 Mar 2014 - 29 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10162_2.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10162_2.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10535]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Sodium Laureth Suplhate/The Gallery Is Now Closed]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Leeds based artists Fred Pepper and Helen Dryden are jointly exhibiting at private residence The Crooked House (in Burley, Leeds).

Helen's exhibition 'Sodium Laureth Sulphate' consists of mixed media paintings and a digital projection.

Her process is spontaneous and instinctive, using media such as acrylics on canvas, boards and cardboard; watercolours, felt tip pens, ribbons and gems. Using imagery from her subconscious, intuitive mark making, and reacting to found pictures and music, Helen creates an uncertain world, sometimes confusing, wondering, atmospheric and difficult to identify.

Fred's exhibition 'The Gallery Is Now Closed' features a display of his ongoing movie monster monoprint series, accompanied by a loop of the video-collage Wastin' Arrers and the sound piece Mr. Leech's Institution by Lynden St. John for Octopus Collective, for which the artist provided voice performance.

Fred Pepper works in an illustrative style and within a narrative tradition. His practice centres on drawing and printmaking, but he also makes forays into the territories of performance, sculpture, digital media and painting.
He was born a Sagittarius on a Woden's Day in a Year of the Wood Rabbit.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[10534]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Crooked House]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[27 Mar 2014 - 2 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10535.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10535.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[8430]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Look Into My World]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Be inspired by young people's artwork in the Gallery!

Groups of young people from ten schools across Leeds were inspired by the Anthony Browne illustration exhibition at Leeds City Museum in 2013. They worked with an artist and responded in their own way to Anthony's work and to the works at Leeds Art Gallery. Come and have a look at the fabulous works they produced!

Six primary schools and four secondary schools were involved in the project from September 2013, and each of the ten schools has hosted an exhibition of all the students work in their school or local community. The young artists worked with curators and learning staff from the Gallery to talk about curatorship and the young people then selected the works you see on display at the Gallery to represent their school.

Been inspired? Want to be involved in creating artworks, or find out more? Contact Leeds Art Gallery on city.art.gallery@leeds.gov.uk]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[150]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Art Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[924]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Museums & Galleries]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[2 Apr 2014 - 1 Jun 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/8430.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/8430.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10027]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Thomas Houseago]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Leeds-born artist Thomas Houseago is today one of the most internationally influential sculptors of his generation.

The Yorkshire Sculpture Triangle, a partnership between four locally rooted world-class sculpture organisations (Henry Moore Institute, Leeds Art Gallery, The Hepworth Wakefield and the Yorkshire Sculpture Park) brings two of Thomas Haseago's sculptures to Yorkshire - a monumental new commission made specifically for Leeds city centre and one located at Yorkshire Sculpture Park.

The Los Angeles-based sculptor grew up in Leeds and is considered to be one of the most distinctive voices in contemporary art today. While his work has been shown globally, this is the first major commission in Yorkshire, a region that boasts a unique artistic legacy as the birthplace of Barbara Hepworth and Henry Moore. Drawing on references ranging from Greek mythology, Darth Vader, Moore and Hepworth and the Incredible Hulk, Houseago's giant figures are concerned with volume, gravity and scale. 

Outside Leeds Art Gallery stands a new sculpture by Houseago, made specifically for the occasion of the Yorkshire Festival 2014 and inspired by the city of Leeds. Caught in arrested motion, this gargantuan striding figure moves unrelentingly forward. Sited right on the Headrow, the sculpture alludes to the frenetic bustle of the surrounding urban landscape. With its rough finish, Houseago's figure contains the feeling of energy which the artist senses in the city. Within the grounds of Yorkshire Sculpture Park is another of Houseago's sculptures, an owl's head cast in bronze on a redwood plinth, reflecting the artist's interest in natural forms and forces and echoing the symbol of Leeds.   

This ambitious project to bring Thomas Houseago back from the US to his birthplace in Yorkshire has been developed by the Yorkshire Sculpture Triangle and realised with the support of the 2014 Grand Depart Cultural Festival and Leeds and Wakefield City Councils.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[150]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Art Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7293]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Museums & Galleries]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[30 Apr 2014 - 6 Jul 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10027.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10027.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10194]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Leeds International Tattoo Exposition]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Leeds International Tattoo Exposition (LITE) will be taking place at The New Dock Hall (part of the world famous Royal Armouries).

We have access to some truly inspirational international tattoo artists (please keep your eyes on the website (right) for artist announcements). We are also holding a huge alternative market under a heated, weather proof marquee out on the plaza, art exhibitions and an awesome after party including bands, DJs and other performances!

www.leedstattooexpo.com
www.instagram.com/leedstattooexpo
www.twitter.com/leedstattooexpo]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[10192]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[New Dock Hall]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10193]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds International Tattoo Exposition]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[24 May 2014 - 25 May 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10194.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10194.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10107]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Claude Cahun]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Claude Cahun (1894-1954) is best known for her riveting photographic self-portraits, that seem at least half a century ahead of their time where she acted out diverse identities both male and female in scenes that range from starkly minimal to the elaborately staged. She has inspired an almost cultish devotion among those who know her art. Cahun pioneered many of the concerns of contemporary artists like Cindy Sherman, who was born the year Cahun died. Cahun was born in France and was an avid participant in the cultural avant garde of Montparnasse in the 1920s and 30s mingling with many of the leading artists of her day, she eventually moved to Jersey, in the Channel Isles where she was imprisoned during the Nazi occupation. Exhibition organised in collaboration with Jersey Heritage Trust]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[150]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Art Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7293]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Museums & Galleries]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[6 Jun 2014 - 7 Sep 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10107.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10107.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[5444]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Willow Deer Weaving With Phil Bradley]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[We are very excited to be hosting a workshop run by Phil Bradley, willow weaver and basket maker extraordinaire! 

Phil will guide you through the process of making a lovely Deer sculpture to take home. You don't need to have done any willow weaving before, and all materials needed will be provided for you.  Early booking is recommended as Phil's workshops are always very popular. Please visit our website to make a booking.

Feedback from a previous participant "A wonderfully creative and relaxing day in great company in a beautiful eco centre and natural environment. My willow hare now stands proudly in my garden - making me smile every morning when I look out! Thank you so much Phil and the welcoming team at Skelton Grange - when is the next course??!!"

When not teaching, creating, demonstrating or weaving baskets, Phil manages and harvests his own organic willowbeds in Cumbria.

Plentiful tea, coffee and soft drinks provided, but please do bring your own lunch!]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[5420]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Skelton Grange Environment Centre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5423]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Skelton Grange]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[11 Sep 2014 10:00am - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/5444_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/5444_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10268]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Thoughtbubble Festival]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[This year's festival runs from 9th - 16th November in association with the 28th Leeds International Film Festival, with our centre-piece convention taking place on 15th & 16th November....

We'll have further updates regarding ticket pre-sales opening, and exhibitor registration for the convention will be posted to Facebook as soon as all the details are confirmed.

The first wave of guests for the 2014 festival, include:

Natasha Allegri (creator of Bee & Puppycat, and writer/illustrator of the Adventure Time: Fionna & Cake comics);

Andy Belanger (creator of Black Church, and artist on IDW's hit series Kill Shakespeare);

Emily Carroll (award-winning webcomic creator, whose work has featured in Vertigo's The Witching Hour and Dark Horse's Creepy);

Becky Cloonan (artist on Dark Horse's The True Lives of the Fabulous Killjoys, and recently self-published Demeter);

Danielle Corsetto (creator of webcomic Girls With Slingshots, and the Adventure Time graphic novels Playing With Fire and Pixel Princesses);

Adam Hughes (award-winning cover artist for titles such as DC's Wonder Woman, Fairest, Catwoman, and Power Girl);

Jeff Lemire (creator of acclaimed series Essex County, The Underwater Welder, Sweet Tooth, and Trillium);

Matteo Scalera (artist on Image's Dead Body Road and Black Science, and Marvel's Secret Avengers and The Incredible Hulk);

Scott Snyder (creator of Vertigo's American Vampire and The Wake, and writer on DC's Batman and Superman Unchained);

Allison Sohn (artist on trading and sketch cards for Star Wars, LotR, Indiana Jones, and Women of Marvel, cover artist for Dynamite Comic's Red Sonja);

Jillian Tamaki (creator of webcomic Supermutant Magic Academy, graphic novels Gilded Lilies, Indoor Voice, and co-creator of Skim and This One Summer);

We'll have many more guests to announce in the coming months, so keep an eye on the website as the festival draws ever closer!

The official festival image for this year is by the awesome Annie Wu, and we love the 1920's vibe she's brought to it. Even ghostly apparitions reading over your shoulder can't spoil a good comic!

We're working hard to make this year's Thought Bubble even bigger and better than those that came before it, and we hope you'll join us in celebrating the best creative medium in the whole dang world come November!]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[797]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Various Locations]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[2737]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Thought Bubble Comic Art Festival]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[9 Nov 2014 - 16 Nov 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10268.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10268.jpg]]></image_original></item></objects></response>