<?xml version="1.0"?><response><status><![CDATA[200]]></status><status_message><![CDATA[OK]]></status_message><message><![CDATA[OK]]></message><objects><item><event_id><![CDATA[9921]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Lucy Suggate Morning Class]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Lucy Suggate
Give Us Our Daily Dance

"Five years ago I became interested in developing a daily practice to support and maintain training and help elevate my performance and choreographic work. So I set myself the task of dancing everyday, when I say dancing I mean it in the truest sense. Unleashing an internal force, re-connecting with the feelings and ideas that encouraged me to dance in the first place.

"The class will consist of guided exercises,  departure points and lots of flamboyant dancing. We will cultivate a playground of possibilities, discover new forms that collide and stretch our limitations."

Part of Yorkshire Dance's Juncture; a festival of contemporary movement, theatre and film work curated by Wendy Houstoun.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[321]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Yorkshire Dance]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[2258]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Yorkshire Dance]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[9 Mar 2014 9:45am - 10:45am]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9921.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9921.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9800]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Drawing And Painting]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The course will help improve or refresh both your drawing and painting techniques. The focus to the 6 weeks differs for each course, exploring artists, movements and current exhibitions.

In general terms the emphasis for drawing will be learning to 'look' with a series of drawing exercises in measurement, proportions, compositions and shade and tone.

Acrylic paints will be used as our painting medium.

# BYOB (bring your own baby) parents can bring along their baby up to 8 months old]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2074]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Bowery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[24 Feb 2014 - 31 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9800.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9800.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9924]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Robert M Hayden Workshop]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Robert M. Hayden's Sifting focuses on the body as a 'total instrument', capable of what can be called the 'total act', working on physical actions, movement as theatrical act, and the voice.

A series of physical exercises will establish a strong, vital body-breath connection, unlocking the flow of living impulses within the body, allowing our attention, intention and awareness to flow more freely.

Specific 'impossible' tasks will allow our inner 'obstacles' to become more transparent. Dealing with the element of physical risk or danger, these tasks emphasize our apparent limitations and give us the chance to go beyond them.

We will compositionally combine movement, voice and text to develop our own individual 'score' within which to work. We will focus on relationships between precision and organicity, awareness of space and one's ability to react to its constituent elements, improvisation within a structure as well as dramaturgical elaboration.

By harnessing creative energy in a more present, active and alive manner, the act of creating can then develop within a more structured or compositional frame. Participants will be asked to create a score of actions between 3-5 minutes in length with a clear beginning, middle and end. We will be focusing on its logic, actions, intentions, meaning and content.

This workshop is open to both amateur and professional performers, pedagogues and directors.

Part of Yorkshire Dance's Juncture; a festival of contemporary movement, theatre and film work curated by Wendy Houstoun.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[321]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Yorkshire Dance]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[2258]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Yorkshire Dance]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[10 Mar 2014 - 14 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9924.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9924.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[5982]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Yoga - Stretch Out And Tone Up]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Yoga in the city centre for everyone; from beginners to yoga boffins. All equipment is provided, just bring yourself! 

Ashtanga yoga is a powerful form of yoga which improves flexibility and strength, whilst relaxing the mind.

Get fit, flexible and even more fabulous. Be a hero!

Any questions? No problem - just email holly@yogahero.co.uk]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[9270]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Lambert's Yard]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Jan 2014 - 28 May 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/5982.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/5982.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10020]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[365 Leeds Stories Choir]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Would you like to sing songs about Leeds?

We are looking for people who enjoy singing to take part in a 10 week choir project. No experience is necessary but enthusiasm is essential!

There are many things we take for granted about the place we live in - and what is familiar to one person may be surprising to someone else. 365 Leeds Stories is a way of sharing our experience of the city in a creative and informal way.

Since September 2013, Leeds-based artists Matthew Bellwood and Alison Andrews have been working together with a range of people who live, work or seek residence in Leeds on the creation of series of maps of the city; maps that tell stories and make connections between the people who live there. They have been rendered in different forms - expressed in textiles, written in stories, floated down the river or rendered as conventional cartographic representations, albeit with a twist.

In November and December, we ran two day-long workshops with composer James Redwood. These were open to anyone in the city who wanted to come along and join in. We spent the first day getting to know each other and sharing ideas, thoughts, feelings and impressions of the city, before settling down to write some lyrics that we felt summed up our experiences of living in Leeds. The material we created was quite diverse - quirky, poetic and sometimes slightly sinister. By the end of the first day, we felt we had the basis for three different songs.

The following week, we worked with James to set the songs to music. James led us in a series of warm-ups, which got us on our feet and singing together and then helped us to find our way into the songs, deciding on a tone and mood for each one, pulling out melodies and rhythms from the group and shaping the resultant material. He then took the pieces away with him to polish up and score.

From 24th February onwards, we'll be working with vocal animateur Caroline Challis to bring these songs to life, with a view to singing them at the opening of the project exhibition in Leeds Central Library on 3rd May.

Rehearsals will be at the Central Library on Monday evenings (6.15pm - 7.45pm) from 24th February.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[476]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Central Library]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10019]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[365 Leeds Stories]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[24 Feb 2014 - 28 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10020.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10020.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9374]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Complete Beginners Taichi Course]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Start the spring by detoxing your body, de -stressing your mind and revitalising your spirit.  Lishi Taichi's friendly instructors offer you  ancient Chinese Daoist exercises to find inner peace, relax and be re-energised on the hunt for your Qi. Turn up and let your worries and distractions slip away into oblivion.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3932]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Wrangthorn Church Hall]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[10 Feb 2014 - 14 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9374.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9374.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9782]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Life Drawing ]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Working directly from a life model, the course will introduce you to a variety of drawing approaches. You will focus on observational skills, proportions of the body and composition. With regards to technique you will use a range of materials from acrylics and watercolour to charcoal and oil pastels.

Throughout the course inspiration will be sought from the work and practice of other artists. For those more experienced individual tasks will be set according to needs.

All materials and equipment are provided.

6 weeks &pound;90]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2074]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Bowery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[24 Feb 2014 - 31 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9782.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9782.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9932]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Argentine Tango Mondays]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Weekly Argentinian Tango classes and social. 

7pm-8pm beginners class
8pm-9pm improvers class
9pm-11pm social / milonga]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[9930]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[New Burley Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[9931]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Tango Yorkshire]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[27 Jan 2014 - 26 May 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9932.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9932.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9794]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Sewing - Fashion/Interiors/Accessories]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Beginners will start by making a pair of simple cushions. This initial project will equip you in the basics of patterns cutting and familiarise you with the operation of using a sewing machine. From here you can choose from a variety of projects like a simple skirt or tote bag. For the more experienced, there are a number of projects depending on skills, you can choose from a lined dress to a more complicated blouse. 

The emphasis is on making garments that fit by learning how to alter and grade patterns. For those wanting to concentrate on interiors or accessories you can make blinds, curtains, clutch bags and more.

All equipment is provided. 
You will need to bring your own material and other bits and bobs for individual projects

No fabric is required for the first session

# BYOB (bring your own baby) parents can bring along their baby up to 8 months old]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2074]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Bowery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[25 Feb 2014 - 1 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9794.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9794.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9795]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Sewing - Fashion/Interiors/Accessories]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Beginners will start by making a pair of simple cushions. This initial project will equip you in the basics of patterns cutting and familiarise you with the operation of using a sewing machine. From here you can choose from a variety of projects like a simple skirt or tote bag. For the more experienced, there are a number of projects depending on skills, you can choose from a lined dress to a more complicated blouse. 

The emphasis is on making garments that fit by learning how to alter and grade patterns. For those wanting to concentrate on interiors or accessories you can make blinds, curtains, clutch bags and more.

All equipment is provided. 
You will need to bring your own material and other bits and bobs for individual projects

No fabric is required for the first session

# BYOB (bring your own baby) parents can bring along their baby up to 8 months old]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2074]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Bowery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[25 Feb 2014 - 1 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9795.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9795.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9907]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Creative Contemporary Dance]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[A weekly drop-in class for adults 18+ who want to dance for fun and develop physical confidence and technique. In a relaxed studio space, the classes will offer the opportunity to engage your body and imagination to explore wider ranges of movement, body awareness and creativity.

The sessions are lead by three different teachers; Rosemary Spencer, Vanessa Grasse and Kim Glassby. Between them they have wealth of experience and a variety of dance styles to draw on. Every session is different and like a 'mini workshop'. All levels of dance experience welcome. 

Please wear comfortable clothing to move in & bare feet/soft indoor shoes
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[458]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Dance Studio Leeds]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[14 Jan 2014 - 8 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9907.png]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9907.png]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10536]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Interested In Queer Culture?]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Come and join a new group which will explore Queer Culture at Leeds Art Gallery.

This group will meet in the Art Gallery each Thursday and explore visual arts from a different perspective.  Everyone is welcome, whether you are new to the subject or if you are already involved in queer cultural projects.  Participants will explore visual arts, gallery performance and the collection with a queer eye and mind but we are also interested in including all other art forms.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[150]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Art Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7293]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Museums & Galleries]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[11 Mar 2014 - 10 Jun 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10536.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10536.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9684]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Oasis Project]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The Oasis Project is a partnership project between Artlink West Yorkshire and Leeds Jewish Welfare Board.

This free project is open to adult unpaid carers across Leeds and is an opportunity to work with professional artists Bryony Pritchard and Becky Cherriman.

A non-faith based project, open to all abilities.

Across the 11 weeks you will be able to experiment with creative writing, storytelling, movement, set design and more.  This will be a space to make time for yourself and to meet other people.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[9683]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Marjorie & Arnold Ziff Building]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[6383]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Artlink West Yorkshire]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[18 Feb 2014 - 20 May 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9684.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9684.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9772]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Printing For Beginners]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[This course will provide a general overview of printmaking with a focus on learning simple printing techniques that you can do at home. We will explore various methods within these three areas of print, silk screen, relief and mono type. Once you have the basics, you can choose to develop or two methods further to create a collection of paper prints.

All equipment is provided.

Materials are provided for students to practice on, but for final pieces, good quality artist's papers and print 

Plate materials can be bought from the tutor.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2074]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Bowery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[25 Feb 2014 - 1 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9772.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9772.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9792]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Digital SLR Photography]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[This course is suitable for beginners and those who want to refresh their knowledge and skills. The course will take you through the basics of how to use your camera on it's manual settings, looking at exposure and shutter speed and other vital settings to help you gain more control of your photography.

The tutor will take you through different genres of photography and set you projects to work on within the class and at home. You can interpret the projects as you wish, making every ones images personal and unique. initial projects focus on composition, framing and portraits.

You will need to bring you own digital slr camera
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2074]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Bowery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[25 Feb 2014 - 1 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9792.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9792.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10025]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Woolly Bike Trail Workshop]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Cassandra Kilbride is a prolific yarn-stormer. Her crocheted street art makes cheeky visual statements that offer a new reading of the towns and cities we travel through and the monuments and street furniture we pass by. For the Grand Depart, Cassandra is creating ten woolly bikes for a year-long trail connecting ten towns with the many knitters, crocheters and yarn-stormers that have taken part.

Drawing inspiration from iconic Yorkshire themes including the landscape of the Dales, Yorkshire's textile mills, literary heroines and heroes, and the iconic flat cap, each bike gets a woolly makeover using local yarn. Most of the yarn is the produce of Yorkshire sheep, but one special batch comes from a collection of reclaimed saris. The transformed knitted vehicles will go on display in Sheffield this July, before they take up individual positions along the trail route.  

Workshops take place between January and June at festivals and venues across the region and are open to anyone with a basic ability of crocheting.  ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[395]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[West Yorkshire Playhouse]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[12 Mar 2014 - 19 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10025.png]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10025.png]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9435]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Creative 10:  Art And Design At Union105]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[A 10 week general art and design course that will help you develop a range of creative skills using a specific theme as a starting point for making work and exploring your own ideas. 

This course is suitable for beginners or those with some experience. 

Fee information: 
Free - if you are in receipt of any benefits or declare a health related issue
&pound;12 - If you are in receipt of a state pension
&pound;46 - Full course fee

Please get in touch if you would like more information.

If you would like to book a place or have any questions then please get in touch with Lotte on 0113 262 6633 (please leave a message if I'm out of the office) or email lotte@esamail.org.uk]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4020]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Union 105 Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[6932]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[East Street Arts]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[15 Jan 2014 - 26 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9435.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9435.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9780]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Ceramics For Beginners]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[During this six week course you will be taught basic ceramic techniques of coiling, press moulding and slab building as well as basic decorative techniques. The skills learnt will give you 
the confidence to apply and develop them independently to create unique and desirable objects.

This class would be most suited to complete beginners with a passion to learn about the versatility of clay. 

All equipment is provided
All materials are provided to complete the initial skills building project. 

(Additional projects would incur an additional cost for clay & firing)

]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2074]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Bowery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[26 Feb 2014 - 2 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9780.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9780.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9781]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Sewing - Fashion/Interiors/Accessories]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Beginners will start by making a pair of simple cushions. This initial project will equip you in the basics of patterns cutting and familiarise you with the operation of using a sewing machine. From here you can choose from a variety of projects like a simple skirt or tote bag. For the more experienced, there are a number of projects depending on skills, you can choose from a lined dress to a more complicated blouse. 

The emphasis is on making garments that fit by learning how to alter and grade patterns. For those wanting to concentrate on interiors or accessories you can make blinds, curtains, clutch bags and more.

All equipment is provided. 
You will need to bring your own material and other bits and bobs for individual projects

No fabric is required for the first session]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2074]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Bowery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[26 Feb 2014 - 2 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9781.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9781.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9436]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Creative 10: 3D At Barkston Studios ]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Learn basic skills in drawing, plaster casting and sculpture using a variety of materials. You will look at different artists, who specialise in 3D, to explore your own ideas and take inspiration for creating work.

This course is suitable for beginners or those with some experience. 

Fee information: 
Free - if you are in receipt of any benefits or declare a health related issue
&pound;12 - If you are in receipt of a state pension
&pound;46 - Full course fee

Please get in touch if you would like more information.

If you would like to book a place or have any questions then please get in touch with Lotte on 0113 262 6633 (please leave a message if I'm out of the office) or email lotte@esamail.org.uk]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2510]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Barkston House]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[6932]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[East Street Arts]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[16 Jan 2014 - 27 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9436.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9436.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9745]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Hand Embroidery]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Learn decorative hand embroidery stitches to design and make your own stitch sampler and picture to use at home.

Led by local maker Karen Lewis of Blueberry Park.

All materials and equipment provided, as well as refreshments.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3985]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Chirpy]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[3986]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Chirpy]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Mar 2014 7:00pm - 9:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9745.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9745.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9783]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Traditional Re Upholstery]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[This is an introduction into traditional and contemporary re-upholstery techniques. Using the upholstery tools provided you will strip down your chair or stool, insert new padding or waddings, re webb and even re spring your article. We will also look at top covers and where you can source up to date and exciting fabrics. 

If the wood needs a re-vamp the tutor can show you the basics of furniture restoration

All equipment is provided.

Materials necessary for completing your project will need to be purchased from the tutor.

A small dining room chair or foot stool is needed on the first session. unfortunately due to size of classroom and limited storage, please do not bring larger items to work on. Items need to be small enough to be carried up 1 flight of stairs and be taken home at the end of each session. 

&pound;90 for 6 weeks
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2074]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Bowery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[27 Feb 2014 - 3 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9783.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9783.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9793]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Sewing - Fashion/Interiors/Accessories]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Beginners will start by making a pair of simple cushions. This initial project will equip you in the basics of patterns cutting and familiarise you with the operation of using a sewing machine. From here you can choose from a variety of projects like a simple skirt or tote bag. For the more experienced, there are a number of projects depending on skills, you can choose from a lined dress to a more complicated blouse. 

The emphasis is on making garments that fit by learning how to alter and grade patterns. For those wanting to concentrate on interiors or accessories you can make blinds, curtains, clutch bags and more.

All equipment is provided. 
You will need to bring your own material and other bits and bobs for individual projects

No fabric is required for the first session]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2074]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Bowery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[27 Feb 2014 - 3 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9793.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9793.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10253]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Me Time]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Me Time is an artist-led arts group for adults of any ability and experience.

Come along and explore materials to create and make work in a supportive environment with like minded people.

All sessions are run in a fully equipped studio by artist, Sarah-Jane Mason.

]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3722]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[ArtBug Studio]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10254]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Sarah-Jane Mason]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[6 Mar 2014 - 31 Jul 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10253.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10253.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9057]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Sportivate: Skelton Grange Green Team]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Taster opportunties - get active and involved in the outdoors!

Want to get involved in practical phyical activity, learn new skills, get fitter, and do something that makes a difference to your local environment? 

We'll be learning new skills around the Skelton Grange site including hard and soft landscaping of the new 'megapond' area, plus traditional hedge laying techniques and there will also chances to get involved in the food growing area and fruit orchard at the centre. 

On Friday the 21st of February 2014 there will also be a guided cycle ride happening to the centre - to help people find their way to us. Meet by the White Pedestrian Bridge over the river by the Royal Armories at 9:15am ready for a 9:30 departure to follow the canal side Trans Pennine Trail route to Skelton Grange Environment Centre. Its about a 15-20 minute cycle ride, but traffic free almost all the way - so its a great way to get to know the way to Skelton Grange.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[5420]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Skelton Grange Environment Centre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5423]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Skelton Grange]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[21 Feb 2014 - 28 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9057_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9057_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9791]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Traditional Reupholstery]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[This is an introduction into traditional and contemporary re-upholstery techniques. Using the upholstery tools provided you will strip down your chair or stool, insert new padding or waddings, re webb and even re spring your article. We will also look at top covers and where you can source up to date and exciting fabrics. 

If the wood needs a re-vamp the tutor can show you the basics of furniture restoration

All equipment is provided.

Materials necessary for completing your project will need to be purchased from the tutor.

A small dining room chair or foot stool is needed on the first session. unfortunately due to size of classroom and limited storage, please do not bring larger items to work on. Items need to be small enough to be carried up 1 flight of stairs and be taken home at the end of each session. 
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2074]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Bowery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[28 Feb 2014 - 4 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9791.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9791.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[7981]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Lindy Fridays]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Learn Swing Dancing in a fun relaxed environment at the Carriageworks in Millenium Square every Friday. Swing dancing is awesome social dancing from the 20s-50s focussing on fun and giving you cool moves, and with no lycra or sequins in sight!

Intermediates at 7
Beginners at 8pm (beginners are INCREDIBLY 
WELCOME)

These are drop-in classes and we will go through the basics every week so you can join in any time. 

No partner required, wear comfy clothes and flat shoes.

Find out more by liking the facebook page Lindy Fridays or at lindyfridays.com]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[304]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Carriageworks Theatre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[6 Sep 2013 - 1 Aug 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/7981.png]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/7981.png]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[8639]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Narrative Drive: Jacob Ross]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[INSCRIBE Masterclass series.

Three monthly sessions. The series offers a compact survey of Jacob Ross' immensely popular and highly regarded technical creative approach to crafting fiction. His very successful course has been running for more than fifteen years. Many beginning writers developed and fine-tuned their writing skills in his course, to the point where their work has been shortlisted in major competitions, or won prizes.

Narrative Drive is for writers who want to maximise the quality and impact of their work. At the end of the series you will have a better awareness of your own strengths and weakness as a writer and the steps you need to take to address them. We will examine the building blocks of stories and how they work together to produce strong memorable narratives.

The series will expose you to the very best examples of modern fiction from which you can learn and refine your skills. Your knowledge of contemporary themes and styles will be enhanced. This course is for advanced writers already working on their novel-in-progress or their collection of short stories. You will be required to submit work in advance of the course.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[8638]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[TBC]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1638]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[INSCRIBE & Peepal Tree Press]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[18 Jan 2014 - 15 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/8639.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/8639.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10494]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Matt Roberts Arts: Open Forum 2014]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The aim of Open Forum 2014 is to allow Matt Roberts Arts to use their experience to provide advice to artists in regions where the commercial sector is developing and less visible.

In the evening there will be a panel discussion between Matt Roberts, Chris Yeats, and Leeds based artists groups &Model and blip blip blip. The discussion will be about opportunities to show your work, sell your work, and ways in which the sector is changing.

Please visit the website to book your place: http://eaststreetarts.org.uk/projects/matt-roberts-arts-open-forum-2014/



Further Information:

Matt Roberts Arts is a not-for-profit organisation founded in 2006 to create opportunities for artists in new locations and contexts. Matt Roberts Arts offers support to creative practitioners through regular lectures, workshops and national and touring exhibitions.

Vane represents the work of a number of artists, both from across the UK and internationally, as well as showing the work of invited artists in collaboration with other galleries. Vane was founded in 1997 in Newcastle upon Tyne in the North East of England. The gallery directors are Paul Stone and Christopher Yeats.

&Model is a gallery space in central Leeds. Occupying all three floors of a 19th century building on East Parade, it shows contemporary visual art and other work that crosses the genres of art and design. It brings a diverse range of international artists to Leeds whilst also showcasing some of the city's best young talent. &Model's co-directors are Chris Bloor, James Chinneck and Derek Horton.

blip blip blip is an exhibitions programme committed to examining and fostering relationships between contemporary art practice and art education. Art students are involved in the running of the programme from installing and invigilating shows to helping realise works. Since 2013, blip blip blip has been hosted at East Street Arts.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[8631]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Patrick Studios]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10493]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[East Street Arts]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[15 Mar 2014 6:30pm - 8:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10494.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10494.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[1863]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Make A Basic Pair Of Trousers]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Using your own machine

You will learn how to cut a trouser pattern, make pockets and a fly front fastening

Please note this is not a beginners class and you will need to know how to use your machine and have some  experience of cutting out, sewing seams, zips etc and basic garment making

Please note all our classes need to be prebooked.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4404]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Fabrication Crafts Limited]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1430]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Fabrication Crafts Ltd]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[16 Mar 2014 10:30am - 5:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/1863.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/1863.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9746]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Felt Flower Brooch Workshop]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Create an attractive felted flower brooch using the wet felt method. 

You will make a felted flower and embellish with beads, buttons and threads.  

Only thing to bring is an old towel.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3985]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Chirpy]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[3986]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Chirpy]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[20 Mar 2014 6:30pm - 9:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9746.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9746.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10550]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Card & Letter Writing To People In Detention & Prison]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Writing letters and making cards is a simple and fun way to show solidarity to people in prison or detention centres. 

Materials provided but bring along any stationery (and/or stamps) if you can.

There will be delicious hot vegan food.

Being in detention or prison is incredibly isolating. People are often held in detention indefinitely and it is incredibly hard to stay positive and strong. Getting a little message of hope and friendship can mean so much.

All welcome!

]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1603]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Wharf Chambers]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10545]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds No Borders]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[20 Mar 2014 8:00pm - 9:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10550.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10550.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10552]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Immigration Bill: Know Your Rights]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The proposed Immigration Bill - which is not yet law - is essentially a new attempt to try and introduce ID cards to the UK. It will have massive implications for:

anyone applying for asylum
international students
anyone needing hospital treatment
anyone trying to rent a house, open a bank account or get a driving licence will have to show proof of their immigration status.
anyone who doesn't look 'British'

It is an attempt to legalise the harassment witnessed last summer with the hateful 'go home' campaign and the stop checks in London. 

Speakers will outline key changes to:

access to NHS
stop & search powers
housing, bank accounts, driving licence
asylum, bail, appeals
international students

Followed by workshops on how to challenge this racist law.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[9355]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Bangladesh Centre Leeds]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10545]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds No Borders]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[22 Mar 2014 2:00pm - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10552_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10552_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10596]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Surviving The Publishers]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Published author Alison Taft will lead a two hour workshop on how to put together the perfect submission package in order to sell your work to agents, publishers (and the general public). 

We will look at how to write a gripping synopsis as well as how to craft the perfect biography before submitting your work. We will also examine self publication options and there will be ample opportunity to ask questions.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2074]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Bowery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[6703]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Headingley LitFest]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[22 Mar 2014 3:00pm - 5:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10596.JPG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10596.JPG]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9945]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Create a Vision Board]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[... for the next chapter of your life.

Before you set out on a journey it helps to know where you're going. If not, you're going to end up SOMEWHERE . . . just not where you want to be.

What if your elusive dreams took shape before your eyes? What would you discover? What could you then bring into your life for real?

Vision boards are a fabulous technique for focussing our energy and commitment on what's important. Then we get to have more of it in our lives. Pictures, words, photos, lines from poems, colour - they all help to create a powerful reminder of what you want in your future.

Making them in a workshop is fun, playful, stress free and collaborative. You get to share ideas and tell other people about yours. That's the added extra of doing this with others - you get to say it out loud as well.

"I don't want to get to the end of my life and find that I lived just the length of it. I want to have lived the width of it as well." Diane Ackerman

This workshop will suit anyone who is
- Seeking a different way to approach the new year.
- Wanting to look at your life as a whole and create greater fulfilment and richness in it.
- Has an idea for a specific project you want to create (and maybe you keep putting it on the back burner).
- Planning something big like a wedding, new business idea or retirement.

This special workshop retreat is for a maximum of 6 people, book early to be sure you're one of them. How about booking a place with your partner and creating a shared vision for your future.

During the workshop you'll
- Plug into the power of your dreams.
- Get in contact with your wisest inner self and use that inner knowing to create your vision from.
- Be coached to explore that vision so it becomes richer and more vibrant.
- Create your own vision board using a collage of images, words and colour.
- Talk about the significance of the elements of your vision so you get to hear yourself claim it out loud.
- Plan how you're going to use your board to keep focussed on what's important to you.
- Spend a day in a warm, cosy home, eat well, share laughter and have some playful fun cutting out!

" My partner and I did this course with Tilla - this weekend we have a romantic retreat by the sea to complete our shared vision board!"   Helen Collier, Money Coach HarmoneyLife

All you need is comfy clothes, a desire to create your own life and an open mind. The desire to have that fun will also come in useful! This is Blue Peter for adults!

I'll provide all the materials, and if you want to bring along old magazines to share around that'll be great.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[7008]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[5 Wensley Grove]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4308]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Tilla Brook]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[23 Mar 2014 9:30am - 4:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9945.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9945.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9784]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Introduction To Millinery: Make A Cocktail Hat ]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[A fun, one-day workshop with milliner Claire Spooner, who will show you some basic techniques as you hand-block and hand-sew your own fabulous little vintage-style cocktail hat.

We will make a mini hat-base using wooden blocks and steam-irons, cover it with fabric and trim with material, veiling and feathers.

No experience required and all materials provided.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4404]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Fabrication Crafts Limited]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1430]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Fabrication Crafts Ltd]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[23 Mar 2014 10:30am - 5:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9784.JPG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9784.JPG]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10075]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Crow_Sourcing Workshops]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Crow_Sourcing by Andy Deck, featured in the Digital Zoo exhibition, is an installation that calls attention to the echoes of the wild in language. Andy invites audiences to help build a collection of their favourite animal idioms and expressions using social media and an installation.
 
To accompany Crow_Sourcing, a series of 60-90 minute creative, fun workshops will feature across three days. Children aged between 6 and 11 years old are invited to explore art, technology and nature. 
 
In groups, the children will be able to create absurd and unusual creatures using craft materials and stencils, record animal sound bites, and explore language to describe their creatures, making funny and nonsensical names for them. They can then take their creations home or display at the venue.
 
Crow_Sourcing is part of Digital Zoo - Life from the world wild web, London's Furtherfield and CultureCode's groundbreaking national touring exhibition at Trinity Leeds shopping centre.
 
Digital Zoo is supported by Arts Council England through the Strategic Touring programme.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[5976]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Trinity Leeds ]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[2277]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Trinity Leeds Ltd]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[15 Feb 2014 - 23 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10075.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10075.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9679]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Little Voices, Opera North]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Little Voices is a series of fun, 45 minute workshops, where adults, tots and babies can be creative together in a friendly environment.  You'll have the chance to sing songs, explore instruments, play games and generally have fun with music.   It's also a great opportunity for socialising and making new friends!  

Sessions aim to introduce music, drama and movement at the earliest stages of a child's development to spark a life-long connection with the arts.  They also provide the ideal environment in which adults and infants can bond through creative play.

Little Voices takes place every Monday during term time at the Howard Assembly Room, Leeds.  There are two sessions each week, at 10am and 11:15am.  Both sessions will share a refreshment break from 10.45-11.15am which you are invited to join before/after your session.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1026]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[8506]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Opera North]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Jan 2014 - 31 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9679.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9679.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10387]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Upholstery Course]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[This open level upholstery course is perfect for a beginner or more advanced student. inc.workshop has a fully equipped upholstery space with all specialist materials stocked on sight. The workshop has all the had told you will need as well as upholstery tables, tressels, cutting table, compressor powered staple guns, industrial sewing machine and an overlocker. 

Learners bring along their own items to work on over the duration of the course with the possibility to contiunue on to a more advanced level. 
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2780]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[inc.workshop]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[2779]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[inc.workshop]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[24 Mar 2014 - 28 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10387.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10387.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9906]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Clasp Purse Workshop]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Make a beautiful clasp purse!

Perfect to keep, or to give as a gift for Mother's Day.

Let by the lovely Emily and Sam of local crafting business Love Me Sew.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3985]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Chirpy]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[3986]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Chirpy]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[26 Mar 2014 6:30pm - 9:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9906.JPG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9906.JPG]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9835]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Needle Felting - Mother's Day Workshop]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Make a present for your mum or why not treat your mum to a workshop session and share the morning together. 

Create a small needle felted picturefor a greetings card and a needle felted flower corsage.

Led by local maker Agnis Smallwood.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3985]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Chirpy]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[3986]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Chirpy]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[27 Mar 2014 11:00am - 2:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9835.JPG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9835.JPG]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9981]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Chocolate Making for Mothers Day]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Make handmade chocolates for your mums, and learn how to temper chocolate.  

You'll leave with your chocolate creations in packaging ideal for gifting for Mothers Day.

Led by the lovely Christina of locally based The Sophisticated Chocoholic. ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3985]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Chirpy]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[3986]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Chirpy]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[27 Mar 2014 6:00pm - 8:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9981.JPG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9981.JPG]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9016]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Playground]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Come and enjoy exciting multisensory art events inspired by a different Gallery artwork each month.

Suitable for under five's and their carers to gain confidence in themselves as learners, explorers, discoverers and thinkers. 

Drop in event. Please wear suitable clothes. ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[150]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Art Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7293]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Museums & Galleries]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[15 Nov 2013 - 25 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9016.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9016.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10490]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Engineering Experience]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Supported by the Royal Academy of Engineering, this free public event will demonstrate the importance of engineering disciplines. Come along to our 'market-place' of hands-on interactive activities suitable for adults and children of all ages, and see demonstrations from disciplines such as Medical Engineering, Civil Engineering, Electrical Engineering, and more! No booking required - just drop in!

This event is part of the Leeds Festival of Science - to find out about our range of other public events, including sessions on the ethics of fracking, cancer research and self-led trails around the city, please visit http://www.stem.leeds.ac.uk/lfos-public/
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[777]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Parkinson Court]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10488]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[University of Leeds]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[29 Mar 2014 10:00am - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10490_1.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10490_1.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10466]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Play In A Day]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Fancy trying your hand at acting?  Come along to day of drama workshops, leading to a performance in the evening. 

Who's in charge?
Ron Wiener, who will direct the day, is a Senior Sociodrama Trainer with extensive experience in community theatre in the UK and abroad. He was Creator and Producer of Bradford The Musical and Director of Leeds on Trial, and has led sociodrama workshops around the world.

Tickets for Play In A Day, the evening performance and the Wednesday workshops are all available through the ticket link below.

For more info: www.ronwiener.co.uk

No experience needed, just enthusiasm...  

The day is open to anyone over 18.  ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[759]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Left Bank]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[760]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Left Bank Leeds]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[29 Mar 2014 10:30am]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10466.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10466.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10216]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Build Your Dreams! Minecraft And Lego Activities]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[In the Children's library have a go at group Lego, work together to build epic structures and improve your ideas for creative building. Learn more about the basics of Minecraft, why the game is so popular and what your child can learn. We will be consulting with young people and families regarding setting up a regular LEGO and Minecraft group at Leeds Central Library, future session content and timing. 

Funded by the City Centre Youth Activity Fund
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[476]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Central Library]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[29 Mar 2014 1:00pm - 3:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10216.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10216.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10291]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Film Making: Part II]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Film editing with professional film makers The Creative Condition. With a premiere screening to follow!...

Mike Cooper and Jay Sillence will be back in the Gallery to help you through the editing processes involved in film production. Part 2 of a two day workshop, this is open to all who attended Film Making: Part 1 (http://take-one.eventbrite.co.uk) as  well as anyone interested in the post-production stage of film making.

The session will begin with a review of the footage gathered the previous week (cut down to the best takes by Jay and his team in preparation for the workshop), the editing process itself and will end with a screening of the films made during the workshops.

The work produced will be available on the Gallery website for a few weeks as well as the Gallery's youtube page so that you can share your work and show others your name on the big screen!


The Creative Condition (www.thecreativecondition.co.uk) are a creative agency team made up of three York based entrepreneurs, who work hard to support individuals and business alike. Their client list to date involves Officers and Gary Numan, Lush Cosmetics, Contact Theater, The Quietus, York St John University and plenty more. Put simply, they say; "we have a passion for people and stories. Stories are what bring us together so we combine our skills to engage and excite people about events, products and projects." They are three of the loveliest people you are likely to meet...]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4854]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Stanley & Audrey Burton Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1403]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Stanley & Audrey Burton Gallery]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[29 Mar 2014 1:30pm - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10291.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10291.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[4409]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Make Mother's Day]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Stuck for a mother's day pressie and want to give something more personal this year, we have a created a special pressie making day where you can just come along and make pretty stuff for her

On our Textiles bring along lovely fabrics, scraps of lace, old buttons etc and turn them into gorgeous gifts, from lavender bags, pinnies, bunting, covered hangers, corsages, pincushions, pj cases and many other ideas, the choice is yours, make as many or as few items as you can fit into the day

Please note all our classes need to be prebooked


&pound;35 + materials. Refreshments, but not lunch, included]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4404]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Fabrication Crafts Limited]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1430]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Fabrication Crafts Ltd]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[30 Mar 2014 10:30am - 4:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/4409.JPG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/4409.JPG]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[4846]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Laydeez Do Comics Leeds]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Laydeez do Comics is the UK's first women's led comics forum, that focuses on autobiographical comics and dramas of the everyday. It was started by illustrator Nicola Streeten & artist Sarah Lightman in London in 2009. In 2011 illustrator Lou Crosby set up Laydeez do Comics in Leeds which now runs bi-monthly. 

Laydeez do Comics, Leeds presents it's first themed night ...

... This will form part of the Yorkshire Festival 2014, the first ever Arts & Cultural Festival in the lead up the Tour de France. The Grand Depart 2014 starts in Yorkshire on the 5th July and the Yorkshire Festival runs for the 100 days up to the 6th July.

COMICS & THE SENSES 
31st March 2014 
Starts 6.30pm prompt  Ends 9.15 pm (approx)
&pound;1.50 All welcome (mixed event)

Speakers

Ian Hague - academic and director of Comics Forum. Author of Comics and the Senses: A Multisensory Approach to Comics and Graphic Novels. Talking about his research into the ways comics stimulate all 5 senses and are challenge the idea that comics are purely visual in nature. www.ianhague.com     www.abpositivecomic.com

Louise Crosby & Clare Shaw - Illustrator and poet. Poetry performance and a talk about their collaboration, Seeing Poetry: Poetry in Words and Comics.  www.facebook.com/SeeingPoetry  www.clareshaw.co.uk    www.lindenartstudio.org/artists/louise-crosby/ 

Ravi Thornton & Dr Matt Green - Ravi is a award winning cross-media writer whose work includes the debut graphic novel  The Tale Of Brin & Bent And Minno Marylebone. Ravi will be speaking about her present project HOAX My Lonely Heart a musical stage performance, and HOAX Psychosis Blues a graphic novel.  ravithornton.com
Matt is an academic from University of Nottingham who edited Alan Moore and the Gothic Tradition. He is working with Ravi on several projects. He will be speaking about this & the gothic tradition in comics. http://www.nottingham.ac.uk/english/people/matt.green


]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1603]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Wharf Chambers]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[3963]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[LaydeezdoComics Leeds]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[31 Mar 2014 - 17 Nov 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/4846_13.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/4846_13.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10354]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Willow Hare Workshop - Phil Bradley]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Master willow weaver Phil Bradley's reputation as an excellent teacher and craftsman has made him very much in demand, so we are really pleased to welcome him back to Skelton Grange for another willow weaving and sculpture workshop! During the day you will learn to create a willow sculpture of your own.

Feedback from a previous participant "A wonderfully creative and relaxing day in great company in a beautiful eco centre and natural environment. My willow hare now stands proudly in my garden - making me smile every morning when I look out! Thank you so much Phil and the welcoming team at Skelton Grange - when is the next course??!!

When not teaching, creating, demonstrating or weaving baskets, Phil manages and harvests his own organic willowbeds in Cumbria.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[5420]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Skelton Grange Environment Centre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5423]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Skelton Grange]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[5 Apr 2014 10:00am - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10354.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10354.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[4558]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Saturday Family Art Workshop]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Saturday Art Workshop for Families (6yrs plus)

ArtBugs Monthly Art Workshops  in Yeadon starts Saturday 5th October. Each workshop will explore a different art form and artist such as textiles, sculpture, painting, and mixed media.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[8001]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[St John's Church Hall]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4009]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[ArtBugs]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[5 Oct 2013 - 4 Oct 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/4558.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/4558.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9018]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[SatARTday]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Come to our drop-in workshops for families and enjoy being imaginative and creative together whilst finding out more about the art and artists in the Gallery's collection and exhibitions.

Find us in ArtSpace - everyone welcome.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[150]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Art Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7293]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Museums & Galleries]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[7 Dec 2013 - 5 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9018.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9018.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9751]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[James Bywood Print School - Screenprint]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[This popular course gives you the opportunity to utilise screenprint techniques to print your own 2-colour images onto supplied cotton bags.

Starting with a design in your head your will learn how to develop your ideas into two paper stencils from which to print the final design.

Choose and mix your own colours from quality textile inks, then print the designs onto the bags.  All equipment will be supplied.

This relaxed session will give you the opportunity to produce a quality finished bag, ideal to be given away as a gift, if indeed you don't want to keep them for yourself!

Led by local artist James Bywood.

All materials and equipment provided, as well as refreshments.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3985]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Chirpy]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[3986]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Chirpy]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[5 Apr 2014 12:00pm - 6:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9751.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9751.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10217]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[TEENS 13-17 Build Your Dreams! Minecraft And Lego activities]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[This event is aimed at teens 13-17.
In the Art Library Reading Room we will be having a go at group Lego, work together to build epic structures and improve your ideas for creative building. Meet up with other Minecrafters to work together on awesome creations, build bigger, better and faster, share ideas and have fun, No Grief. 

We will be consulting with young people aged 13-17 regarding setting up a regular LEGO and Minecraft group including future session content and timing at Leeds Central Library. 
Funded by the City Centre Youth Activity Fund
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[476]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Central Library]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[9 Apr 2014 1:00pm - 3:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10217.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10217.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10063]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Easter Bunting Making]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Learn to sew bunting to decorate your Easter egg hunt!

All materials and equipment provided.

Led by the lovely girls from locally based crafting company Love Me Sew.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3985]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Chirpy]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[3986]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Chirpy]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[9 Apr 2014 6:30pm - 9:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10063.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10063.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10522]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Dr Sketchy's Life Drawing]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Join our alternative life drawing class run by Dr Sketchy's Leeds and experience this popular themed burlesque, life drawing evening for yourself. Held every second Thursday of the month...

Presenting to you, Dr Sketchys Leeds for all you art-thrill seekers and cabaret fans!....

Welcome to an art school with a difference: An anti art school. Here there's no teaching, just lots of lifedrawing. Prepare for monthly themes or burlesque, cabaret and the very strange indeed. Let your hosts guide you through the merriment of prize challenges and obscure anti art practices. 

Join us on the second Thursday of every month from 6.30/7 - 9pm and experience the magic and the surreal as you sharpen your skills with the old fashioned pencil.

Please bring your own tools, we'll provide prizes and all the fun!!

For more information about Dr Sketchy's Leeds visit their website http://www.drsketchy.com/branch/Leeds Or find them on facebook and have a look at the fun that they have in store for you!

Contact the gallery for further details: 
email: gallery@leeds.ac.uk or Tel:0113 3432 778]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4854]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Stanley & Audrey Burton Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1403]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Stanley & Audrey Burton Gallery]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[10 Apr 2014 - 13 Jun 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10522.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10522.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9290]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Participate: Saturday Morning Sing]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Raise your voice in this Singing Workshop for young people and their families inspired by Opera North's production of La Boheme.

Suitable for children aged 4-7 and their parents/carers. All children should be accompanied by an adult, and all adults should be accompanied by a child!  ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1026]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4191]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[12 Apr 2014 10:00am]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9290.JPG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9290.JPG]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[6331]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Tart Up Your Tat ]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Do you have small household items & furniture that are still useful but don't look so pretty anymore?

Our class will show you basic preperation & decoration techniques that will transform the saddest looking object in to your own amazing creation to rival the best the designer stores have to offer!

Please email before booking with the item/s you wish to revamp as larger pieces of furniture may require a different workshop.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4404]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Fabrication Crafts Limited]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1430]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Fabrication Crafts Ltd]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Apr 2014 10:30am - 4:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/6331.JPG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/6331.JPG]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10105]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Style, Glam And Cycling Sam]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Take part at the M&S Company Archive. We'll have jive dance classes with Swing Dance Leeds, talks and a special exhibition featuring our very own Cycling Sam. 

Come in your finest 50s outfit and enter our Best Dressed Competition, and there'll be tea and cake too! From Cycling Sam in the 1950s to the M&S 24 Hour Bike Challenge, cycling plays an important role at M&S. Sam Worton achieved an amazing feat in 1955, but you'll have to come along to find out what it was! We'll also have talks about the remarkable innovations in stores and fashion that M&S pioneered in the 50s. You can also watch our fantastic 1950s cinema adverts throughout the day... complete with popcorn. 

Activities are all free and will run from 11am to 3pm. There's no need to book, although places will be limited for the dance classes due to space restrictions.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2711]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Marks & Spencer Company Archive]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[2539]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Marks & Spencer Archive]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[26 Apr 2014 ]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10105.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10105.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10525]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[IN FOCUS: Drew Millward - Illustrator]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[As part of our ongoing talk series looking at collectors and makers, we welcome illustrator Drew Millward into the Gallery to discuss his unique practice and some of his career highlights to date.

North Yorkshire based illustrator Drew likes to draw 'the old fashioned way', using pencils, pens and a love of the craft of illustration. While his subject matter can vary dramatically, he hopes that the attention to detail and the love of drawing is apparent throughout his work.
 
Drew's clients are based internationally and include Arctic Monkeys, Nike, Epitaph Records, Bon Iver, and Sonic Youth to name a few.

See some examples of Drew's work on his website.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4854]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Stanley & Audrey Burton Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1403]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Stanley & Audrey Burton Gallery]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[26 Apr 2014 12:00pm - 1:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10525.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10525.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10526]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[So, You Want To Work In The Art World?]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Meet creative entrepreneur Dom Smith and learn the secrets of making that business idea into a reality and really making it in the art world.

Dom Smith, editor of Soundsphere Magazine, co-founder of the Disabled Entrepreneurs Network and director of creative agency, The Creative Condition, will be in the Gallery to provide some key tips about getting ahead in the arts world and promoting your arts business or idea. 

The key aim of this workshop is to inspire start-up creative business owners, artists and writers: And to address central aspects of business promotion from creating press releases and news story building, to utilising social media and blogging platforms to their full potential.

This workshop is open to all aged 16+, particularly professional or budding artists, creative thinkers, idea generators, entrepreneurs and fledgling journalists...

Please bring your own laptop if possible!   

To find out more about Dom and his work visit his website: http://www.domsmithonline.co.uk]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4854]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Stanley & Audrey Burton Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1403]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Stanley & Audrey Burton Gallery]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[26 Apr 2014 2:00pm - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10526.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10526.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10518]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[A Bird's Eye View]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[A partnership project with Artlink West Yorkshire & Britain From Above.

Open to adult mental health service users.  A creative project with professional artists Jill Johnson and Beverley Haines.

A Bird's Eye View is inspired by a collection of aerial photos of Leeds & Britain, taken by daring young men in their flying machines.  Looking at these photos and seeing the changing scenery over the years will inspire us to explore this landscape through creativity.  Starting with simple printing and layering techniques we'll let our imaginations take flight and go wherever the creative flow takes us!]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3209]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Artlink West Yorkshire]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[6383]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Artlink West Yorkshire]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[30 Apr 2014 - 16 Jul 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10518.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10518.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10408]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Wire Bird Workshop With Chris Moss]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Having admired the work of Yorkshire wire sculptor Chris Moss at a number of exhibitions over the years, we are thrilled to welcome her to Skelton Grange Environment Centre to lead a workshop for us! During the day you will learn to create a wire sculpture of your very own such as a duck or chicken. To see examples of Chris's beautiful work, please have a look at her website: www.chrismossart.co.uk
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[5420]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Skelton Grange Environment Centre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5423]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Skelton Grange]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[24 May 2014 10:00am - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10408.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10408.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9946]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Create A Vision Board ]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[... for the next chapter of your life.

Before you set out on a journey it helps to know where you're going. If not, you're going to end up SOMEWHERE . . . just not where you want to be.

What if your elusive dreams took shape before your eyes? What would you discover? What could you then bring into your life for real?

Vision boards are a fabulous technique for focussing our energy and commitment on what's important. Then we get to have more of it in our lives. Pictures, words, photos, lines from poems, colour - they all help to create a powerful reminder of what you want in your future.

Making them in a workshop is fun, playful, stress free and collaborative. You get to share ideas and tell other people about yours. That's the added extra of doing this with others - you get to say it out loud as well.

"I don't want to get to the end of my life and find that I lived just the length of it. I want to have lived the width of it as well." Diane Ackerman

This workshop will suit anyone who is
- Seeking a different way to approach the new year.
- Wanting to look at your life as a whole and create greater fulfilment and richness in it.
- Has an idea for a specific project you want to create (and maybe you keep putting it on the back burner).
- Planning something big like a wedding, new business idea or retirement.

This special workshop retreat is for a maximum of 6 people, book early to be sure you're one of them. How about booking a place with your partner and creating a shared vision for your future.

During the workshop you'll
- Plug into the power of your dreams.
- Get in contact with your wisest inner self and use that inner knowing to create your vision from.
- Be coached to explore that vision so it becomes richer and more vibrant.
- Create your own vision board using a collage of images, words and colour.
- Talk about the significance of the elements of your vision so you get to hear yourself claim it out loud.
- Plan how you're going to use your board to keep focussed on what's important to you.
- Spend a day in a warm, cosy home, eat well, share laughter and have some playful fun cutting out!

" My partner and I did this course with Tilla - this weekend we have a romantic retreat by the sea to complete our shared vision board!"   Helen Collier, Money Coach HarmoneyLife

All you need is comfy clothes, a desire to create your own life and an open mind. The desire to have that fun will also come in useful! This is Blue Peter for adults!

I'll provide all the materials, and if you want to bring along old magazines to share around that'll be great.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[7008]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[5 Wensley Grove]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4308]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Tilla Brook]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[7 Jun 2014 9:30am - 4:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9946.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9946.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9755]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Moving Landscapes 2014]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Five day Skinner Releasing Technique and Movement workshop.

This course will take advantage of our location, integrating the beautiful surrounding countryside of Yorkshire with the imagery used in SRT and using this as a spring board for creative work. The course will include two trips out into Yorkshire's breath-taking countryside to visit Brimham Rocks and Timble which will feed into our creative explorations in the studio.

Skinner Releasing Technique (SRT) is a pioneering approach to dance, movement and creative process that has evolved from the simple principle that when we are releasing physical tension, we can move with greater freedom, power and articulation. Artists, actors, dancers, musicians, poets and curious explorers of all kinds welcome! All levels of experience welcome.

"A fantastic experience. Excellent teachers... very accessible, inspiring introduction to the technique. The best course I have ever experienced by far!!! I will take all I have learnt back into my practice and continue experiencing the work." Participant Feedback - Moving Landscapes'13

"Love the invitation for non-dancers - I never felt intimidated or out danced. Have seen a definite change in my body and felt so much more." Participant Feedback - Moving Landscapes '13.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2142]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Otley Courthouse]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[21 Jul 2014 - 27 Jul 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9755.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9755.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10452]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Contemporary Dance Summer School]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[A five day summer school delivered by Northern School of Contemporary Dance (NSCD).

An energetic, fun and challenging experience for dancers. The Summer School will run from Monday 28 July to Friday 1 August 2014, and will consist of groups including:

- participants currently studying dance aged 18-21 years old
- adults with some dance experience 18+ years

*Please note: we also run a Professional Intensive in partnership with Phoenix Dance Theatre.

The Summer School will feature a range of contemporary dance technique classes, contact work, repertory, improvisation and creative workshops, and will culminate with an informal performance in The Riley Theatre.

- Led by experienced dance artists
- Technique and creative sessions
- World class facilities at NSCD, Leeds
- Opportunity to meet and work with other keen dancers
- Performance opportunity

]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[460]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Northern School of Contemporary Dance]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[2123]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Northern School of Contemporary Dance]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[28 Jul 2014 - 1 Aug 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10452.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10452.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[5444]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Willow Deer Weaving With Phil Bradley]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[We are very excited to be hosting a workshop run by Phil Bradley, willow weaver and basket maker extraordinaire! 

Phil will guide you through the process of making a lovely Deer sculpture to take home. You don't need to have done any willow weaving before, and all materials needed will be provided for you.  Early booking is recommended as Phil's workshops are always very popular. Please visit our website to make a booking.

Feedback from a previous participant "A wonderfully creative and relaxing day in great company in a beautiful eco centre and natural environment. My willow hare now stands proudly in my garden - making me smile every morning when I look out! Thank you so much Phil and the welcoming team at Skelton Grange - when is the next course??!!"

When not teaching, creating, demonstrating or weaving baskets, Phil manages and harvests his own organic willowbeds in Cumbria.

Plentiful tea, coffee and soft drinks provided, but please do bring your own lunch!]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[5420]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Skelton Grange Environment Centre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5423]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Skelton Grange]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[11 Sep 2014 10:00am - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/5444_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/5444_0.jpg]]></image_original></item></objects></response>