<?xml version="1.0"?><response><status><![CDATA[200]]></status><status_message><![CDATA[OK]]></status_message><message><![CDATA[OK]]></message><objects><item><event_id><![CDATA[8483]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA['Metamorphosis I' - Daniel Cooper]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Fascinated by the beautiful textures and markings within slate, Daniel Cooper's solo showcase explores this wonderful material with a series of vessels.  His inspiration comes from a visit to Elterwater Slate Quarry in the Lake District where he adopted the working methods, knowledge and local dialect of the quarrymen to produce this collection of works. Daniel hosts a Meet the Maker afternoon on Saturday 18th January, please contact the gallery for further information.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3905]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Craft Centre and Design Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4655]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[The Craft Centre and Design Gallery]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[18 Jan 2014 - 30 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/8483.JPG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/8483.JPG]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9090]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Vladimir And Georgii Stenberg]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Construction for a spatial Structure VI ('KPS6', 1919/73)

Trained engineers, the Stenberg brothers (1899-1982 / 1900-33) were central to the Russian Constructivist movement. Their achievements included designing theatre sets, women's shoes, posters for the films of Sergei Eisenstein and, in 1947, Vladimir designed the May Day decorations for Red Square. This display presents a 1973 reconstruction of the lost 1919 sculptural prototype for a building, known as 'KPS6', or 'Construction for a Spatial Structure VI'. Related archival material shows the brothers' important role in the Moscow avant-garde on the 1920s, tracing this sculpture's continued influence since its original showing at Moscow's Poet's Cafe in January 1922.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[388]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Henry Moore Institute]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[2657]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Henry Moore Institute]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[22 Jan 2014 - 20 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9090.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9090.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10198]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[PAN Berlin Record Label]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Leeds College of Art welcomes an exhibition from PAN, a critically acclaimed platform for experimental sound and art, based between Berlin and New York. This exhibition showcases a range of artwork produced by the label for PAN artists' records.  
 
Founded in 2008 by artist Bill Kouligas, PAN represents a community of artists united by their singular contributions to the electronic vanguard. PAN has released records by some of the world's most acclaimed electronic and experimental artists over its four year lifespan. The beautiful artwork is a critical part of its success, and, for Bill and label partner Kathryn Politis, a crucial part of the business, conceived as a visual project as much as a musical one.
 
The PAN label boss Bill Kouligas says, "The design of the label has a cohesive aesthetic that the musicians/artists we work with are aware of. There is no fixed process in regards to working with them on the artwork, PAN strive to make something within the concept of their album as far as possible, and we both approve the final artwork. Some artists are more involved than others; some may suggest images they want to use, or drawings of theirs they would like translated into the PVC design. With others we discuss influences that they would like to see incorporated into the design on a more abstract level. In any case, with each release, comes an exchange of ideas. The label was conceived initially as a platform for our artwork and interests. We are trying to not limit ourselves to being a record label in the traditional sense; there have been numerous shows, events, showcases and festivals etc. to date as part of the label, and there are some non-music related projects in the works."

This exhibition is free and open to all members of the public. ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[5496]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds College of Art, Blenheim Walk Building]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10124]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds College of Art]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[14 Feb 2014 - 16 May 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10198_1.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10198_1.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[8484]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Shoots And Leaves]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Print exhibition.

Hedgerows are explored by two printmakers in this wonderful exploration of growth.  Stef Mitchell's seasonal monoprints work directly with natural materials acting as recordings of walks which viewers can easily relate to.  Lynn Bailey combines several printmaking techniques in her collection including etching, collagraph, drypoint, mono print and photo etching which create an exciting and organic series of works.  Stef Mitchell's work pictured.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3905]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Craft Centre and Design Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4655]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[The Craft Centre and Design Gallery]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[1 Mar 2014 - 28 Jun 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/8484.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/8484.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10005]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Drift]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[This exhibition was organised by respected social-documentary photographer Ian Beesley and the poet and presenter Ian McMillan. The display was brought to Leeds Industrial Museum as part of a continued commitment to draw visitors' attention to industries that remain active in Yorkshire today. The show portrays the mental, social and physical impact mining has on the lives of modern miners and has previously been on display at the National Coal Mining Museum back in 2011. 

Taking nearly twenty years to complete, this multi-layered body of work explores the harshness and dangers of coal mining in one of the last working pits in England. The physicality of the work, the relationship between the underground and the surface, the claustrophobia and darkness of the pit are explored in this collaboration between the photographer Ian Beesley, the poet Ian McMillan and the miners of Hayroyd's colliery.

Image: Ian Beesley
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[151]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Armley Mills Leeds Industrial Museum]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7293]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Museums & Galleries]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[7 Jan 2014 - 30 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10005.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10005.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10428]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Ones To Watch]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[An exciting exhibition in collaboration with students from Leeds College of Art, "Ones to Watch" features fine art, sculpture, furniture, photography, film, textiles, an interactive sound piece ( make your own sound art) and the chance to look through the unique perspective of a camera obscura. 
 
Selected in a competitive process from dozens of entries across the many disciplines within the College the work informs and challenges; demonstrating the talent and enthusiasm of the next generation of artists, makers and designers.

Directed by Ryan Smith.  Branded by Sam Lane.  Hosted by Sunny Bank Mills Gallery.
Preview: 7 March : 7-9pm]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3147]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Sunny Bank Mills]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[6705]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Sunny Bank Mills]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[8 Mar 2014 - 30 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10428.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10428.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[8475]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Potts Of Leeds (Clocks Of Character)]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[From the Town Hall to the Corn Exchange, so many of the clocks familiar to us in the townscape of Leeds and beyond were made by Potts of Leeds. To celebrate the work of this great Leeds company Armley Mills is exhibiting the Potts family's private collection of clocks for the public for the very first time. Come down and see what really makes them tick.

William Potts began making clocks in Pudsey in 1833 before moving to central Leeds in 1862. With a growing fame for the quality and reliability of their clocks the company received a Royal Warrant from Queen Victoria in 1897. Over five generations the Potts family produced some 1,600 public clocks for towns all over Britain and across the world. 

This exhibition brings together examples spanning the history of the company and features a varied collection of turret clocks, wall clocks, drum clocks and unusual clock-based items. There are prominent royal clocks and an example of the company's famous railway clock from Argentina. There will also be never-before-seen archive documents from the earliest days of the Potts company. Uniquely, all of the clocks on display will be wound daily and will run for the duration of the exhibition. If you've ever wondered what the workings of a cathedral clock look like, or questioned where the tick-tock sound comes from then the Potts of Leeds - Clocks of Character exhibition is the place to get all the answers.

There is no additional charge for visiting this exhibition.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[151]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Armley Mills Leeds Industrial Museum]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[924]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Museums & Galleries]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[5 Oct 2013 - 28 Sep 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/8475.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/8475.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9729]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[A Snapshot of Yorkshire]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Discover a new exhibition celebrating Yorkshire past and present.

We all know that Yorkshire is the biggest county in England.
Famous for its beautiful green spaces and sprawling landscapes it is also home to the longest steam operated railway in the UK, Britain's highest pub and the oldest registered visitor attraction in the country.

To celebrate this, Abbey House Museum has a fantastic new
exhibition all about Yorkshire and the traditions which make
it what it is today.

Discover which beauty spots were voted as the favourite place to visit in our Yorkshire survey, find out which famous brands originate from this county, learn about Yorkshire people and culture, and take a closer look at iconic and quirky Yorkshire objects from our collections.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[152]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Abbey House Museum]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7293]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Museums & Galleries]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[25 Jan 2014 - 31 Dec 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9729.PNG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9729.PNG]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9730]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Natural Beauty 2]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[A stunning display of images captured by the public and inspired by the wonderful wildlife all around us.

Natural Beauty 2 showcases the best entries of a public photography competition that was inspired by the wonderful wildlife all around us. We challenged photographers of all ages and abilities to capture and share their images of the natural world, and now you can see the results for yourself.

- ANIMAL BEHAVIOUR
- BEAUTIFUL BOTANY
- BEAUTIFUL YORKSHIRE
- BRITISH WILDLIFE
- LEEDS WILDLIFE
- WILD YORKSHIRE
- WORLD WILDLIFE

Leeds City Museum is a free attraction located just up the
steps on Millennium Square in Leeds city centre.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[385]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds City Museum]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7293]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Museums & Galleries]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[7 Feb 2014 - 17 Aug 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9730.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9730.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9847]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Bruce McLean: Beyond the Pose]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Bruce McLean is a sculptor who makes work that draws on a variety of media from live art, film, photography, painting and sculpture, dispensing with categories of definition as it moves across media, carried by an interdisciplinary, riotous imagination. Significantly McLean is a sculptor who has been professor of painting at The Slade for over 25 years and now, recently retired, has been prolific in producing work that continues to enliven and interrogate the very nature of sculpture.

The exhibition draws upon work made by Bruce McLean over 50 years but through the prism of new and recent work. Introducing his work to audiences not familiar with his distinctive, irreverent voice and providing new perspectives by creating surprising junctures between earlier and new work, it shows McLean to be an artist who, frequently joining forces with others, consistently breaks rules, and permits audiences to experience work that disrupts disciplines and breaches borders.

Paintings present sculpture and are sculptural, photography is performance, live works and ceramics act as sculptures. This exhibition aims to get to the heart of this mischievous sense of play and iconoclasm.

The exhibition is a partnership with Firstsite, Colchester.

Image: Bruce McLean, The generation game of sculpture, a cuddly toy, a ...no I've said that, 2010. Oil, acrylic and charcoal on canvas. Courtesy of the artist and Tanya Leighton, Berlin.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[150]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Art Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7293]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Museums & Galleries]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[14 Feb 2014 - 11 May 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9847.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9847.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9854]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Nocturne: Journeys Into The Night-time With Atkinson Grimshaw And George Shaw]]></event_title><description><![CDATA['For countless millennia humankind has lived in step with the cycles of the moon; planting crops, wooing lovers and gathering harvests according to celestial clockwork. It is scarcely more than a century since this connection was decisively broken, since we turned our back on the sky and our faces towards the brilliantly lit interiors..' James Attlee: 'Nocturne' 2011

We have traditionally feared the night and wanted to lighten the darkness, but for artists it has also been a zone of uncertainty to capture in painted form.  This display sets Leeds artist Atkinson Grimshaw's much loved 19th century 'moonlights' alongside Turner-prize nominee George Shaw's atmospheric paintings of the housing estate where he grew up (from the Arts Council Collection). 

Also included are paintings by Jack Yeats, George Sauter and Walter Greaves.

This display celebrates the continuing partnership between Leeds Museums & Galleries and the Arts Council Collection, supported by Christies.

Image: George Shaw, The End of Time, 2008-2009, Enamel on board. Arts Council Collection (2010) © the artist.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[150]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Art Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7293]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Museums & Galleries]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[20 Jan 2014 - 1 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9854.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9854.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10013]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Paula Dunn]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[After the success of Paula's exhibition in 2013 we are delighted to be showing a series of paintings from her God's Own Range. These wonderful textured paintings of the Yorkshire Dales will be on display until the end of March so make sure you find time to come in to the gallery and see them before they are sold.

More information about Paula and her paintings can be found here http://pauladunnartist.com/

Also and display are a collection of handpicked artists by Gallery manager Zack who has chosen work that he finds inspiring and a delight to look at, so there is plenty to see in the gallery in the next few months.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4921]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Old Grammar School Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[9262]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[The Old Grammar School Gallery]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[1 Feb 2014 - 31 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10013_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10013_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10557]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Slim Aarons]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Slim Aarons worked mainly for society publications, taking pictures of the rich and famous both before and after serving as a photographer for the US military magazine Yank during World War II. 

His work has been included in the publications Town and Country, Holiday, Venture and LIFE among others. Aarons was known for the positive portrayals he gave to the people he photographed and was invited to high-society gatherings for exactly this reason. His subject matter covered American and European society as well as nobility and both minor and major stars of the day.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1544]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[White Cloth Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4002]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[White Cloth Gallery]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[7 Mar 2014 - 13 May 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10557.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10557.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10492]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Her Sela Art Exhibition]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[That Sela Art Thing and The Juju Art Agency join forces in presenting:

Her Sela Art Exhibition

A celebration of female artists, makers and creators in honour of International Women's Day 2014. 

We will be featuring work from some amazing women including:

Bess Martin
Charlie Jackson 
Clare Morgan 
Ellie Depp 
Emma Saynor
Josephine McYebuah
Kristyna Baczynski 
Lily Best
Nicola Hanrahan
Suzie Cichy

With more to be confirmed.

We will also be fundraising for Support After Rape & Sexual Violence Leeds (www.supportafterrapeleeds.org.uk) the Rape Crisis centre for Leeds. 

Join us with pizza, beer and cocktails for this salon style selabration of women in the arts! Not one to be missed on your tour of International Women's Day events this weekend. ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3749]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Sela Bar]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[8149]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[That Sela Art Thing]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[8 Mar 2014 - 22 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10492.JPG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10492.JPG]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10360]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Monthly Pop-Up Exhibition]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Focusing on a specific discipline, Arts @ Trinity hosts a new monthly one day event, each culminating with an evening show.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1956]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Holy Trinity Church]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10359]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Arts @ Trinity]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[12 Mar 2014 - 13 Nov 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10360_1.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10360_1.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10336]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Lore Of The North]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[An exhibition by Lord Whitney.

'The moor was still, poised at this hour as if this extraordinary event had dispelled time...'

Lord Whitney's Lore of the North project presented in an exciting publication and exhibition, based on Yorkshire Folklore.

If you've missed the project, catch up here - http://loreofthenorth.tumblr.com/
www.lordwhitney.co.uk

Supported by Grants for the Arts and Leeds Inspired]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1782]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Munro House]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10330]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Lord Whitney]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Mar 2014 - 25 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10336.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10336.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9529]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Down To Earth]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[An exhibition showcasing work which has been inspired by the Earth either through use of texture, colour, imagery and materials used in the creation of the collections.  A variety of environments have inspired the participating makers including coastlines, woodland, moorland and mountain ranges.  Featuring work by Mandy Parslow, Ben Davies, David Wright, Valerie Wartelle, Catherine Woodall (pictured) and Elizabeth Terzza to name just a few.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3905]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Craft Centre and Design Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[22 Mar 2014 - 28 Jun 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9529.JPG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9529.JPG]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10162]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Overtime]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[SEIZE Leeds presents: OVERTIME : Art and the Office

Opening Night - Wednesday 26th March 7pm, All Welcome

Situated in Leeds' busy financial district, OVERTIME brings together a diverse group of both emerging and more established practitioners from across the country to explore the differences between the office and the artist's studio.

Often seen as a bureaucratic environment, offices are associated with systemized tasks, the management of data and pro rata salaries, but rarely unregulated creative play. This exhibition seeks to use the unexpected friction generated by placing the work of art in the office to interrogate fixed attitudes towards working practices more generally.

Participating artists & collectives are: 
Lily Ackroyd-Willoughby 
Mike Ainsworth 
Anachron-Gen 
Alice Bradshaw 
Lydia Catterall 
Spike Dennis 
Natalie Drenth 
Emma Hardaker 
Phill Hopkins 
Edward Hurst 
Luc Jones 
Ellie MacGarry 
Bess Martin 
Tom McGinn 
Emma Moody-Smith 
Julia Miorin 
Shanie Mor 
OFFCUT collaborative 
Leo Plumb 
Ned Pooler 
Stanley Quaia 
Alec Shepley 
Will Turner 
Philip Welding 
Matt Wheeldon

SEIZE Leeds is an artist-led organisation that works to engage and support emerging and mid-career artists both regionally and nationally through a programme of ambitious temporary art shows and events. SEIZE works with vacant spaces in-situ to produce exciting and accessible exhibitions that explore ideas relevant to each site and promote talent.

Partners:  &Model Gallery / BasementArtsProject]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[10161]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Wellington Park House]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[9360]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[SEIZE]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[26 Mar 2014 - 29 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10162_2.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10162_2.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10535]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Sodium Laureth Suplhate/The Gallery Is Now Closed]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Leeds based artists Fred Pepper and Helen Dryden are jointly exhibiting at private residence The Crooked House (in Burley, Leeds).

Helen's exhibition 'Sodium Laureth Sulphate' consists of mixed media paintings and a digital projection.

Her process is spontaneous and instinctive, using media such as acrylics on canvas, boards and cardboard; watercolours, felt tip pens, ribbons and gems. Using imagery from her subconscious, intuitive mark making, and reacting to found pictures and music, Helen creates an uncertain world, sometimes confusing, wondering, atmospheric and difficult to identify.

Fred's exhibition 'The Gallery Is Now Closed' features a display of his ongoing movie monster monoprint series, accompanied by a loop of the video-collage Wastin' Arrers and the sound piece Mr. Leech's Institution by Lynden St. John for Octopus Collective, for which the artist provided voice performance.

Fred Pepper works in an illustrative style and within a narrative tradition. His practice centres on drawing and printmaking, but he also makes forays into the territories of performance, sculpture, digital media and painting.
He was born a Sagittarius on a Woden's Day in a Year of the Wood Rabbit.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[10534]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Crooked House]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[27 Mar 2014 - 2 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10535.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10535.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10116]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Yesterday]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Alongside In Pursuit of the Exquisite, a complimentary contemporary exhibition in the Terrace Gallery, Yesterday, will feature the work of artists Dan Scott and Michelle Taylor. This exhibition incorporating ceramics, music and sound will explore how objects powerfully connect us to the past and in this respect for both artists the iconic and notorious figure of Marie Antoinette acts as a catalyst to explore this relationship.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[391]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Harewood House]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[2 Apr 2014 - 8 Jun 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10116.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10116.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9530]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA['Metamorphosis II' - Mark Cooke]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Mark Cooke explores the striking and timeless beauty of Welsh slate in this series of wall hung works and freestanding uprights.  His sensitivity to the material he uses maximises the inherent qualities found in slate creating a contemporary collection of works.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3905]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Craft Centre and Design Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4655]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[The Craft Centre and Design Gallery]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[1 May 2014 - 31 Jul 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9530.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9530.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10028]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Eyes On Le Tour De France]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Graham Watson and Bernard Thompson's photography of Le Tour promises an unrivalled view on and off the race track, White Cloth Gallery presents two exhibitions in tribute to these great talents, complimented by a summer programme of events, talks and screenings.

Be Part Of It: A talk, Q&A, film screening and display of additional archive materials will take place during the summer to celebrate Bernard Thompson's contribution to sports photography.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1544]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[White Cloth Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4002]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[White Cloth Gallery]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[15 May 2014 - 31 Aug 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10028.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10028.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10194]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Leeds International Tattoo Exposition]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Leeds International Tattoo Exposition (LITE) will be taking place at The New Dock Hall (part of the world famous Royal Armouries).

We have access to some truly inspirational international tattoo artists (please keep your eyes on the website (right) for artist announcements). We are also holding a huge alternative market under a heated, weather proof marquee out on the plaza, art exhibitions and an awesome after party including bands, DJs and other performances!

www.leedstattooexpo.com
www.instagram.com/leedstattooexpo
www.twitter.com/leedstattooexpo]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[10192]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[New Dock Hall]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10193]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds International Tattoo Exposition]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[24 May 2014 - 25 May 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10194.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10194.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10115]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Bicyclism ]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Bicyclism is a new exhibition about people in and around Leeds who inhabit cycling, its history and popular culture. A collaboration between photographer Casey Orr, writer/musician Boff Whalley and curator Jenny Harris, Bicyclism includes a series of new portraits of (extra) ordinary Leeds cyclists, from stunt bikers in skate parks to local men and women who pedal daily well into old age, alongside crowd-sourced and archive images of Leeds people on their bikes.

The exhibition will unearth stories and histories of the area's cycling past, from the socialist Clarion Clubs to the role played by bicycles in the suffrage movement, from cycling cafe culture to the role of the many cycling clubs (and the cyclists) in Leeds' social history, geography and landscape.

A new soundtrack composed using bicycles will accompany the exhibition. Watch the live at the Museum on Thursday 26th June. 

Be Part Of It: If you have a photo in your album of you or a family member on their bike that you would like to submit for inclusion in the exhibition visit www.bicyclism.co.uk for more information.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[385]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds City Museum]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7293]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Museums & Galleries]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[24 Jun 2014 - 7 Jul 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10115.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10115.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9531]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Bloom: Print Exhibition]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Ruth Green and Sue Vanderplank explore the wonderful world of flowers with their unique screen prints.  Vibrant, exciting, colourful and fun this exhibition explores a whole host of beautiful flowers to cheer up anyone's day.  Pictured; print by Ruth Green.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3905]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Craft Centre and Design Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4655]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[The Craft Centre and Design Gallery]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[5 Jul 2014 - 25 Oct 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9531.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9531.jpg]]></image_original></item></objects></response>