<?xml version="1.0"?><response><status><![CDATA[200]]></status><status_message><![CDATA[OK]]></status_message><message><![CDATA[OK]]></message><objects><item><event_id><![CDATA[9923]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Vanessa Grasse - Movementscapes]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Vanessa Grasse leads a walk from Yorkshire Dance to Hyde Park Picture House (in time for the screenings of All This Can Happen and Touched).

This choreographed journey through the city will heighten our awareness of everyday 'urban choreographies' and play with our kinetic and perceptual experience of the space. The walk will suggest new ways to relate to our surroundings and to capture our experience along the way.

Part of Yorkshire Dance's Juncture; a festival of contemporary movement, theatre and film work curated by Wendy Houstoun.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[321]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Yorkshire Dance]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[2258]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Yorkshire Dance]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[9 Mar 2014 2:00pm - 3:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9923.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9923.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9753]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Birdwatching for Beginners]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Brush up on your bird identification and visit some of the best nature areas in and around Leeds. Start Birding birdwatching classes provide a friendly and supportive learning environment for those new to birdwatching or anyone who want to return to this exciting and rewarding hobby. ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[797]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Various Locations]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5487]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Start Birding]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[7 Jan 2014 - 24 Jun 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9753.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9753.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[5430]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Green Team!]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[We run practical environmental volunteering days most Fridays (see our website for calendar of events), when there is a chance to join the 'Green Team' to help develop and maintain the wildlife area at Skelton Grange. You can come for a one-off day or every week - it's a great chance to get involved and learn new skills, and no previous experience is needed!

Get in touch to let us know if you're planning to come along to any of the events. Tea, coffee and biscuits will be provided but please bring a packed lunch. Wear old clothes that you don't mind getting mucky, and dress for the weather.

Directions to the Centre can be found on our website
.
- Under 18s must be accompanied by an adult for all events.
- Please arrive at nine thirty for a ten o'clock start.
- Generally sessions run until three thirty unless advertised otherwise.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[5420]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Skelton Grange Environment Centre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5423]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Skelton Grange]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[27 Sep 2013 - 26 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/5430.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/5430.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9057]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Sportivate: Skelton Grange Green Team]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Taster opportunties - get active and involved in the outdoors!

Want to get involved in practical phyical activity, learn new skills, get fitter, and do something that makes a difference to your local environment? 

We'll be learning new skills around the Skelton Grange site including hard and soft landscaping of the new 'megapond' area, plus traditional hedge laying techniques and there will also chances to get involved in the food growing area and fruit orchard at the centre. 

On Friday the 21st of February 2014 there will also be a guided cycle ride happening to the centre - to help people find their way to us. Meet by the White Pedestrian Bridge over the river by the Royal Armories at 9:15am ready for a 9:30 departure to follow the canal side Trans Pennine Trail route to Skelton Grange Environment Centre. Its about a 15-20 minute cycle ride, but traffic free almost all the way - so its a great way to get to know the way to Skelton Grange.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[5420]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Skelton Grange Environment Centre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5423]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Skelton Grange]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[21 Feb 2014 - 28 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9057_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9057_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9510]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[St Patrick's Day Parade]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The Leeds St Patrick's Day Parade is in its fifthteenth year and is a celebration of all things Irish.

This year's parade will be followed by celebrations in Millennium Square, including live traditional Irish music and dancing, stalls, food, displays and much more. 

This is a fantastic event for families and friends of all ages, and all are welcome to join in the fun. 

The parade will leave from Cookridge Street at 11:00am. This year's parade will be bigger and better with a stream of colourful floats, followed by an afternoon of events in Millennium Square, showcasing different aspects 
of Irish Culture.

For further information visit the website.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[295]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Millennium Square]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[16 Mar 2014 11:00am]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9510.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9510.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10407]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Biodiversity Month: Bird Brains!]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[In The Bird Garden Education Room

- BIODIVERSITY MONTH -

Come and make a living bird feeder to attract birds to your garden or your local green space.

Bird related crafts and activities!
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[156]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Lotherton Hall and Estate]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4754]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Lotherton Hall]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[16 Mar 2014 1:00pm - 3:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10407.png]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10407.png]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10609]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Tolkein Trail]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[On this guided linear walk Tolkienist Claire Randall will discuss local landscape and linguistic features around Headingley that Professor JRR Tolkien will have known from his time in Leeds just after the Great War (1920-25), which provocatively suggest themselves as inspirations and influences on his creation of Middle Earth. We shall also visit several of the houses where he lived, contextualising his Leeds period and exploring aspects of his mythology, which was already well developed at this time.

This walk is 4.5 miles and finishes at the West Park Cafe; for
optional refreshments.

]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[7843]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Hyde Park Public House]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[6703]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Headingley LitFest]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[29 Mar 2014 12:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10609.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10609.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10610]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Literary Scarecrow Festival]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The Far Headingley Village Society & Headingley
LitFest Literary Scarecrow Festival.

Enter the festival. Follow the trail. Go to the scarecrow meet.

All scarecrows must have some sort of literary connection,
however loose - e.g. a character (human, animal or scarecrow) in a book, poem or play. 

There will be an end-of-trail 'scarecrow meet' at the community orchard near St Chad's church on Sunday 6 April from 2pm onwards. 

Or for only &pound;1 you can just follow the scarecrow trail from 29 to 30 March, see how many scarecrows you can find and help to judge the winning entries. Buy your scarecrow trail map from HEART, Headingley library or local shops or check
the FHVS website for other sources.

Keep up to date with all the latest scarecrow news at
www.fhvs.btck.co.uk/scarecrows]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[797]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Various Locations]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[6703]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Headingley LitFest]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[29 Mar 2014 - 6 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10610.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10610.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10416]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Campfire Cooking With Chris Ensor]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Al fresco cooking at its most fun with our very own man of the woods Chris Ensor!

Join us for a hands on day spent in our woods round the fire with Chris guiding you through the art of campfire cooking.  During the day we will be preparing a variety of dishes and looking at different cooking techniques which can be utilised when out in the wilderness.

Happy times spent outdoors plus something extra special to excite the taste buds!

You can book via Eventbrite or our website where you can also check out other exciting workshops we are planning.

All proceeds will go to support the great charitable work of The Conservation Volunteers at Skelton Grange Environment Centre!
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[5420]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Skelton Grange Environment Centre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5423]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Skelton Grange]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[12 Jul 2014 10:00am - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10416.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10416.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10539]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Hospice Cycle Sportive]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[This inaugural 68 mile circular route will take in the stunning scenery of West and South Yorkshire, creating a fabulous event that riders of all abilities can get involved in.

Starting at St Gemma's Hospice in Moortown the route takes cyclists past other hospices including Overgate, Kirkwood and Barnsley. There will be a checkpoint at each Hospice where water will be available and once back at St Gemma's you can enjoy refreshments, music and a well-earned rest.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4709]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[St. Gemma's Hospice]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4489]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[St Gemma's Hospice]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Jul 2014 6:30am]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10539_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10539_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[5381]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Leeds Pride 2014]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The 9th annual Leeds Gay Pride event in the city.

The Committee have chosen this years theme to reflect the ongoing push for change and equality and recognise the legalisation to allow same sex marriage in the United Kingdom. Love&Marriage will feature strongly in our campaign and shows as we celebrate this important milestone in LGB&T rights.

Its time to buy a hat!

This year, we are pleased to introduce Gay Leeds Legends Kira & Degsie as your Parade Stage hosts as well as inviting back the one and only Miss Orry on Main Stage - flying back from Gran Canaria to join her is Chelsea from Ricky's Cabaret Bar.

Starting in Millennium Square at midday, the parade stage officially kicks off Leeds Pride with speakers and a selection of performances. Then join the parade through Leeds as it winds its way down to Briggate or "Gay Leeds" where the party continues.

The main stage in the heart of the LGBT community will showcase even more local stars as well as popular LGBT scene performers, camp cabaret, a headliner and our ever popular dance session. 

We are the UK's fastest growing LGB&T pride and the biggest
annual street event in the City of Leeds. With your support we hope to continue delivering a top class pride for Leeds. Here is just a taster of what's to come...

Stooshe 
Your headline act for Main Stage at this years
LeedsPride. Since 2010, this UK trio have belted out top 20 hit after hit with single - "Slip" holding steady as a Summer 2013 anthem. MOBO & Brit Award nominated, get set for our BIGGEST headline act to date. 

Lonnie Gordon
3 UK top 40 hits // 3 US Number 1's. Philliadelphia (USA) born Lonnie Gordon is a 90's Dance legend working with names such as BlackBox. Her most memorable hits include "Gonna Catch you" & "Happenin all over again". Lonnie is about to release her new single "Horny". She will be joining the Main Stage line up at Leeds Pride 2014.

Katrina
(Katrina & the Waves) Katrina is an American musician, author and former lead singer of English pop rock band Katrina and The Waves. The hit song "Walking on Sunshine", billed in the top 10 of charts across the globe and is still the most played summer track on radio in the US, 28 years after its release. In 1997, Katrina restored British faith in the  Eurovision Song Contest- breaking through political & block voting with the anthem "Love Shine a Light", giving the United Kingdom its first win in Decades. Katrina will headline the Parade Stage at Millennium Square before this years big parade sets off! 

More acts will be confirmed in the run up to the event.

There's much more info on the website and facebook page which is constantly updated in the run up to Leeds Pride.

Image: Miss Orry]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[295]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Millennium Square]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5380]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Pride]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[3 Aug 2014 ]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/5381_0.png]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/5381_0.png]]></image_original></item></objects></response>