<?xml version="1.0"?><response><status><![CDATA[200]]></status><status_message><![CDATA[OK]]></status_message><message><![CDATA[OK]]></message><objects><item><event_id><![CDATA[5982]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Yoga - Stretch Out And Tone Up]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Yoga in the city centre for everyone; from beginners to yoga boffins. All equipment is provided, just bring yourself! 

Ashtanga yoga is a powerful form of yoga which improves flexibility and strength, whilst relaxing the mind.

Get fit, flexible and even more fabulous. Be a hero!

Any questions? No problem - just email holly@yogahero.co.uk]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[9270]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Lambert's Yard]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Jan 2014 - 28 May 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/5982.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/5982.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9374]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Complete Beginners Taichi Course]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Start the spring by detoxing your body, de -stressing your mind and revitalising your spirit.  Lishi Taichi's friendly instructors offer you  ancient Chinese Daoist exercises to find inner peace, relax and be re-energised on the hunt for your Qi. Turn up and let your worries and distractions slip away into oblivion.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3932]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Wrangthorn Church Hall]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[10 Feb 2014 - 14 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9374.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9374.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[8719]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Yoga For Fitness]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Yoga is a wonderful work out for the body; helping to tone up muscles and increase flexibility, whilst calming the mind and de-stressing completely.

In these Monday 7:15pm classes, we follow the 'Rocket' sequence; a dynamic sequence which is designed to build strength and tone in the muscles, whilst still offering a deep stretch to unwind any tension.

We finish with some lovely relaxation, and leave feeling energised and refreshed. For any questions, or to book a place, just email holly@yogahero.co.uk]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[9270]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Lambert's Yard]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Jan 2014 - 26 May 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/8719.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/8719.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[7801]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Unwind and Relax Yoga Class]]></event_title><description><![CDATA['Unwind and Relax' focuses on relaxation through restorative yet still physically demanding yoga postures.

'Unwind the body', practised to beautiful low lighting and relaxing music, begins with a short relaxation period to clear the mind, before being guided through a series of energising stretches at a steady pace. The class finishes with a deep relaxation to relieve stress and release tension from the body.

This is the perfect mid-week treat, to stretch out and challenge the body; increase strength and flexibility, whilst completely relaxing the mind, ready for the rest of the week ahead. The class is timed so students can, go home and pretty much straight to bed for a wonderful night's sleep if they would like!

Any questions? No problem - just email holly@yogahero.co.uk]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[9270]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Lambert's Yard]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[15 Jan 2014 - 28 May 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/7801.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/7801.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9147]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Leeds Half Marathon]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The Leeds Half Marathon is one of the highlights of Leeds' sporting calendar. The 13.1 mile run starts on the Headrow, close to the iconic Town Hall and finishes in Cookridge Street, to the side of landmark Millennium Square. With an electric start and finish, the Half Marathon is a fantastic challenge and a step-up from the 10K series for those who want to push themselves a little further]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3802]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds City Centre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[9145]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Run for All]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[11 May 2014 9:30am - 2:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9147_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9147_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9095]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[WWE Live]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[WWE Live returns to the first direct arena!

Following on from the success of last 2013s awesome evening WWE Live will be returning to the first direct arena this summer. The announcement of this event is first direct arena's first repeat booking.

Come see your favourite WWE Superstars and Divas from RAW and SmackDown live in action. The match-card will be announced soon.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4063]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[first direct arena]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5131]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[first direct arena]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[16 May 2014 ]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9095.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9095.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[8554]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Grand Depart 2014]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[It is official: The world's greatest cycle race - the Tour de France - will start in the world's greatest county on 5th & 6th July 2014 bringing millions of fans to the Yorkshire roadside to cheer on the champions of the sport.

It will be the first time Le Tour has visited the north of England having previously only made visits to the south coast and the capital. We guarantee it will be a festival and a spectacle for fans and first timers alike and are sure Yorkshire will rise to occasion and give the riders, the teams and the race organisers a Grand Depart to remember. Yorkshire is a world class county and it will deliver a world class event.

The official route of the 2014 race including road-by-road details of the route the legendary cycle race will take through Leeds when the Grand Depart begins in the city on the morning of Saturday 5 July can be seen at the website - www.letouryorkshire.com.

After completing the official signing-in ceremony in front of Leeds Town Hall, the world's leading riders will then line up on The Headrow for the ceremonial start of the Tour de France. The initial non-racing rollout will see the peloton ride along The Headrow to Eastgate before turning left onto Regent Street and following the A61 out of town towards Harewood. 

For those keen to view the race as it journeys through Leeds, there will be spectator 'hubs' including family-focused activities at Scott Hall playing fields and Harewood House with other locations also being discussed.

The route of stage one is to start to be permanently waymarked so cyclists and motorists can follow the stage themselves in the build-up and following the Grand Depart.

Routes of the Grand Depart including interactive maps are available on www.letouryorkshire.com]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[313]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Town Hall]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[5 Jul 2014 11:00am]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/8554.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/8554.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10423]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Triathlon Pink UK]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Leeds is the third event as part of a new series changing the way women view triathlons; combining a fun 'girl's day out' with feel-good fitness. The swim, bike and run events are aimed at women of all abilities, ages and backgrounds, meaning anyone can take part with minimal training and preparation. But there is also an event for the kids and men.
Triathlon Pink 
Short Course	100 Metres	3 Kilometres	1 Kilometre
Medium Course	200 Metres	6 Kilometres	2 Kilometres
Long Course	300 Metres	9 Kilometres	3 Kilometres
Triathlon Pink Kids (Under 13)	50 Metres	1.5 Kilometres	500 Metres
Pink Pyjama Fun Run - a 3km run, walk or jog with a twist - you wear your pink pyjamas. For everyone to take part.
Raising money for Breakthrough Breast Cancer.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[237]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[John Charles Centre for Sport]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10422]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Sport 3 Event Management UK]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[6 Jul 2014 6:00am - 12:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10423.JPG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10423.JPG]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10539]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Hospice Cycle Sportive]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[This inaugural 68 mile circular route will take in the stunning scenery of West and South Yorkshire, creating a fabulous event that riders of all abilities can get involved in.

Starting at St Gemma's Hospice in Moortown the route takes cyclists past other hospices including Overgate, Kirkwood and Barnsley. There will be a checkpoint at each Hospice where water will be available and once back at St Gemma's you can enjoy refreshments, music and a well-earned rest.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4709]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[St. Gemma's Hospice]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4489]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[St Gemma's Hospice]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Jul 2014 6:30am]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10539_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10539_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9146]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[ASDA Foundation Leeds 10K]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Part of the Jane Tomlinson's 10K Series.

Smash your PB with our new flatter and faster course. Jane's legacy run, now in its eighth year.

]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3802]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds City Centre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[9145]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Run for All]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[20 Jul 2014 9:30am - 11:30am]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9146_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9146_0.jpg]]></image_original></item></objects></response>