<?xml version="1.0"?><response><status><![CDATA[200]]></status><status_message><![CDATA[OK]]></status_message><message><![CDATA[OK]]></message><objects><item><event_id><![CDATA[9843]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Grand Budapest Hotel ]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Wes Anderson's new film, THE GRAND BUDAPEST HOTEL, recounts the adventures of Gustave H, a legendary concierge at a famous European hotel between the wars,
and Zero Moustafa, the lobby boy who becomes his most trusted friend.

The story involves the theft and recovery of a priceless Renaissance painting and the battle for an enormous family fortune -- all against the back-drop of a suddenly and dramatically changing continent.


Director: Wes Anderson 
Country: US/DE, 2014
Duration: tbc
Certification: tbc
Starring: Saoirse Ronan, Ralph Fiennes, Edward Norton
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[317]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Hyde Park Picture House]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1370]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Hyde Park Picture House]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[7 Mar 2014 - 13 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9843.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9843.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10548]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Unstill]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Hugo Glendinning & John Avery

unstill by photographer and filmmaker Hugo Glendinning is a big-screen projected photo-work with newly commissioned music by John Avery (long-time collaborator with Forced Entertainment and Wendy Houstoun).

Glendinning's work draws on 30 years of photographing dance and performance, also including work from across his archive. John Avery's music both leads and follows the imagery in a series of long leaning notes that float, and are held, at once in motion and waiting to move.

This piece is part of Juncture 2014, Yorkshire Dance's festival of contemporary movement, theatre and film work, taking place at various venues throughout Leeds from 4-15 March. Juncture is curated by Wendy Houstoun, award-winning maker of art. 
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[7775]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Tetley ]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[9437]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[The Tetley]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[7 Mar 2014 - 15 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10548.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10548.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9845]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[JUNCTURE 2014: All This Can Happen & Touched]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[A flickering dance of intriguing imagery brings to light the possibilities of ordinary movements from the everyday which appear, evolve and freeze before your eyes. Made entirely from archive photographs and footage from the earliest days of moving image, ALL THIS CAN HAPPEN follows the footsteps of the protagonist from the short story 'The Walk' by writer Robert Walser. Juxtapositions, different speeds and split frame techniques convey the walker's state of mind as he encounters a world of hilarity, despair and ceaseless variety.

Also screening will be the short film TOUCHED choreographed by Wendy Houstoun and directed by David Hinton. This screening is part of Yorkshire Dance's Juncture 2014, a festival of contemporary movement, theatre and film work. 

www.yorkshiredance.com

Director: Siobhan Davies, David Hinton
Country: UK, 2012
Duration: 65mins approx
Certification: E
Starring: John Heffernan
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[317]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Hyde Park Picture House]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1370]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Hyde Park Picture House]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[9 Mar 2014 3:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9845.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9845.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10529]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Princess Bride]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Get ready for some swash-buckling adventuring and some fair maiden rescuing in this epic tongue in cheek fairy-tale romance.

Some may call it an action movie - with scenes including (but not limited to) - fencing, trickery, poisoning, torture, death and giants; but in truth this really is a romantic movie that puts Sleeping Beauty and Cinderella to shame.

Warning: Kissing Scenes

All tickets include a screening of The Princess Bride and a glass of Prosecco.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1544]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[White Cloth Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4002]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[White Cloth Gallery]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[9 Mar 2014 4:00pm - 7:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10529.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10529.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10340]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Breaking Bad - The Pub Quiz]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Traditional pub quizzes are boring, so we're taking the concept to a new level and a far more important topic - BREAKING BAD. Put all that binge TV-watching to good use and test your knowledge of the hit TV show through six rounds for cash and booze prizes.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[9073]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Belgrave Music Hall and Canteen]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10339]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Geeks Inc]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[9 Mar 2014 6:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10340.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10340.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10367]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Wadjda]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Free event, all welcome!

UTravelActive and Leeds STAR Bike Project are pleased to present a screening of the award-winning film Wadjda, to coincide with UTravelActive's Bike Belles campaign and International Women's Day 2014.

Wadjda is a 10-year-old girl living in a suburb of Riyadh, the capital of Saudi Arabia. Although she lives in a conservative world, Wadjda is fun loving, entrepreneurial and always pushing the boundaries of what she can get away with. 

Wadjda sees a beautiful green bicycle for sale that she wants desperately so she can race her friend, Abdullah. But Wadjda's mother won't allow it, fearing repercussions from a society that sees bicycles as dangerous to a girl's virtue. So Wadjda decides to try and raise the money herself. At first, Wadjda's mother is too preoccupied with convincing her husband not to take a second wife to realize what's going on. And soon enough Wadjda's plans are thwarted when she is caught running various schemes at school. 

Just as she is losing hope of raising enough money, she hears of a cash prize for a Koran recitation competition at her school. She devotes herself to the memorization and recitation of Koranic verses, and her teachers begin to see Wadjda as a model pious girl. The competition isn't going to be easy, especially for a troublemaker like Wadjda, but she refuses to give in. She is determined to continue fighting for her dreams...

Wadja is the first feature film shot entirely in Saudi Arabia and is the first feature-length film made by a female Saudi director.

Germany/Saudi Arabia/USA/United Arab Emirates 2012
Certificate PG 96m 54s
Directed by Haifaa al Mansour]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[9418]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[LT G.02 Maurice Keyworth Building]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[9419]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[UTravelActive]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[11 Mar 2014 6:00pm - 8:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10367.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10367.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9848]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Missing Picture (L'image manquante)]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Having chronicled the Pol Pot regime in documentaries such as S-21 THE KILLING MACHINE, director Rithy Panh returns to the subject with this deeply felt account of a childhood endured in various Khmer Rouge labour camps. In these camps Panh suffered profound hunger and brutality in conditions that saw the rest of his family perish. Looking back on the horrific events from middle age, he recreates his experiences with miniature clay figures. These totems of defiled childhood innocence fill the gap indicated in the title - the missing photographic record of the horror and oppression behind the government's official ideology. 

Director: Rithy Panh
Country: KH/FR, 2013 
Duration: 96mins
Certification: 12A
Narrated by: Randal Douc
French with English subtitles 
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[317]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Hyde Park Picture House]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1370]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Hyde Park Picture House]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[11 Mar 2014 6:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9848.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9848.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10279]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Caesar Must Die]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Prisoners in Italy put on a production of Shakespeare's 'Julius Caesar'.   As they rehearse, the prisoners, many of whom are long-termers and lifers for serious crimes, find that the classic play has both a striking resonance and a contrast to their confined lives. 

In partnership with Headingley LitFest 2014

If you would like to be on our mailing list please email with your name to filmsatheart@gmail.com]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[956]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Headingley Enterprise and Arts Centre (HEART)   ]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[9880]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Films at Heart]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[11 Mar 2014 8:00pm - 10:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10279.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10279.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9119]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Movie Matinees: Great Expectations]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[This new multi award winning version of the classic novel by Dickens follows the life of Pip, who starts out as a humble orphan and becomes a gentleman with the help of an unknown benefactor.  Miss Havisham is played by Helena Bonham Carter, Madwitch by Ralph Fiennes and Jaggers by Robbie Coltrane.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2142]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Otley Courthouse]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7150]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Otley Courthouse]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Mar 2014 1:30pm - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9119.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9119.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10117]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Hairspray]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[As part of our exhibition 'Saturday Girl' by acclaimed photographer Casey Orr, we are hosting a pop-up film night in the gallery showing John Water's infamous 1988 film, Hairspray! 

Cafe 164 will be open, selling teas coffees, cakes, and popcorn, and Leeds latest food pop-up Grub and Grog will be serving up some superb craft beers, stew and delicious nibbles.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[839]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Mar 2014 6:30pm - 9:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10117_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10117_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[7526]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Oblong Cinema]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Oblong Cinema is a monthly event to discover and showcase local filmmaking talent in Leeds & Yorkshire with a different theme each month - this March the theme is Documentary.

(Image is from 'Closure' a film about our fast-disappearing pubs)

Run by filmmakers for filmmakers, Oblong Cinema's schedule is an eclectic mix of programmed and submitted work and we are always looking for films by Yorkshire filmmakers.

Oblong Cinema showcases short films in the hall at Woodhouse Community Centre with an intimate and friendly screening, encouraging audience feedback and Q+A's with filmmakers. Join us for a fun night of films and networking - and free popcorn!

Oblong Cinema screens at Woodhouse Community Centre on the first Thursday of each month from 7pm - 8pm ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[184]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Woodhouse Community Centre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7525]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Oblong Cinema]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Mar 2014 7:00pm - 8:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/7526_10.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/7526_10.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10546]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Riots Reframed]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Hard-hitting documentary which reframes England's 2011 riots in the context of the role played by police, power, racism, government, prison, war, resistance and more.

Screenings followed by discussion with:

Fahim Alam, Producer
Claude Hendrickson, Race Card Project Manager at Leeds West Indian Centre Charitable Trust
Lutel James, Strategic Leader at Chapeltown Youth Development Centre
Khadijah Ibrahiim, Artistic Director at Leeds Young Authors
Richard Smith, Leeds Black Film Club & founder of Leeds Black Awards
Sai MuRai, poet/facilitator on Platform's youth arts and activism project 
Shake!, creative director of Liquorice Fish.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2954]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds West Indian Centre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10545]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds No Borders]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Mar 2014 7:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10546_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10546_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9242]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Fish 'N' Reels]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Otley Film Society and Otley Action for Older People present two classic films from the '40s and '50s together with a fish and chip supper (or veggie) in the interval.

]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2142]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Otley Courthouse]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[9241]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Otley Film Society and otley Action for Older people]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[15 Mar 2014 3:00pm - 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9242.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9242.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10530]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[True Romance]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Ticket price includes free popcorn, powdered sugar doughnuts and a beer.

True Romance is a 1993 American romantic crime film directed by Tony Scott and written by Quentin Tarantino and it certainly isn't your run-of-the-mill love story.

A modern day Bonnie and Clyde. Clarence and Alabama meet, fall in love. They then proceed to steal a whole lot of drugs from Alabama's pimp and try to sell it in Hollywood, while the owners of the coke try to reclaim it.

The film stars Christian Slater and Patrica Arquette, and includes stellar performances by Christopher Walken, Gary Oldman, Dennis Hopper, Brad Pitt (as a total pothead), and James Gandolfini. Even Val Kilmer as "Elvis" makes a cameo.

As ever, the White Cloth Gallery Bar will be open, serving drinks and food to enjoy whilst watching the movie.

What better way to spend a Sunday afternoon. You could do worse my friend, you could do worse.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1544]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[White Cloth Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4002]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[White Cloth Gallery]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[16 Mar 2014 4:00pm - 7:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10530.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10530.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10547]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Leeds No Borders Film & Music Night]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[An amazing double bill...

We will be showing a brilliant Malian film called Bamako -https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=onRjI8yLsy0 (trailer).

Followed by political folk-pop from Faith Taylor and Crazy Divine, who are stopping by as part of their spring tour together. Check them out here...

http://www.faithtaylor.net/
https://soundcloud.com/crazydivine

This is part of an ongoing educational, political and cultural project to screen films and documentaries that might broaden our understandings of issues that affect some of the most vulnerable yet strongest people in our world today.

Hot soup and bread will be served so COME EARLY to be fed!]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1603]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Wharf Chambers]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10545]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds No Borders]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[18 Mar 2014 6:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10547_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10547_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10501]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Fantomas - Biography Of An Imaginary Criminal]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Presented in English by guest speakers Loic Artiaga (University of Limoges) and Matthieu Letourneux (Univ. Paris-Ouest Nanterre)

The arch-criminal Fantomas was a popular fictional character throughout Europe in the early 20th century, first invented by the popular authors Pierre Souvestre and Marcel Allain in a series of 32 novels published 1911-13, becoming a pan-European anti-hero through the films of Feuillade (1913-14). He has re-appeared in films and comics up to the present day. 

To see some of the early Feuillade silent films see Youtube:

http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dr96bljszWI
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=993NAHyDylg
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lx17rDzUnnU
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VqJjdlj2EmQ

This event is open to all and will include a drinks reception afterwards. ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1732]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The University of Leeds]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10500]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Diana Holmes]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[19 Mar 2014 4:00pm - 6:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10501_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10501_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10554]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[What's Happening In Calais?]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Film screening and talk about Calais Migrant Solidarity.

Leeds No Borders have visited Calais a number of times in the last year to drop off donations, cook & hang out with migrants stuck at the border. We will be heading out again soon so this is a great introduction for anyone thinking of joining us or just wanting to know more. There's recently been an increase in fascist attacks in Calais and a crack down on anyone trying to shelter in the many empty buildings there. Hear the latest from migrants who have recently undertaken the risky journey to the UK and now live in Leeds.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[10553]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Maurice Keyworth Room SR 1.15]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10545]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds No Borders]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[25 Mar 2014 7:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10554_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10554_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10605]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Ice Cold In Alex]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[During the Western Desert Campaign of the Second World War, a British unit is attacked by the German Afrika Korps in the coastal town of Tobruk. 

During the evacuation which follows, Captain Anson (John Mills), a near-alcoholic transport pool officer, Sergeant- Major Tom Pugh (Harry Andrews) and two nurses - Diana Murdoch (Sylvia Sims) and Denise Norton (Diane Clare) team up to drive 'Katy', a military ambulance, across the desert with the intention of reaching British lines and safety. 

Christopher Landon wrote the screenplay for the film, based on his novel.  He knew his subject well: he had been in the RAMC (Royal Army Medical Corps) and had driven ambulances in North Africa.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[964]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Cottage Road Cinema]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[6703]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Headingley LitFest]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[26 Mar 2014 ]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10605.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10605.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10119]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Crazy About One Direction: A Film By Daisy Asquith]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Gallery Munro House opens it doors for something special....

A one - off film screening of Daisy Asquith's 'Crazy About One Direction' and director discussion.

Directioners are a rare breed of fan. Connected to their idols through social media, they have a love and dedication like no other. These are the girls that heart One Direction.

Daisy Asquith's documentary reveals what it truly means to be a Directioner, the lengths they will go to meet 1D, and how these teenage girls are united in their love of the most popular boy band in the world.

From Milton Keynes to Glasgow, Directioners dedicate their lives and their money to following Harry, Zayn, Niall, Liam and Louis. They camp out before and after concerts, book into hotels and watch Twitter constantly to get an idea of where the boys might be.

With their love of 1D being compared to drug addiction, the belief that Twitter is like a form of prayer communication with the boys, and girls getting braces and tattoos just to have something in common with their heart-throbs, is this the future of the fan?

Daisy Asquith will be present during this event to answer any questions. 
 
Please enter via Cafe 164 where hot and cold refreshments will be available to purchase. Screening will start at 7pm. 

This event is part of an exhibition, 'Saturday Girl' by acclaimed photographer Casey Orr. 

For more details of other events linked to this, please visit the website(right).]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[839]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[840]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Gallery]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[26 Mar 2014 6:30pm - 9:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10119_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10119_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[8346]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Hush Hush Film Night]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The night will showcase the best in Northern film-making talent, exhibiting short films spanning a variety of different techniques and genres. 

Drinks and popcorn are available on the night.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4142]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Base]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[26 Sep 2013 - 31 Jul 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/8346.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/8346.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10549]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Minicine At The Mills: Zift]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The final film in our Modern Monochrome season, Javor Gardev's Bulgarian crime drama, ZIFT, tells the story of Moth - a petty criminal wrongfully convicted of murder.

Jailed shortly before the Bulgarian communist coup of 1944, he now finds himself in a new and alien world - the totalitarian Sofia of the 1960s. His first night of freedom draws the map of a diabolical city full of decaying neighbourhoods, gloomy streets and a bizarre parade of characters.

Like his namesake to a flame, it is not long before Moth is drawn back to his old habits. Part La Haine-part Chopper, Zift is both brutal and funny, romantic while packing one hell of a punch.

Our feature presentation will be preceded by a selection of short films plus a preview of our upcoming African season.

Tea, coffee and homemade cake will be available on arrival.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[151]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Armley Mills Leeds Industrial Museum]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[2938]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Minicine]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[27 Mar 2014 7:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10549.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10549.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10291]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Film Making: Part II]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Film editing with professional film makers The Creative Condition. With a premiere screening to follow!...

Mike Cooper and Jay Sillence will be back in the Gallery to help you through the editing processes involved in film production. Part 2 of a two day workshop, this is open to all who attended Film Making: Part 1 (http://take-one.eventbrite.co.uk) as  well as anyone interested in the post-production stage of film making.

The session will begin with a review of the footage gathered the previous week (cut down to the best takes by Jay and his team in preparation for the workshop), the editing process itself and will end with a screening of the films made during the workshops.

The work produced will be available on the Gallery website for a few weeks as well as the Gallery's youtube page so that you can share your work and show others your name on the big screen!


The Creative Condition (www.thecreativecondition.co.uk) are a creative agency team made up of three York based entrepreneurs, who work hard to support individuals and business alike. Their client list to date involves Officers and Gary Numan, Lush Cosmetics, Contact Theater, The Quietus, York St John University and plenty more. Put simply, they say; "we have a passion for people and stories. Stories are what bring us together so we combine our skills to engage and excite people about events, products and projects." They are three of the loveliest people you are likely to meet...]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4854]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Stanley & Audrey Burton Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1403]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Stanley & Audrey Burton Gallery]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[29 Mar 2014 1:30pm - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10291.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10291.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9298]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Film With Live Score: New Babylon]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Shostakovish had a born dramatist's sense... The New Babylon score is full of moments in which the music directly, unambiguously accompanies the screen' NY Times
Trauberg and Kozintsev's great masterpiece of Soviet avant-garde cinema is a powerful story of the 1871 Paris commune told through the eyes of a shop-girl working in the New Babylon emporium.

Scored by the then 23 year old Dmitri Shostakovich, the film is accompanied live by the Orchestra of Opera North. Bursting with jazz and cabaret inspired music, this is Shostakovich at his most satirical. Together, the film and music reflect both on revolutionary Russia and the enduring Russian fascination with Paris.

Film courtesy of European Film Philharmonic Institute.
Music courtesy of Sikorski Musikverlage
Dir.Trauberg and Kozintsev; USSR; 1929; 96 mins]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1026]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4191]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[29 Mar 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9298.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9298.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10353]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Leeds Young Film Festival 2014]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Looking for something exciting for all the family to do this Easter? Leeds Young Film Festival 2014 is a perfect way for young people to enjoy the Easter holidays with their families - at a fantastic price. 

There are films, events, animation and filmmaking workshops, and activities ideal for young people. There will be plenty for older audiences including a Teen Gala, 25th Anniversary screenings of cinema classics and some of the most popular films from the 27th Leeds International Film Festival too. 

The full festival programme will feature screenings and events at venues including the Hyde Park Picture House, Everyman Leeds and Leeds Town Hall but we are already very pleased to announce a screening of the new film Horizon Beautiful (pictured), a wonderful story about a 12 year old Ethiopian street kid who discovers something more important than fulfilling his dream of becoming a professional footballer.
 
On Saturday 5 April we have an extra-special Scooby Doo event for audiences aged three and up. There will be lots of Scooby Doo related activities, together with a screening of the animated film Scooby Doo and the Cyber Chase in which Scooby and the gang are trapped inside a video game and must defeat a phantom virus. A real-life Mystery Machine will be making an appearance at the event so you can have your photo taken in it with Scooby Doo himself!
 
We will welcome very special guest David Dimbleby to the 2014 Leeds Young Filmmaker Golden Owls Awards, an Oscars style ceremony for young filmmakers aged between three and 19, at Leeds Town Hall on Wednesday 2 April. Hyde Park Picture House will host The INDIs (Independent Directions) Awards on Monday 7 April, the UK's only film competition which solely champions and celebrates the talent of the UK's independent filmmakers under 25.
 
Come and be a part of all of this and more for exceptional value for money.
 
Leeds Young Film Festival is presented by MediaFish and Leeds City Council. MediaFish is a cooperative of young people aged 14 - 19 from Leeds that are facilitated by Leeds Young Film. MediaFish are involved in the organisation, programme and marketing of the Leeds Young Film Festival and provide a variety of film screenings, workshops and masterclasses for all ages year round.

For more information please visit www.leedsyoungfilm.co.uk]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[317]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Hyde Park Picture House]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1039]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Young Film Festival]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[31 Mar 2014 - 11 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10353_1.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10353_1.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10612]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[When The Wind Blows]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Beloved British writer and illustrator Raymond Briggs celebrates his eightieth birthday this year so the Picture House is proud to present in partnership with Headingley LitFest this beautiful adaptation of his classic 1986 work.

Jim and Hilda Bloggs are a typical, retired couple in rural England. They drink endless cups of tea and have an unwavering faith in the wisdom of their government. They understand that a Third World War is imminent between the US and the Soviets. However, they fail to grasp the concept that war will be fought by nuclear means, and what consequences this will have.

This animated film, directed by Jimmy T Murakami, features the voices of Peggy Ashcroft, John Mills and Robin Houston. PG certificate.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[317]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Hyde Park Picture House]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[6703]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Headingley LitFest]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[31 Mar 2014 6:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10612.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10612.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9120]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The King's Speech]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The story of King George V1 (Colin Firth) and his impromptu ascension to the throne, and the speech therapist (Geoffrey Rush), who helped the unsure monarch become worthy of his title.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2142]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Otley Courthouse]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[10 Apr 2014 1:30pm - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9120.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9120.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9299]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Great Flood]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[American Routes

'one of the highlights of the 2012 London jazz festival' The Guardian

In the spring of 1927, the Mississippi river broke its banks in 145 places and inundated 27,000 square miles to a depth of up to 30 feet. One of the most destructive floods in history, part of its enduring legacy was the mass exodus of displaced sharecroppers. Musically, the 'Great Migration' of rural southern blacks to northern cities saw the Delta Blues electrified and reinterpreted as the Chicago Blues, Rhythm and Blues, and Soul.

Using minimal text and no spoken dialogue, filmmaker Bill Morrison and composer / guitarist Bill Frisell create a powerful portrait of a seminal moment in American history, through a collection of silent images matched to a searing original soundtrack.

Soundtrack by Bill Frisell. Please note the soundtrack is recorded.

Dir Bill Morrison; 2011; 80mins, USA]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1026]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4191]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[12 Apr 2014 8:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9299.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9299.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10341]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Game Of Thrones - The Pub Quiz]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Traditional pub quizzes are boring, so we're taking the concept to a new level and a far more important topic - GAME OF THRONES. Put all that binge TV-watching to good use and test your knowledge of the hit TV show through six rounds for cash and booze prizes. ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[9073]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Belgrave Music Hall and Canteen]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10339]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Geeks Inc]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Apr 2014 6:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10341.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10341.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10446]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Family Film: Madagascar]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Children and Families Movie Matinees Easter Film:

Spoiled by their upbringing with no idea what wild life is really like, four animals from New York Central Zoo escape, unwittingly assisted by four absconding penguins, and find themselves in Madagascar, among a bunch of merry lemurs.

Ice creams and popcorn available.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2142]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Otley Courthouse]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7150]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Otley Courthouse]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[17 Apr 2014 2:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10446.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10446.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9282]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Film With Live Score: Sunrise]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[A Song of Two Humans

With newly commissioned live soundtrack by Joanna MacGregor and Andy Sheppard.

'Inspirational, intense and deeply moving' The Arts Desk on Joanna MacGregor

Taking inspiration from the music of Tom Waits, Johnny Cash and traditional American spirituals, pianist Joanna MacGregor and jazz saxophonist Andy Sheppard create a new live score for Sunrise, F.W. Murnau's 1927 masterpiece of silent film, especially for the Howard Assembly Room.

Made in the twilight of the silent era, Sunrise became a swan-song for the vanishing medium and one of its greatest expressions, a story about innocence and experience, urban and rural America, about love and violence.

As part of an ongoing fascination with film and music, this Sunrise live soundtrack explores the effect that music has on film and vice-versa.

Supported by the Opera North Future Fund]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1026]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4191]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[26 Apr 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9282.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9282.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10342]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Sherlock - The Pub Quiz]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Traditional pub quizzes are boring, so we're taking the concept to a new level and a far more important topic - SHERLOCK. Put all that binge TV-watching to good use and test your knowledge of the hit TV show through six rounds for cash and booze prizes. ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[9073]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Belgrave Music Hall and Canteen]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10339]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Geeks Inc]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[11 May 2014 6:00pm - 8:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10342.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10342.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10109]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Tour De Cinema]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The Tour de Cinema, working with National Trust, Cine Yorkshire and many other partners, will unveil thirty super-high-definition screens in unusual locations across Yorkshire for an unrivalled programme of fiction and non-fiction films about cycling.

The programme includes a brand new commission teaming up award-winning director Daisy Asquith with composer Bill Nelson and drawing on rare BFI film and music archives to chart the journey of the bicycle from new technology to familiar household transport.

It also highlights forgotten treasures like Alan Bennett's rarely seen BBC film from the 1970s - A Day Out, about a Halifax cycling club, and is a chance to see The Big Melt, paying homage to a century of steel-making with a blazing soundtrack compiled by Sheffield's Jarvis Cocker.

Alongside these gems, The Yorkshire Film Archive introduces a newly compiled film drawn from cine club and home movie collections to show cycling in all its forms, from childhood to adulthood.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[295]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Millennium Square]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10108]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Festival Yorkshire]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[21 May 2014 ]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10109.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10109.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9304]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[FILMusic: Grouper And Paul Clipson]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[American Routes

HYPNOSIS DISPLAY

'The music of Grouper creates a feeling that can only be defined as awe, an uncanny mixture of wonder and dread that nobody does better' Pitchfork

A new FILMusic commission by Opera North, HYPNOSIS DISPLAY is a meditation on contemporary America in sound and image. Portland based musician Grouper (Liz Harris) juxtaposes layers of processed field recording, choral vocal harmony and keyboard in a resonant framework that moves behind and through Paul Clipson's 16mm film. Clipson's densely rhythmical images in turn traverse Grouper's musical language to create startling, revelatory, and critical associations.

Together they invite the audience to participate in a collective mind's-eye trip through landscapes of American myth making, including: the west coast, the worker, the city and the street.
Commissioned by Opera North Projects
Supported by the Opera North Future Fund]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1026]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4191]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[5 Jun 2014 7:45pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9304.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9304.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10110]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Tour De Cinema]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The Tour de Cinema, working with National Trust, Cine Yorkshire and many other partners, will unveil thirty super-high-definition screens in unusual locations across Yorkshire for an unrivalled programme of fiction and non-fiction films about cycling.

The programme includes a brand new commission teaming up award-winning director Daisy Asquith with composer Bill Nelson and drawing on rare BFI film and music archives to chart the journey of the bicycle from new technology to familiar household transport.

It also highlights forgotten treasures like Alan Bennett's rarely seen BBC film from the 1970s - A Day Out, about a Halifax cycling club, and is a chance to see The Big Melt, paying homage to a century of steel-making with a blazing soundtrack compiled by Sheffield's Jarvis Cocker.

Alongside these gems, The Yorkshire Film Archive introduces a newly compiled film drawn from cine club and home movie collections to show cycling in all its forms, from childhood to adulthood.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[295]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Millennium Square]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10108]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Festival Yorkshire]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[15 Jun 2014 ]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10110.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10110.jpg]]></image_original></item></objects></response>