<?xml version="1.0"?><response><status><![CDATA[200]]></status><status_message><![CDATA[OK]]></status_message><message><![CDATA[OK]]></message><objects><item><event_id><![CDATA[9591]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Quiz Night]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Every Thursday join join our Quiz Night with a Twist ;)]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[9587]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Inkwell Bar]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[26 Dec 2013 - 24 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9591.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9591.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10117]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Hairspray]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[As part of our exhibition 'Saturday Girl' by acclaimed photographer Casey Orr, we are hosting a pop-up film night in the gallery showing John Water's infamous 1988 film, Hairspray! 

Cafe 164 will be open, selling teas coffees, cakes, and popcorn, and Leeds latest food pop-up Grub and Grog will be serving up some superb craft beers, stew and delicious nibbles.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[839]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Mar 2014 6:30pm - 9:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10117_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10117_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10052]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Bare Plume]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Bare Plume club night returns to Wharf Chambers with its winning mix of live bands, DJs, vegan food and cocktails indulging senses on a shoestring. 

This time with performances from

Jooklo Duo
Head and soul cleansing Italian blazing free improv sax and drums duo revered by The Wire, Henry Rollins and all believers in spiritual redemption through 'the good energy'. Previous collaborators include Bill Nace, Sonic Youth and Merce Cunningham.
http://jooklo.altervista.org/

Gelba
Guitar, tape loops and field recordings duo also from Italy.
http://gelba.bandcamp.com/

Dave Jackson
Improvised sax from Solar Fire Trio man.
http://davejackson.bandcamp.com/

Elizabeth
Ambient guitarscapes and projections by Andy Abbott of That F#cking Tank / Nope.

Vegan food and cocktails from 6pm | Bands from 8pm | DJs from 11pm.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1603]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Wharf Chambers]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10051]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[BARE PLUME]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[14 Mar 2014 6:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10052.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10052.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9593]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Saturday Night Live]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Every Saturday join us for Live Music or DJ from 8pm.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[9587]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Inkwell Bar]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[28 Dec 2013 - 3 Jan 2015]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9593.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9593.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10412]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Paddy's Day Celebration!]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[We're really looking forward to Paddy's Day this year and hope you'll pop down to celebrate with us. We've got something for everyone, with a very special selection of meats and cheeses as well as some exciting new scotch egg flavours. Our guest beers are coming from 'Eight Degrees Brewing' in Cork, as well as beers from other Irish brewers such as Evin from 'The Kernel' and Gregg from 'Weird Beard'.

There will also be some traditional music provided by Dr Reel Good, a lively folk band playing the best in Irish songs and jigs to keep us in high spirits. 

We can't promise you novelty hats but it promises to be a fun evening of tasty treats and toe tapping tunes. Music begins at 7.30pm and entry is free.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[6498]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Friends of Ham]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[17 Mar 2014 ]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10412.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10412.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10586]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Dinner Date With Dante]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Listen to La Divina Commedia - well, not exactly all of it - by Italy's greatest poet, Dante Alighieri together with extracts from some of the storiesin Giovanni Bocaccio's Decamerone - yes, including the ones you might have in mind.

The readings will be in Italian and English, and there will be a light supper. You'll be in Paradiso!
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[940]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Salvo's Restaurant & Salumeria]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[6703]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Headingley LitFest]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[17 Mar 2014 7:15pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10586.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10586.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10551]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Leeds No Borders Monthly Social]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Come along for a celebratory night of food, music, dancing, short films, poetry and talks with a Zimbabwean theme.

All welcome, bring friends and family. Bring along your favourite tunes and let's dance!

Delicious food - bring something to share if you can.

It's 'open mic' so if you want to perform, just step up!]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1603]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Wharf Chambers]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10545]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds No Borders]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[23 Mar 2014 3:00pm - 8:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10551_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10551_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10451]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Magical Musical Feast At Hansa's]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[A Keep Streets Live Fundraiser.

The Keep Streets Live Campaign exists to keep our public spaces open to informal performances of art & music. Street culture is under severe threat across the UK but particularly in Camden, perhaps London's most musical borough, where a new law criminalises street musicians and threatens them with large fines and instrument confiscations, and the sale of musical instruments to pay fines. We are crowd-sourcing the funds to challenge this decision in the High Court to send a strong message to local authorities and national government: Support street culture, don't strangle it!

Our friends at Hansas Restaurant in Leeds, winners of the prestigious Cobra award for "Best UK Indian Vegetarian Restaurant" have offered us their restaurant for a unique fundraiser: a delicious three course meal, music between courses from the remarkably talented Beccy Owen, The Jamie Fletcher Band, Jonny Walker and many more, punctuating your culinary delight with melody. Between courses and performances there will be the obligatory raffle and we are delighted to announce that an expert in antiques and professional auctioneer has volunteered their services for what will be the inaugural interactive Keep Streets Live Auction... If you have ideas for the auction feel free to bring them along, we hope to auction off poems, songs, house gigs, luxury beauty treatments, guitars and much more besides! 

Links

http://leeds-list.com/a-leeds-restaurant-to-celebrate/
http://www.hansasrestaurant.com/
http://beccyowen.bandcamp.com/music
https://www.facebook.com/JamieFletcherBand
http://www.facebook.com/JonnySongs

We are strictly limited to 95 places for this one off event,
places/tickets are available via the crowd-funding website, just click through on the "tickets" link below make your
contribution. All funds raised will go the fighting fund of the Keep
Streets Live Campaign. Places are not confirmed until the perk has been claimed via the indiegogo link!]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[10449]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Hansa's Gujarati Restaurant]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10450]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Keep Streets Live]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[23 Mar 2014 5:00pm - 9:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10451_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10451_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10257]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Captain's Table - Vegan Supper Club With That Old Chestnut]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[After a short break The Captain's Table returns to Outlaws Yacht Club. This month our host will be That Old Chestnut the vegan bakery who will be putting together the menu for our first 100% vegan supper club.

For those who don't know That Old Chestnut are a small vegan bakery run by Elly & Chris in Leeds, West Yorkshire.

They began life in 2009 holding a stall once a month at Kirkgate Farmer's Market. They now supply to a number of cafes, shops and deli's within the Leeds and York area as well as holding regular stalls and occasional events.

They source many of their ingredients from Lembas Ltd (a Sheffield based wholefoods company), and Natural Food Store, a cooperative in Headingley. Their fresh ingredients are bought from local grocers, Kirkgate Market and Bardon Grange Growing Project - helping them support local independent businesses.

All of their food is 100% vegan and they run their business with the following values as much as possible: local, sustainable, ethical and handmade.

We look forward to welcoming them on board and invite you to join us at the captain's table. ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3679]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Outlaws Yacht Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7768]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Outlaws Yacht Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[26 Mar 2014 6:00pm - 10:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10257.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10257.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9897]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Mother And Daughter Day]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Mother's Day Tea Party.

Join us for a Mad Hatter's tea party with cream topped scones, drizzled cakes, spicy wraps and finger sandwiches all served on vintage china! 

This charity fundraiser is focusing on making your mum feel special and is an ideal girly day out. We will have craft corner with a range of volunteers showing you the basics of knitting, furniture painting and more. A raffle, goody bags, photo opportunities, children's activities, music and lots more. We will also have an Indian head masseuse on hand to shoo those tensions away! ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[7001]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[SLATE The Feel Good Cafe]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[9896]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Samantha Dodds]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[30 Mar 2014 11:00am - 3:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9897.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9897.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10234]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Amazing Graze]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Leeds Street Culture Festival brought to you by Left Bank Leeds and Manjit's Kitchen.

Please bring cash for food and art stalls. Art workshops for all ages. A celebration of award-winning street food, music, art and bazaar brought in from the streets of Leeds and beyond! 

Stir it Up on Saturday evening features the Valv-A-Tron a handbuilt all valve sound System playing the very best in vintage,classic reggae music. Emjay and Dr Huxtable at the controls. Local  bands and DJs on Sunday evening. For the latest line-up follow us on Twitter (see links to right).

manjitskitchen.com]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[759]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Left Bank]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1617]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Manjit's Kitchen]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[5 Apr 2014 - 6 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10234.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10234.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10461]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[North Leeds Charity Beer Festival 2014]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Fans of beer and live music can swell the coffers of the Lord Mayors Appeal by attending the North Leeds Charity Beer Festival to be held on Friday 30th and Saturday 31st May 2014 at St Aidan's Community Hall on Roundhay Road. The Rotary Club of Roundhay will also be raising money for additional local, national and international charities.

This year the North Leeds Charity Beer Festival organised by The Rotary Club of Roundhay in association with The Lord Mayor of Leeds will have a Tour de France theme. Seventeen exclusive Le Tour de Yorkshire Grand Depart beers will be brewed especially for the 2014 festival. A further eleven beers brewed in Leeds will be served "in the wood". We will also have a selection of ciders and English Country Wines on offer.

CAMRA, The Campaign for Real Ale are offering their assistance and expert knowledge and their many volunteers will be making sure the beers are served correctly. A spokesman said, "If this is the first time anyone has visited a Beer Festival we want to ensure their experience is one they will enjoy and savour and will hook them to how beer should really taste

No event is complete without live music and there will be a number of bands performing throughout the North Leeds Charity Beer Festival. St Aidan's Community Hall is set over two floors so there will also be a quieter area where those who wish to can enjoy their beer in peace. Locally produced food will also be available and served at all times. 
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[5315]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[St Aidan's Community Hall]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5316]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[The Rotary Club of Roundhay, Leeds]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[30 May 2014 - 31 May 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10461_1.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10461_1.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10514]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Veg Out 2014]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[A vegetarian food & drink festival with music & art 

FOOD & DRINK

Bundobust http://bundobust.com/
Vegetarian Indian street food kitchen

The Grub & Grog Shop http://www.grubandgrog.co.uk/
Stews, sandwiches & salads in many shapes and forms

That Old Chestnut http://thatoldchestnutishere.com/
Irresistible vegan cakes, baked goods & savouries

The Wheely Nice Ice Cream Tricycle
A fun, vintage, environmentally friendly ice cream tricycle

Laynes Espresso http://www.laynesespresso.co.uk/
Serving the best coffee in Leeds since 2011

Leeds Bread Coop http://leedsbread.coop/
Leeds based artisan bakery

The Real Cider Company http://realcidercompany.co.uk/
Hand crafted ciders

MUSIC - SATURDAY

Bearfoot Beware http://bearfootbeware.co.uk/
Energetic & scrappy alternative rock band from Leeds

Juffage http://juffage.com/
a solo sound artist and multi-instrumentalist from Leeds UK, via Chicago, Illinois.

Magnapinna http://magnapinna.bandcamp.com/
A trio of handsomes who play jarring, groove-laden repeato rock

Douga http://douga.bandcamp.com/
A rich mix of warm psychedelia, Americana and more European experimental influences.

IMP http://impblogblog.blogspot.co.uk/
Habitual popsters practicing a riff heavy-pop chime with hi-deluxe vocal melodies

Plus Stuart Benjamin Briggs spinning funk, soul and disco vinyl in the bar room. http://tightenupleeds.tumblr.com/

AFTERPARTY DJS

Vessels DJs

Matt Woodward (Galaxians/Release Yourself)

MUSIC - SUNDAY (Hosted by Youth Anthems)

Middleman http://www.middlemanband.co.uk/Welcome!/Home.html
4-piece alternative rap rock band based in Leeds

Pifco http://pifco1.bandcamp.com/
Somewhere between the dry Nothern wit of The Fall and the party sounds of Bis or Devo

Zapiain http://zapiain.bandcamp.com/
Bombed Out Records finest are here to bring the 90's punk rock sound of Leeds to your ears

We Died at Sea http://wediedatsea.bandcamp.com/
Guitars, violins, double bass and even the odd kazoo

Just Another Warning http://justanotherwarning.bandcamp.com/
One man socio political acoustic punk rock!

ART

Hope House Prints
Live screen printing

PLUS MUCH MORE TBC]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1603]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Wharf Chambers]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10255]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[The Grub & Grog Shop]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[31 May 2014 - 1 Jun 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10514.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10514.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10416]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Campfire Cooking With Chris Ensor]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Al fresco cooking at its most fun with our very own man of the woods Chris Ensor!

Join us for a hands on day spent in our woods round the fire with Chris guiding you through the art of campfire cooking.  During the day we will be preparing a variety of dishes and looking at different cooking techniques which can be utilised when out in the wilderness.

Happy times spent outdoors plus something extra special to excite the taste buds!

You can book via Eventbrite or our website where you can also check out other exciting workshops we are planning.

All proceeds will go to support the great charitable work of The Conservation Volunteers at Skelton Grange Environment Centre!
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[5420]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Skelton Grange Environment Centre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5423]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Skelton Grange]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[12 Jul 2014 10:00am - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10416.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10416.jpg]]></image_original></item></objects></response>