<?xml version="1.0"?><response><status><![CDATA[200]]></status><status_message><![CDATA[OK]]></status_message><message><![CDATA[OK]]></message><objects><item><event_id><![CDATA[10454]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Herculaneum: New Discoveries, New Problems]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Prof. Andrew Walace-Hadrill (Director of the Herculaneum Conservation Project) provides the fourth lecture in a six-lecture series organised by Dr Virginia Campbell with the support of The Leverhulme Trust.

The lecture will also be available afterwards as a vodcast through Virginia's pompeiinetworks blog.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1944]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[University of Leeds]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[3948]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Classics@Leeds]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[19 Mar 2014 3:00pm - 4:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10454.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10454.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9973]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Early Music Lent Tour]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Early Music Tour during Lent


The Churches Conservation Trust, the national charity protecting historic churches at risk are proud to announce their collaboration with internationally acclaimed early music ensemble Poeticall Musicke.

In March Poeticall Musicke will be touring and performing their beautiful Tenebrae Programme in 8 historic churches in the care of The Churches Conservation Trust up and down the country.

On 26 March the Tour comes to Leeds where the musicians will be playing the wonderful St John the Evangelist Church.

We hope you will join us for what will be a wonderful evening.  For more information and to book your tickets please visit www.tenebraetour.co.uk
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[9098]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[St John the Evangelist]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[9972]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[The Churches Conservation Trust]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[26 Mar 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9973.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9973.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9525]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Leeds Town Hall Tours]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Explore the hidden secret side to the Town Hall! This tour is your chance to stand at the dock where prisoners once stood, sit at the judge's bench in the Courtroom, see the Victorian prison cells and climb the 203 steps to the top of the clock tower to see the clock whilst taking in a view of Leeds unlike any other.

Saturdays: 10.30am & 1pm  
Mondays:   2.30pm

Private tours: We are also able to offer private tours at a date/time to suit you (including Saturdays and evenings). Tours are &pound;100 and we can take up to 25 people. Call 0113 2476419 to enquire.

Please note: for those unable to ascend the clock tower stairs an audio-visual presentation will be available upon request. If the weather is particularly bad then we will not be able to take people onto the outside of the clock tower.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[313]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Town Hall]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[3903]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[ArtsDevLeeds]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[25 Jan 2014 - 28 Jul 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9525.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9525.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9402]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[We Will Be Free ]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[From Townsend Productions who brought you The Ragged Trousered Philanthropists in Spring 2013 comes a new play of the story of The Tolpuddle Martyrs. 

We Will Be Free is the true story of George and Betsy Loveless and the Dorset farm labourers who colluded to form a Trade Union in 1834 to fight against the local landowner.

This inspirational tale tells of their conviction and transportation by an oppressive government. Their determination, solidarity and courage is presented using an entertaining theatrical style, political cartoon, puppetry and folk music.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[304]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Carriageworks Theatre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[3 Apr 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9402.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9402.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10485]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Sex [Latin For 6] Degrees Of Separation]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Dr Virginia Campbell presents the final talk in the six-lecture "The Present and Future of Vesuvian Research" research seminar series, focusing on social networks in Pompeii.

The talk will be in lecture theatre 3 (LT3) of the Clthworkers' Building, entrance opposite the Students Union.

Dr. Campbell holds a Leverhulme Early Career Fellowship for her project 'Social Network Analysis in Pompeii.' Her work on the tombs of Pompeii led to an interest in the epigraphic evidence from Pompeii and how this can be examined to explore the connectedness of the community. One of her recent publications, 'Menedemerumenus: tracing the routes of Pompeian graffiti writers,' Tyche (2012), demonstrates one way the graffiti can be used to study networks in an ancient city. Her blog further documents her initial work on this project. 

The talk will be available online as a vodcast after the event through Virginia's Pompeian Connections blog.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1944]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[University of Leeds]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[3948]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Classics@Leeds]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[30 Apr 2014 3:00pm - 4:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10485.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10485.jpg]]></image_original></item></objects></response>