<?xml version="1.0"?><response><status><![CDATA[200]]></status><status_message><![CDATA[OK]]></status_message><message><![CDATA[OK]]></message><objects><item><event_id><![CDATA[8786]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Cleopatra]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[In a world ruled by men, this courageous and compulsive woman overturned convention and changed the course of history.

Cleopatra's legacy has inspired generations. Now, composer Claude-Michel Schonberg (Miss Saigon, Les Miserables) and Northern Ballet Artistic Director David Nixon OBE, bring her astounding story to the stage in this must-see ballet for 2011.

As Cleopatra's star rises once more, book now for Northern Ballet's unique retelling of this remarkable woman's story.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[394]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Grand Theatre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[8784]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Northern Ballet]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[6 Mar 2014 - 15 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/8786.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/8786.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10133]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Words On Tap: Open-Mic Showcase]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Presented by Headingley Litfest ... 

One of Leeds' most successful monthly literary events will take part in this year's LitFest. Following appearances from national poets such as Michael Symmons Roberts and Helen Mort, not-for-profit Words on Tap will invite emerging local wordsmiths from the city to take part in an open-mic showcase. 

The Chemic Tavern is one Leeds's most celebrated public houses, providing the ideal setting for an informal evening of verse and drink. Always a warm response from the audience and decent pint in the glass, this is a perfect opportunity for any poets wanting to try out new material or take their first steps onto the spoken word stage.

The Words on Tap ethos is very simple: to promote the region's poets and support local pubs, while introducing and promoting free poetry events to audiences that both would and would not ordinarily be interested. We may bend our own rules from time to time depending on the opportunities that should come our way, but these are our main aims - free art in an environment that nurtures it!]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1810]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Chemic Tavern]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[14 Mar 2014 7:30pm - 11:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10133.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10133.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9925]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Stupid Women]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Stupid Women is a live directed improvisation. It aims to combine idiocy with skill, anarchy with meaning and costumes with music. A number of guests, of high calibre and low pay, attempt the possible and quite probably fail.

Stupid Women is an endeavour made especially for Juncture as a tribute to the late and great Nigel Charnock whose piece Stupid Men irritated and annoyed most audiences that saw it.

We are hoping to be able to achieve something similar.

Stupid Women will have been created at Yorkshire Dance over four days by Wendy Houstoun with Jo Fong, TC Howard, Sophie Unwin, Vivien Wood and others.

Part of Yorkshire Dance's Juncture; a festival of contemporary movement, theatre and film work curated by Wendy Houstoun.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[321]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Yorkshire Dance]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[2258]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Yorkshire Dance]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[15 Mar 2014 7:30pm - 9:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9925.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9925.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10068]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[We Used To Wait ]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The person sat next to you offers you their hand. You take it and then notice that everyone else in the room has begun holding hands too. A man starts to speak. He says:
"Hello everybody, my name is..."
Moving through moments of playful interaction, participation and celebration, We Used To Wait explores what it means to be 'live' and present together in an increasingly digital world. We Used To Wait invites its audience to question why falling asleep on a stranger's shoulder, playing a spontaneous game and feeling the wind of someone run past you might be important.
A rectangle of chairs. Audience and performers sat side by side. No set. Just us together. And a gentle invitation to interact...
"Here I am. Here we are. Here we go."
 
Developed with support from Arts Council England, ARC Stockton, Theatre in the Mill, Bradford, and Live Theatre, Newcastle - upon - Tyne.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2119]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Holbeck Underground Ballroom (HUB)]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[16 Mar 2014 5:00pm - 6:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10068.png]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10068.png]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10587]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Leeds Writers Read]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Leeds Writers read their own material: thin slices of prose, poetry and drama. Contributors include Linda Caspar, Linda Fulton, Marg Greenwood, Steve Hobbs, Iby Knill, Linda Lewis, Vince Mihill, Emma Parkin and Peter Richardson.

Last 30 minutes open mic (max 5 mins) - sign up at the door.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[240]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Headingley Library]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[6703]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Headingley LitFest]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[17 Mar 2014 7:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10587.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10587.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[8915]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Oysterband]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Oysterband emerge from their hugely successful collaboration with June Tabor, the multi-award winning Ragged Kingdom, with a brand new album of original songs full of big, open melodies and uplifting, insightful lyrics and take to the road.  Their new momentum is driven  by core members John Jones, Alan Prosser , Ian Telfer and Dil Davies, with  the chemistry at the heart of the band as vital as ever, and augmented by the bass playing of Al Scott, their producer, the cello of Adrian Oxaal [formerly of the band James] and the emotional singing of Rowan Godel. Ever close to the tradition Oysterband re-discover their song-writing roots and, following a superb run of festivals in 2013, their passion for live performances. 
 
Consistently creative , Oysterband continue to re-define their particular brand of Folk-rock and find an even bigger audience. One of the great live bands returns with a classic mix of old and new songs.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1043]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1252]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[18 Mar 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/8915.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/8915.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9442]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[T42 Dance: Tour D'Horizon]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[T42 are an internationally acclaimed Swiss dance theatre company. Tour D'Horizon brings to life the fascinating story of one man who lived in isolation for decades on the coast of Brittany and the strange fate that befell him. Mesmerising, beautiful and humorous, don't miss this exciting company on their first UK tour.

Suitable for ages 14+
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[9441]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Stanley & Audrey Burton Theatre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[19 Mar 2014 ]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9442.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9442.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9905]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Nosferatu - A Rehearsed Reading]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Carriageworks Theatre is working closely with Proper Job Theatre Company in the ongoing development of their fresh take on the well-known tale of the original monster movie Nosferatu.

We are hosting a rehearsed reading of the script, written by Yorkshire based poet Ian McMillan. There is an original score performed live with singing.

"On the blood dark sea the ship is barely moving 
There's a sail as torn as a shattered shirt 
Something is aboard the ship..."

Nosferatu tells the dark and mysterious tale of the sailors in Bram Stokers novel Dracula, as they journey from Varna to Whitby with an unknown cargo.

This is a fantastic chance to be one of the first to see a new groundbreaking piece of theatre, feeding into the shaping and impression of the play, which will embark on a national tour in 2015. We need your feedback so please join us for an evening of blood, danger and art! 

Proper Job Theatre Company is based in the North of England creating and touring new work as well as large-scale theatre events. Proper Job are passionate about continuously developing projects that excite us, fire our curiosity and expand our imagination. ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[304]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Carriageworks Theatre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[20 Mar 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9905.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9905.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9246]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Wrong 'Un: A Suffragette's Story]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Presented by Red Ladder Theatre Company

A new one-woman musical written by Boff Whaley and directed by Justin Audibert.  February 1918, Parliament is poised to grant what the suffragettes have fought for - votes for all women. After years of direct action, imprisonment and force-feeding, it seems their time has come.    Wrong 'Un tells of the adventures of Annie Wilde, a Lancashire mill-girl galvanised by a rousing mixture of injustice, conviction, self-doubt and fear on her journey from schoolroom to prison cell and beyond.  Suitable for family audiences (age 11+)]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2142]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Otley Courthouse]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7150]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Otley Courthouse]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[21 Mar 2014 7:30pm - 9:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9246.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9246.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10597]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Echoes Of War]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Two poets choose freely to abandon Blighty and head for the trenches. Why? Patriotism? Heroism? A death wish, maybe? 

In Theatre of the Dales' script-in-hand production, Leeds playwrights Stuart Fortey and Peter Spafford explore the motives of Wilfred Owen and Edward Thomas. Neither man survived. What they wrote undoubtedly did.

On Scarborough Front by Stuart Fortey is a short two hander where Owen clashes with a retired colonel in a hotel being used as an officers' mess. As his own son is reported missing, the colonel is bitter and critical towards the young Owen who appears to have found a safe niche as Catering Secretary. But as the play develops, the men grow to a deeper understanding. The son survives, while Owen returns to the front, not for motives of patriotism, but to spur himself to write again. (The Clarence Gardens Hotel, now the Clifton, still stands on North Bay.)

The Edge of the Forest by Peter Spafford has two time scales. A brother and sister now own a house cluttered with war memorabilia - their father's legacy. She wants to sell up, he wants to cling to the past. In fact he has recently become agoraphobic after a mugging incident. The arrival of an estate agent with an eye for the sister pushes things to a climax. The boy is obsessed by Thomas. For long stretches he identifies with him in his mind, imagining his sister and the agent as Edward's wife Helen and their friend the charming and persuasive Robert Frost. Edward, like him, is torn between staying where he is and venturing forth into action.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[954]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[New Headingley Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[6703]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Headingley LitFest]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[22 Mar 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10597.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10597.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9249]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Derren Brown]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Direct from the West End, the acknowledged master of psychological illusion returns to the stage with his latest show, Derren Brown: Infamous, demonstrating once again why Derren is one of the world's most renowned live performers; a dark manipulator of magic and mind control.
 
For Infamous, a more 'personal' show, Derren is re-united with his close collaborator and friend, actor/writer Andy Nyman.
 
Derren says 'Now we've joined forces again, we're very eager to make this show feel different. There was something of a template we followed with all the shows, which worked very well. It's rather exciting and scary leaving that behind. This one should certainly have a different tone, and will mix things up a bit for those who have seen the others on TV or live'.
 
Infamous is Derren's sixth show since 2003. He has toured every year since then and has been watched by an estimated audience of over 2 million people. He has won two prestigious Olivier Awards, for Something Wicked This Way Comes (2006) and Svengali (2012), and confesses that touring is still his favourite thing to do.
 
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[394]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Grand Theatre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1224]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Grand Theatre]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[24 Mar 2014 - 29 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9249.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9249.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9444]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[National Dance Company Wales: Mixed Programme]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[National Dance Company Wales return with a triple bill of dazzling dance from world class choreographers and home-grown talent.

With original music from Grammy and Academy Award-winning composer Atticus Ross (The Girl with the Dragon Tattoo, The Social Network), and choreographed by Stephen Petronio, Water Stories is unmissable. This new piece conjures up the abundant and magical waterscapes of Wales and features stunning original visuals from artist Matthew Brandt.

The programme also includes Lee Johnston's They Seek To Find The Happiness They Seem, inspired by elements of classic love stories and famous dance partnerships, and Stephen Shropshire's Mythology set to Rzewski's Coming Together.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[659]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Stanley & Audrey Burton Theatre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[25 Mar 2014 - 26 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9444_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9444_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10624]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Fictions Of Every Kind: Home]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Welcome to the March Fictions event, where we invite you to reflect on the theme of 'home'. Whether 'home' means a back-to-back terraced house, a tent pitched in a bit of wasteland, or an abandoned rocket on the surface of the moon, Fictions invites you to riff off real or imaginary dwellings past or present. 

Our invited speakers at this event are: 

ZODWA NYONI Zimbabwean-born poet and playwright, who has held residencies at BBC Radio Leeds and at the Ilkley Literature Festival, Zodwa was recently named one of Leeds' 20 best writers under 40, and is certainly one of Fictions' favourite poets. Don't miss this opportunity to see her in action!

NASSER HUSSAIN Nasser is looking forward to the forthcoming publication of his first collection of spoken word poems, entitled 'boldface' - available this summer from Burning Eye Press. In the meantime he teaches literature and creative writing at Leeds Metropolitan University, and is currently at work on something completely different. 

Music at this event will come from DAVID BROAD.

OPEN MIC. There will be a writers' open mic, at which contributions of flash fiction, short fiction, true stories, and excerpts of larger work will all be welcome. You MUST keep your contributions under 6 minutes because if you go over, YOU WILL BE STOPPED. Even in the middle of a sentence if it comes to it. Please practise reading your work out to check that it comes in under 6 minutes - we're taking the very un-Fictions-like step of being firm about this. 

]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1603]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Wharf Chambers]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10623]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Fictions Of Every Kind]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[25 Mar 2014 7:30pm - 10:45pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10624.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10624.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9400]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Dream Yards ]]></event_title><description><![CDATA['If I were to wake you now, you may not know to tell me that you were dreaming.'

In late 2012 we collected accounts of Yorkshire dreams. By dreams we mean the ones that wake you up in the middle
of the night or disappear in an instant in the morning; those ones that really get to you and make you feel a bit strange for the rest of the day or for years to follow. 

Part talk show, part neuro-psychoanalyst's couch, our host Kong Lear is grappling with the riddles of dream generation and sleep science.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[304]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Carriageworks Theatre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[25 Mar 2014 7:45pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9400.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9400.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10607]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Extraordinary Survivors]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Escaping from an overturned cruise liner off the Italian coast, or battling through the Antarctic wastes, or locking the door against a violent partner: the subjects for this evening of stories, poems and real-life accounts are as diverse as the readers and performers: Linda Marshall, Jane Oakeshott and Peter Spafford
are three of them...
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[10606]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Cafe Lento]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[6703]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Headingley LitFest]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[27 Mar 2014 8:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10607.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10607.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[8341]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Yerma]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The anguishing story of Yerma, a woman who suffers heart breaking social torment of a childless marriage forcing her to commit a horrific and irrevocable act set the scene for this powerful production.  Lorca's savage yet poetical lyrical play set in rural patriarchal and religiously repressive Spain is transposed to an inner city British Islamic community.

Amina Khayyam, principal dancer and choreographer will look to share the emotions and experiences of many women in childless marriages, and the communities they are based in, through Kathak Dance. Live musicians Debasish Mukherjee (tabla), Lucy Rahman (vocals) James Barralet (cello) Tarun Jasani (sarod) will add to the narrative, enabling boundaries to be crossed and explored of a topic that is a very personal one, but touches the hearts of everyone.

In association with the Amina Khayyam Dance Company.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[460]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Northern School of Contemporary Dance]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1703]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[SAA-uk]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[29 Mar 2014 7:30pm - 9:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/8341.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/8341.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9332]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Standing In Line]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Presented by Blaize with Hommel Arts.

Through song, poetry and narration, Standing In Line tells the story of the Great War, but specifically about Albert Scrimshaw, Lester Simpson's great uncle, who died at Passendale. Originally commissioned by 'Peace Concerts Passendale', it was premiered in Passendale Church, Belgium in 2003. The performance is centred around Lester's songs though includes songs from the time. The narration includes poems of Wilfred Owen, Siegfried Sassoon and Rudyard Kipling and is accompanied by a series of projected images.  Written by Lester Simpson and Piet Chielans]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2142]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Otley Courthouse]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[6542]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Otley Word Feast]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[29 Mar 2014 7:30pm - 9:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9332.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9332.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9728]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Passion Of Christ]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The Cantata The Passion of Christ was composed by Lake-District born composer Sir Arthur Somervell's exactly a century ago in 1914. The Passion follows very much in the traditions of Stainer [The Crucifixion of 1887] and Maunder [Olivet to Calvary of 1904]. 

The passion narrative unfolds mainly in recitative drawn from Gospel texts, while solo arias and "choral meditations", with words probably by Somervell himself, reflect on the action. As in the Stainer and Maunder pieces, there are hymns for all to sing. Somervell's music is throughout reflective and beautiful and at times exquisite.

"It is, truly, a forgotten masterpiece," said conductor Dr Simon Lindley, "I remember obtaining a copy some years ago from a colleague who was organist of Holy Trinity Church in Boar Lane, and have been wanting for decades to give the piece an airing. The centenary year of its first performance provides us with an excellent opportunity!"]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4897]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Minster]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[6327]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[St Peter's Singers]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[30 Mar 2014 6:30pm - 8:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9728.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9728.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9403]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Wizard of Oz ]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Click your heels, clap your hands and go Over the Rainbow with this fantastic production of The Wizard of Oz.

Watch Dorothy and her cute dog Toto enter the wonderful Land of Oz. During their travels down the yellow brick road they meet some lovely friends and travel to see the great and powerful Wizard of Oz. This won't be easy as the Wicked Witch of the West is determined to stop them by any means necessary!

This is a pantomime style production of The Wizard of Oz.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[304]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Carriageworks Theatre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[7 Apr 2014 - 9 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9403.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9403.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10522]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Dr Sketchy's Life Drawing]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Join our alternative life drawing class run by Dr Sketchy's Leeds and experience this popular themed burlesque, life drawing evening for yourself. Held every second Thursday of the month...

Presenting to you, Dr Sketchys Leeds for all you art-thrill seekers and cabaret fans!....

Welcome to an art school with a difference: An anti art school. Here there's no teaching, just lots of lifedrawing. Prepare for monthly themes or burlesque, cabaret and the very strange indeed. Let your hosts guide you through the merriment of prize challenges and obscure anti art practices. 

Join us on the second Thursday of every month from 6.30/7 - 9pm and experience the magic and the surreal as you sharpen your skills with the old fashioned pencil.

Please bring your own tools, we'll provide prizes and all the fun!!

For more information about Dr Sketchy's Leeds visit their website http://www.drsketchy.com/branch/Leeds Or find them on facebook and have a look at the fun that they have in store for you!

Contact the gallery for further details: 
email: gallery@leeds.ac.uk or Tel:0113 3432 778]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4854]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Stanley & Audrey Burton Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1403]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Stanley & Audrey Burton Gallery]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[10 Apr 2014 - 13 Jun 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10522.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10522.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9512]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Vaisakhi Celebrations]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The Sikh festival Vaisakhi celebrates the Sikh New Year and the founding of the Khalsa. The festival is marked with nagar kirtan street processions which form an important part of Sikh culture and religious celebrations. Proceedings include singing, scriptures and delicious food.
 ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[295]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Millennium Square]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[12 Apr 2014 ]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9512.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9512.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10541]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Taking Charlie]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[TAKING CHARLIE is a dark comedic fantasy, based on a true story, about the abduction of Charlie Chaplin's body by two hapless kidnappers in 1978. A tale full of comedy, bad ideas and dead comics that uses puppetry, physical theatre and shadow play to create its inventive and farcical world.

Written by Neil Warhurst]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2119]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Holbeck Underground Ballroom (HUB)]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Apr 2014 5:00pm - 6:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10541.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10541.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9445]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Manasamitra - Rudra]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Contemporary Kathak choreographer Sonia Sabri resurrects Indian mythology in an exciting programme of dance performed by artists combining classical Indian and contemporary dance backgrounds. With live music and an original score by Shri Sriram (of Badmarsh and Shri fame) Rudra echoes the universal cycle of peace, disturbance, love and lament.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[659]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Stanley & Audrey Burton Theatre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Apr 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9445.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9445.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9201]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Robin Ince Is (In) And Out Of His Mind]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Sony Gold Award winning comedian and science enthusiast Robin Ince comes to City Varieties next year with another in his line of unhinged stand-up comic lectures. Robin delves into his mind as he looks at the last 100 years of psychiatry, psychology and skewiff brain dabblings.

Robin is well known for presenting the science series The Infinite Monkey Cage with physicist Brian Cox on BBC Radio 4. He supports the Rationalist Association by organising events at the Bloomsbury Theatre and at the Hammersmith Apollo featuring scientists, musicians and comedians. These include Nine Lessons and Carols for Godless People and a Night of 400 Billion Stars.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1043]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1252]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[29 Apr 2014 7:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9201.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9201.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9447]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[James Wilton Dance - Last Man Standing]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Fusing martial arts, breakdancing and capoeira,
Last Man Standing is dance driven by unparalleled energy and athleticism. Winner of the Sadler's Wells Global Dance Contest, choreographer James Wilton returns with this exhilarating new piece that will leave you breathless.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[659]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Stanley & Audrey Burton Theatre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[14 May 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9447.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9447.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10024]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Ghost Peloton]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[A Ghost Peloton of cyclists, drawing on the spirit of the Tour de France but forsaking dreams of heroism, commits to mass communal movement juxtaposed with complex and extraordinarily athletic choreography inspired by the wheel in motion and performed on film by Phoenix's dancers.

Each ghost rider, bike and dancer wears a bespoke LED light suit that changes colour, flash-rate and luminosity as the Peloton changes course. The combined results produce mesmerising light patterns as the cyclists interact with their passing surroundings, culminating in a public performance and film projection as night falls in central Leeds.

Both as large-scale public art and through the powerful film and photography it will inspire, the work allows us to see the body in perfect motion and to look again at familiar environments. The landscape of Yorkshire from remote moor to urban heartland becomes an open canvas carrying a new visual language seen in live performance and a documentary film by renowned cycling film director Mark Huskisson.

Ghost Peloton builds on the worldwide success of NVA's Speed of Light which since 2012 has choreographed massed endurance runners in sites as diverse as Arthur's Seat, Yokohama docks and the Ruhr valley. Ghost Peloton is a collaboration between NVA and Leeds based Phoenix Dance Theatre in association with Sustrans.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[7775]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Tetley ]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[16 May 2014 - 17 May 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10024.png]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10024.png]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9671]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Leeds Gilbert And Sullivan Society Gala Charity Performance: Trial by Jury]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[by W S Gilbert and Arthur Sullivan

It is exactly 150 years since Leeds became an assize town and the high court moved in. The TownHall re-opens its courtroom for a Charity Gala Performance of Trial By Jury.

Seating is on benches in the public gallery with limited access and you are invited to bring your own cushion.

Sponsored by The Rotary Club of Headingley, all proceeds to Leeds Foodbanks.

Gala Reception: 6.30pm
Performance: 7pm]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[313]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Town Hall]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[801]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds International Concert Season]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[16 May 2014 6:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9671.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9671.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9448]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Ballet Central - 2014 Tour]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Ballet Central return with an exciting programme of ballet, contemporary and jazz dance featuring a mixture of newly commissioned works and much-loved revivals, which showcase the talent of the company's young and emerging dancers.

New works this year will be from acclaimed choreographers including Northern Ballet's Ballet Master Daniel de Andrade as well as Christopher Marney and Sara Matthews.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[659]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Stanley & Audrey Burton Theatre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[17 May 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9448.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9448.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10240]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Jaleo Flamenco: A Compas]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[In a scintillating fusion of heartwrenching vocals, explosive footwork and virtuoso guitar playing, Jaleo return to Britain after three years with their latest new stage show 'A Compas' , brimming over with the intoxicating rhythms, palpable energy and joie de vivre which has become synonymous with the company.

'A Compas' (in rhythm) charts an evocative musical journey through the diverse flamenco regions of Andalusia in which some of Spain´s finest award-winning artists combine their talents in a mesmerising tour de force to produce a unique spectacle of universal appeal which encapsulates the very essence of flamenco.
PRESS REVIEWS
 
'Flamenco at its very best - a succession of short, sharp human dramas which quicken the pulse and excite the senses' 
Dance Today
 
'Jaleo - sexy, sissling and Spanish.... passion and emotion consistently and movingly displayed.....Jaleo left behind wonderful warm memories of superb dancing and a big hot slice of southern Spain' 
Watford Observer
 
'Spellbinding fusion of acoustic guitar, rhythm, songs, handclapping and ignitable dance' 
The Guardian
 
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1043]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1252]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[20 May 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10240.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10240.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9449]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Tell Tale Hearts - Yummm!]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Acclaimed children's theatre company Tell Tale Hearts present a fun, energetic and vibrant dance theatre show that celebrates all that is messy at meal times.

Yummm! is a celebration of food seen through children's eyes using dance, live music, quirky design and comedy to create an unforgettable theatre experience. A highly imaginative production where tables can dance, plates spin and the audience have a chance to contribute to the dinner time rituals.

The 11.30am performance is suitable for under 4s and the 2.00pm performance is suitable for ages 4+.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[659]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Stanley & Audrey Burton Theatre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[23 May 2014 ]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9449.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9449.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9256]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[I'm Sorry I Haven't A Clue]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Following sell-out tours in 2007 2008, 2009 and 2010, BBC Radio's multi award-winning antidote to panel games starts an all-new touring stage show for 2014.  Join Barry Cryer, Graeme Garden, Tim Brooke-Taylor, Jeremy Hardy and host Jack Dee for an unmissable evening of inspired nonsense.  Colin Sell provides piano accompaniment.
 
"Whether the teams are singing the words of one song to the tune of another, making up serial rhymes or entering the mythic maze of Mornington Crescent, they have now become the National Theatre of fun"  
Gillian Reynolds, Daily Telegraph
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[394]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Grand Theatre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1224]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Grand Theatre]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[2 Jun 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9256.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9256.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10467]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Landscapes]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The sun rises over a buzzing desert,
a chick hatches.
The eagle leaves the nest in search of food.
Below, the Meerkats are alert.
The Journey begins...

Step inside Mimika Theatre's white canvas dome and experience this magical and intimate show. Performed to only 25 people at a time the audience are taken on a journey to four lovingly realised landscapes from desert to rainforest, from beneath the sea to Antarctica.

Using no words, Mimika combine beautifully crafted puppets with an original musical score, stunning visual effects and an ingenious set to create a theatre which wonderfully captures the atmosphere, rhythms and sounds of the natural world. This is a journey that no child should miss and and a theatrical experience that all adults will find unforgettable.

Mimika Theatre have performed this hugely successful show to children in Europe, U.S.A, Canada, South East Asia and China.

For tickets: 
For directions: www.leftbankleeds.org.uk
For more info: www.mimikatheatre.com]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[759]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Left Bank]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[760]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Left Bank Leeds]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[16 Jun 2014 - 19 Jun 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10467.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10467.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9450]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Northern Ballet - Mixed Programme]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Northern Ballet return with a new Mixed Programme featuring works by Dutch dance master Hans van Manen, one of the US's foremost dance makers Lar Lubovitch and Northern Ballet Premier Dancer and British choreographer Kenneth Tindall.
Kenneth Tindall's choreographic debut Project#1 and follow up Luminous Juncture have attracted critical acclaim and made him one to watch in the dance world. The premiere of his hotly anticipated third work is not to be missed.

Northern Ballet dancers stunned audiences when they performed Hans van Manen's Concertante last year. This sensational piece, inspired by and set to Frank Martin's Petite Symphonie Concertante, returns by popular demand.
Described by the New York Times as "one of the ten best choreographers in the world", the final piece will be by Tony Award nominated Lar Lubovitch who has created more than 100 dance works.

Do not miss this unique opportunity to see Northern Ballet's talented dancers up close.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[659]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Stanley & Audrey Burton Theatre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[18 Jun 2014 - 21 Jun 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9450.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9450.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10382]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Brass]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Directed by Sara Kestelman 
Book, Music and Lyrics by Benjamin Till
To commemorate the centenary of the outbreak of the Great War NYMT has commissioned a new work from Benjamin Till. The story follows a group of Leeds residents from the start of the war until the battle of the Somme in 1916. The men, members of an amateur brass band, join up to the Leeds Pals regiment and their womenfolk decide to learn the instruments that the men have left behind to keep the spirit of the brass band alive and to play for them when they triumphantly return to the city after the war. We watch the women trying to learn the brass instruments whilst the men simply try to stay alive. It is an epic musical about love and survival. 
 
Wed 20 to Sat 23 August at 19:30 
Fri & Sat matinees at 14:30

National Youth Music Theatre 
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1043]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1252]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[20 Aug 2014 - 23 Aug 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10382.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10382.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9991]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Dick Whittington The Rock 'n' Roll Panto]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[This year Dick Whittington is set to continue the successful run of Rock 'n' Roll Pantos at City Varieties Music Hall.
 
The Rock 'n' Roll Pantos are hugely popular and are fast becoming a Leeds tradition. The incredible atmosphere has audiences dancing in the aisles.
 
The City Varieties' Rock 'n' Roll Panto has everything you would expect from a traditional family pantomime - slapstick comedy, audience interaction and outlandish costumes -  with the bonus of  a rocking soundtrack and the now-legendary 'boulder fight'.
 
The soundtrack is played live on stage by the extraordinarily talented cast - you won't see anything like this anywhere in Yorkshire. It's a real treat.
  ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1043]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1252]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[29 Nov 2014 - 11 Jan 2015]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9991.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9991.jpg]]></image_original></item></objects></response>