<?xml version="1.0"?><response><status><![CDATA[200]]></status><status_message><![CDATA[OK]]></status_message><message><![CDATA[OK]]></message><objects><item><event_id><![CDATA[9741]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Vintage Fair]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[St Gemma's Hospice Vintage Fairs are extremely popular with over 1,000 people attending each one. As well as the private stall holders, we also have a room jam packed with vintage finds that the 22 St Gemma's charity shops have collected and so all the profit from these items goes to the Hospice. 

There is a wide range of goods on sale, from retro clothes, small pieces of sought-after furniture, classic records to collectable books, plus plenty of timeless pieces of jewellery and artwork, all dating from 1920s - 1980s. In addition to shopping, you can sit back and relax and treat yourself to a hot beverage and cake in our Vintage tea room. BBC Leeds Auctioneer Gary Don will also be attending to provide you with expert valuations on your antiques.

This award-winning fair is for a fantastic cause and is a brilliant day out so get yourself along!]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4709]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[St. Gemma's Hospice]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4489]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[St Gemma's Hospice]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[8 Mar 2014 - 9 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9741.JPG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9741.JPG]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10357]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Alternative Wedding Event]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Are you getting married but a white meringue and hotel wedding the last thing you want then come to our wedding fair

Whether you want a purple victorian coat, a red medieval dress or a tea party with a cake covered in cogs then our sellers should be able to accommodate

Then come along to our shop wedding event and chat with our sellers about all your needs.

We'll also have vintage hair and make up demos and wedding related craft sessions

If you are a wedding seller and want to be part of our team then get in touch asap]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4404]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Fabrication Crafts Limited]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1430]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Fabrication Crafts Ltd]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[23 Mar 2014 11:00am - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10357.JPG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10357.JPG]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9331]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Otley Word Feast 2014 Celebration Weekend]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[This enjoyable feast of words showcases local talent and established writers with an exciting programme for all the community with many free events, at the Courthouse and other town venues. Highlights include creative writing workshops, open mic and slam competitions, author events, speakers, children and family activities. 

For the latest programme news, see www.otleywordfeast.org.uk and check www.otleycourthouse.org.uk for ticket and booking information.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2142]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Otley Courthouse]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7150]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Otley Courthouse]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[28 Mar 2014 - 30 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9331.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9331.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9334]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Otley Green Fair]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Campaigns, charities, crafts, therapies, environmental groups, workshops, entertainment, fantastic food.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2142]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Otley Courthouse]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7150]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Otley Courthouse]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[5 Apr 2014 10:00am - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9334.JPG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9334.JPG]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10046]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Same But Different Art Fair]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[A new art fair inspires the North.

The Same but Different Arts Fair will be exhibiting over eighty artists from across the country, bringing together art and creativity in a relaxed, artistic festival environment. An unmissable opportunity to view works by established and emerging contemporary artists in Britain today.

The fair includes:
A full programme of adult creative workshops that will be delivered by a number of talented artists and writers. Write your own poem using our artworks as inspiration, put your words to music in our song-writing class, or have a go at printing in these hour-long taster workshops.

FREE Family Easter egg hunt. Drop off the children with our specialist team of trained staff and they will explore the gardens whilst hunting for chocolate!  This event is just not for kids, adults are welcome to join in too.

Committing the Perfect Murder - Crime writers, including Danuta Reah/Carla Banks, Nick Quantrill and Nick Triplow, conspire to thrill and inspire you on the Saturday night, brought to you by SBD's Writer in Residence, published author Alison Taft. 

An interactive installation by artfever.org.uk The installation will be a giant woven web, the public are invited to fully immerse themselves in the colours, movement and depth of the yarn providing a sensory journey up towards the marquee.

Live music - full programme to be announced but includes Mark Ruston and The High Club who will be playing throughout the weekend and the Liverpool band Roja will be entertaining us on the Saturday evening with songs from their debut album 

A pop up retail shop will be in the marquee providing an array of unique goodies by designer makers from across the country as well as signed books by our authors.

A cosy cafe/bar, offering delicious locally sourced and home baked goods, as well as the best espresso by Allpress Espesso. 

The Biscuit Factory, the UK's largest art, craft & design gallery set in the heart of Newcastle's cultural quarter is supporting the first ever SBD Art Fair.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[155]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Temple Newsam House and Estate]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[12 Apr 2014 - 13 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10046_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10046_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9512]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Vaisakhi Celebrations]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The Sikh festival Vaisakhi celebrates the Sikh New Year and the founding of the Khalsa. The festival is marked with nagar kirtan street processions which form an important part of Sikh culture and religious celebrations. Proceedings include singing, scriptures and delicious food.
 ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[295]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Millennium Square]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[12 Apr 2014 ]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9512.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9512.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9692]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Leeds Flower, Vegetable And Craft Show 2014]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Celebrating its 150th anniversary the show has a variety of classes and trade stands with experts in all the classes to answer any questions.  Talks will also be given in the lecture theatre on both days.

Musical entertainment will be provided, with a surprise or two in store.

Traders both inside and out will include:  nurseries, specialist growers, garden accessories and tools, photography, paintings and prints, greetings cards and gifts and the ice cream man to cool you down.  Applications for trade stands are still welcome.

Refreshments are available on both days, ranging from coffees to cooked breakfasts, lunches and afternoon teas, all high quality at reasonable prices.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3193]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Grammar School at Leeds ]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[9691]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Horticultural Society]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[2 Aug 2014 - 3 Aug 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9692.JPG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9692.JPG]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9695]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Shadwell Flower Show 2014]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Hundreds of exhibits and displays.  Trade stalls selling plants, homemade produce, cards, etc.  Tombola and musical entertainment throughout.

Bar and tea tent.  Horticultural, craft and hobby entries and exhibits.  Prize giving and auction at 4.30pm.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[9693]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Shadwell Primary School]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[9694]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Shadwell Horticultural Society]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[16 Aug 2014 - 17 Aug 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9695.JPG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9695.JPG]]></image_original></item></objects></response>