<?xml version="1.0"?><response><status><![CDATA[200]]></status><status_message><![CDATA[OK]]></status_message><message><![CDATA[OK]]></message><objects><item><event_id><![CDATA[9741]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Vintage Fair]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[St Gemma's Hospice Vintage Fairs are extremely popular with over 1,000 people attending each one. As well as the private stall holders, we also have a room jam packed with vintage finds that the 22 St Gemma's charity shops have collected and so all the profit from these items goes to the Hospice. 

There is a wide range of goods on sale, from retro clothes, small pieces of sought-after furniture, classic records to collectable books, plus plenty of timeless pieces of jewellery and artwork, all dating from 1920s - 1980s. In addition to shopping, you can sit back and relax and treat yourself to a hot beverage and cake in our Vintage tea room. BBC Leeds Auctioneer Gary Don will also be attending to provide you with expert valuations on your antiques.

This award-winning fair is for a fantastic cause and is a brilliant day out so get yourself along!]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4709]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[St. Gemma's Hospice]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4489]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[St Gemma's Hospice]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[8 Mar 2014 - 9 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9741.JPG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9741.JPG]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9334]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Otley Green Fair]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Campaigns, charities, crafts, therapies, environmental groups, workshops, entertainment, fantastic food.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2142]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Otley Courthouse]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7150]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Otley Courthouse]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[5 Apr 2014 10:00am - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9334.JPG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9334.JPG]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9656]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Picture Lending Scheme: Selection Day]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Leeds Art Gallery's picture lending library was established in 1961 as a way for people to enjoy original art at home - come to the Gallery and choose high quality pictures from a large collection to borrow and take home. 

Over six hundred art works are available to borrow from oils, drawings, photographs and a variety of prints; whether you like landscapes or abstracts, Henri Matisse or Henry Moore, there is something to suit every taste.

How much does it cost?
There is no membership or joining fee, you pay for what you borrow. It costs just &pound;4 per month for one artwork and then &pound;2 per month for any additional works. All artworks are for a minimum period of three months (therefore a min payment of &pound;12 is applicable).]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[150]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Art Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7293]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Museums & Galleries]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[26 Apr 2014 11:00am - 3:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9656.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9656.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9688]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Leeds Horticultural Society's Plant Sale And Coffee Morning]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[A variety of plants, garden accessories and cakes for sale.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3729]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[St Chad's Parish Centre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[17 May 2014 9:30am - 11:30am]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9688.JPG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9688.JPG]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10415]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Yorkshire Bicycle Show]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The second Yorkshire Bicycle Show will take place in Leeds this summer.  Held within the majestic rooms of Leeds Town Hall 4-6 July 2014, it will coincide with the Tour de France Grand Depart in the city centre and be right at the heart of this great Yorkshire cycling weekend.

The Show will present cycling at its best. With a wide array of bicycles and accessories, from handmade frames, to top-end road and mountain bikes, visitors of all ages will find something to excite them. There'll be demonstrations of craftsmanship, dare-devil displays of cycling skill, as well as a packed programme of talks from some of Britain's most intrepid cyclists. Proud to be an independent project, the Show is organised by local businesses to celebrate and promote the region. 
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[313]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Town Hall]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10414]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Yorkshire Bicycle Show]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[4 Jul 2014 - 6 Jul 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10415_0.png]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10415_0.png]]></image_original></item></objects></response>