<?xml version="1.0"?><response><status><![CDATA[200]]></status><status_message><![CDATA[OK]]></status_message><message><![CDATA[OK]]></message><objects><item><event_id><![CDATA[8483]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA['Metamorphosis I' - Daniel Cooper]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Fascinated by the beautiful textures and markings within slate, Daniel Cooper's solo showcase explores this wonderful material with a series of vessels.  His inspiration comes from a visit to Elterwater Slate Quarry in the Lake District where he adopted the working methods, knowledge and local dialect of the quarrymen to produce this collection of works. Daniel hosts a Meet the Maker afternoon on Saturday 18th January, please contact the gallery for further information.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3905]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Craft Centre and Design Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4655]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[The Craft Centre and Design Gallery]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[18 Jan 2014 - 30 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/8483.JPG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/8483.JPG]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[8484]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Shoots And Leaves]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Print exhibition.

Hedgerows are explored by two printmakers in this wonderful exploration of growth.  Stef Mitchell's seasonal monoprints work directly with natural materials acting as recordings of walks which viewers can easily relate to.  Lynn Bailey combines several printmaking techniques in her collection including etching, collagraph, drypoint, mono print and photo etching which create an exciting and organic series of works.  Stef Mitchell's work pictured.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3905]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Craft Centre and Design Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4655]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[The Craft Centre and Design Gallery]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[1 Mar 2014 - 28 Jun 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/8484.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/8484.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10262]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Bicyclism: Photo Drop In Afternoon]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Do you have photos in your family albums of you, your friends or family on bicycles?

If so - old or new, polaroid or digital - artists Casey Orr and Boff Whalley would love to see them. First bikes, old bikes, club pictures, Sunday afternoon jaunts - just bring your photographs, albums or memory sticks along to one of our drop-in photo days in Armley or Kirkstall and they'll be scanned in right there and then!

Photos collected will be posted to our online gallery at www.bicyclism.co.uk and help build up a portrait of Leeds on Two Wheels. A selection will also be displayed at the exhibition Bicyclism which opens on 24th June at Leeds City Museum.

Bicyclism is part of the Yorkshire Festival 2014.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[151]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Armley Mills Leeds Industrial Museum]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[9 Mar 2014 1:00pm - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10262.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10262.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10025]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Woolly Bike Trail Workshop]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Cassandra Kilbride is a prolific yarn-stormer. Her crocheted street art makes cheeky visual statements that offer a new reading of the towns and cities we travel through and the monuments and street furniture we pass by. For the Grand Depart, Cassandra is creating ten woolly bikes for a year-long trail connecting ten towns with the many knitters, crocheters and yarn-stormers that have taken part.

Drawing inspiration from iconic Yorkshire themes including the landscape of the Dales, Yorkshire's textile mills, literary heroines and heroes, and the iconic flat cap, each bike gets a woolly makeover using local yarn. Most of the yarn is the produce of Yorkshire sheep, but one special batch comes from a collection of reclaimed saris. The transformed knitted vehicles will go on display in Sheffield this July, before they take up individual positions along the trail route.  

Workshops take place between January and June at festivals and venues across the region and are open to anyone with a basic ability of crocheting.  ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[395]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[West Yorkshire Playhouse]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[12 Mar 2014 - 19 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10025.png]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10025.png]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9529]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Down To Earth]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[An exhibition showcasing work which has been inspired by the Earth either through use of texture, colour, imagery and materials used in the creation of the collections.  A variety of environments have inspired the participating makers including coastlines, woodland, moorland and mountain ranges.  Featuring work by Mandy Parslow, Ben Davies, David Wright, Valerie Wartelle, Catherine Woodall (pictured) and Elizabeth Terzza to name just a few.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3905]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Craft Centre and Design Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[22 Mar 2014 - 28 Jun 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9529.JPG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9529.JPG]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10097]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Spokes: The Launch]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Our anthology of poems about bicycles and cycling will be launched at a gathering of many of the featured poets and their friends.  Entry by invitation only, but do get in touch with us if you would like to come! ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[10069]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Korks Wine Bar]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[6542]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Otley Word Feast]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[30 Mar 2014 2:00pm - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10097.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10097.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10521]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Everyone's A Winner! Medal Making With Claire Evans]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Family Friendly Medal Making with Claire Evans

The Yorkshire Festival is under way and with 90 days until the Grand Depart part sets out from Leeds what better way to get involved than to celebrate something you are good at and then award yourself with a medal for your skills!

Looking at the medals in our Alfred Drury exhibition Claire will help you make your own unique medals and badges which you can take home at the end of the session and wear with pride. Or why not make one for a friend or family member and honor them with an award for something wonderful!

Activities for younger members of the family can be provided too! Just ask!]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4854]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Stanley & Audrey Burton Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1403]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Stanley & Audrey Burton Gallery]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[5 Apr 2014 2:00pm - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10521_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10521_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10105]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Style, Glam And Cycling Sam]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Take part at the M&S Company Archive. We'll have jive dance classes with Swing Dance Leeds, talks and a special exhibition featuring our very own Cycling Sam. 

Come in your finest 50s outfit and enter our Best Dressed Competition, and there'll be tea and cake too! From Cycling Sam in the 1950s to the M&S 24 Hour Bike Challenge, cycling plays an important role at M&S. Sam Worton achieved an amazing feat in 1955, but you'll have to come along to find out what it was! We'll also have talks about the remarkable innovations in stores and fashion that M&S pioneered in the 50s. You can also watch our fantastic 1950s cinema adverts throughout the day... complete with popcorn. 

Activities are all free and will run from 11am to 3pm. There's no need to book, although places will be limited for the dance classes due to space restrictions.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2711]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Marks & Spencer Company Archive]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[2539]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Marks & Spencer Archive]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[26 Apr 2014 ]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10105.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10105.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[6215]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[La Boheme]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[A revival of the 1993 production.

Phyllida Lloyd's famed production of La Boheme has been praised for its perennial freshness, immediacy and close attention to the text. It gives full expression to the joy, wit and frivolity of student life in Paris in the early 1960s, when it is set, but also faces squarely the devastation that death brings when it arrives in the midst of the lives of a group of young friends. Anthony Ward's detailed and atmospheric designs vividly convey the hustle and bustle of the clubs and cafes of Paris.

Boheme remains one of the most popular of operas, and rightly so. Puccini weaves a web of glorious melody throughout, and his music speaks directly to the heart of anyone who has ever been young, and loved and lost.

'Lloyd's Boheme remains unmatched ... its radicalism remains powerful and immediate, and you would still be hard-pressed to find a production of Puccini's masterpiece that offers quite so challenging and cogent an interpretation as this.' The Guardian, January 2010

Lasts approximately 2 hours 15 mins
Sung in Italian with English titles]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[394]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Grand Theatre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1027]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Opera North]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[29 Apr 2014 - 10 May 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/6215_1.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/6215_1.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10027]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Thomas Houseago]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Leeds-born artist Thomas Houseago is today one of the most internationally influential sculptors of his generation.

The Yorkshire Sculpture Triangle, a partnership between four locally rooted world-class sculpture organisations (Henry Moore Institute, Leeds Art Gallery, The Hepworth Wakefield and the Yorkshire Sculpture Park) brings two of Thomas Haseago's sculptures to Yorkshire - a monumental new commission made specifically for Leeds city centre and one located at Yorkshire Sculpture Park.

The Los Angeles-based sculptor grew up in Leeds and is considered to be one of the most distinctive voices in contemporary art today. While his work has been shown globally, this is the first major commission in Yorkshire, a region that boasts a unique artistic legacy as the birthplace of Barbara Hepworth and Henry Moore. Drawing on references ranging from Greek mythology, Darth Vader, Moore and Hepworth and the Incredible Hulk, Houseago's giant figures are concerned with volume, gravity and scale. 

Outside Leeds Art Gallery stands a new sculpture by Houseago, made specifically for the occasion of the Yorkshire Festival 2014 and inspired by the city of Leeds. Caught in arrested motion, this gargantuan striding figure moves unrelentingly forward. Sited right on the Headrow, the sculpture alludes to the frenetic bustle of the surrounding urban landscape. With its rough finish, Houseago's figure contains the feeling of energy which the artist senses in the city. Within the grounds of Yorkshire Sculpture Park is another of Houseago's sculptures, an owl's head cast in bronze on a redwood plinth, reflecting the artist's interest in natural forms and forces and echoing the symbol of Leeds.   

This ambitious project to bring Thomas Houseago back from the US to his birthplace in Yorkshire has been developed by the Yorkshire Sculpture Triangle and realised with the support of the 2014 Grand Depart Cultural Festival and Leeds and Wakefield City Councils.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[150]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Art Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7293]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Museums & Galleries]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[30 Apr 2014 - 6 Jul 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10027.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10027.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9530]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA['Metamorphosis II' - Mark Cooke]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Mark Cooke explores the striking and timeless beauty of Welsh slate in this series of wall hung works and freestanding uprights.  His sensitivity to the material he uses maximises the inherent qualities found in slate creating a contemporary collection of works.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3905]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Craft Centre and Design Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4655]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[The Craft Centre and Design Gallery]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[1 May 2014 - 31 Jul 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9530.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9530.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10028]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Eyes On Le Tour De France]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Graham Watson and Bernard Thompson's photography of Le Tour promises an unrivalled view on and off the race track, White Cloth Gallery presents two exhibitions in tribute to these great talents, complimented by a summer programme of events, talks and screenings.

Be Part Of It: A talk, Q&A, film screening and display of additional archive materials will take place during the summer to celebrate Bernard Thompson's contribution to sports photography.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1544]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[White Cloth Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4002]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[White Cloth Gallery]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[15 May 2014 - 31 Aug 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10028.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10028.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10024]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Ghost Peloton]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[A Ghost Peloton of cyclists, drawing on the spirit of the Tour de France but forsaking dreams of heroism, commits to mass communal movement juxtaposed with complex and extraordinarily athletic choreography inspired by the wheel in motion and performed on film by Phoenix's dancers.

Each ghost rider, bike and dancer wears a bespoke LED light suit that changes colour, flash-rate and luminosity as the Peloton changes course. The combined results produce mesmerising light patterns as the cyclists interact with their passing surroundings, culminating in a public performance and film projection as night falls in central Leeds.

Both as large-scale public art and through the powerful film and photography it will inspire, the work allows us to see the body in perfect motion and to look again at familiar environments. The landscape of Yorkshire from remote moor to urban heartland becomes an open canvas carrying a new visual language seen in live performance and a documentary film by renowned cycling film director Mark Huskisson.

Ghost Peloton builds on the worldwide success of NVA's Speed of Light which since 2012 has choreographed massed endurance runners in sites as diverse as Arthur's Seat, Yokohama docks and the Ruhr valley. Ghost Peloton is a collaboration between NVA and Leeds based Phoenix Dance Theatre in association with Sustrans.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[7775]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Tetley ]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[16 May 2014 - 17 May 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10024.png]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10024.png]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10109]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Tour De Cinema]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The Tour de Cinema, working with National Trust, Cine Yorkshire and many other partners, will unveil thirty super-high-definition screens in unusual locations across Yorkshire for an unrivalled programme of fiction and non-fiction films about cycling.

The programme includes a brand new commission teaming up award-winning director Daisy Asquith with composer Bill Nelson and drawing on rare BFI film and music archives to chart the journey of the bicycle from new technology to familiar household transport.

It also highlights forgotten treasures like Alan Bennett's rarely seen BBC film from the 1970s - A Day Out, about a Halifax cycling club, and is a chance to see The Big Melt, paying homage to a century of steel-making with a blazing soundtrack compiled by Sheffield's Jarvis Cocker.

Alongside these gems, The Yorkshire Film Archive introduces a newly compiled film drawn from cine club and home movie collections to show cycling in all its forms, from childhood to adulthood.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[295]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Millennium Square]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10108]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Festival Yorkshire]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[21 May 2014 ]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10109.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10109.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10114]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Hoarder]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Inspired by the astonishing true story of chronic hoarder Richard Wallace, whose hoarding is so out of control that his own life is in danger. Mountains of papers and packaging fill his home from floor to ceiling and trap Richard in a world of his own, away from his community and any human connection. Sticks Theatre have devised this touching piece that tells the story of how, with a little understanding, friendship can make a world of difference. Post show discussion with artistic director and West Yorkshire Fire Service.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[304]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Carriageworks Theatre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[6049]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Carriageworks Theatre]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[22 May 2014 7:45pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10114.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10114.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10461]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[North Leeds Charity Beer Festival 2014]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Fans of beer and live music can swell the coffers of the Lord Mayors Appeal by attending the North Leeds Charity Beer Festival to be held on Friday 30th and Saturday 31st May 2014 at St Aidan's Community Hall on Roundhay Road. The Rotary Club of Roundhay will also be raising money for additional local, national and international charities.

This year the North Leeds Charity Beer Festival organised by The Rotary Club of Roundhay in association with The Lord Mayor of Leeds will have a Tour de France theme. Seventeen exclusive Le Tour de Yorkshire Grand Depart beers will be brewed especially for the 2014 festival. A further eleven beers brewed in Leeds will be served "in the wood". We will also have a selection of ciders and English Country Wines on offer.

CAMRA, The Campaign for Real Ale are offering their assistance and expert knowledge and their many volunteers will be making sure the beers are served correctly. A spokesman said, "If this is the first time anyone has visited a Beer Festival we want to ensure their experience is one they will enjoy and savour and will hook them to how beer should really taste

No event is complete without live music and there will be a number of bands performing throughout the North Leeds Charity Beer Festival. St Aidan's Community Hall is set over two floors so there will also be a quieter area where those who wish to can enjoy their beer in peace. Locally produced food will also be available and served at all times. 
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[5315]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[St Aidan's Community Hall]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5316]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[The Rotary Club of Roundhay, Leeds]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[30 May 2014 - 31 May 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10461_1.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10461_1.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10107]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Claude Cahun]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Claude Cahun (1894-1954) is best known for her riveting photographic self-portraits, that seem at least half a century ahead of their time where she acted out diverse identities both male and female in scenes that range from starkly minimal to the elaborately staged. She has inspired an almost cultish devotion among those who know her art. Cahun pioneered many of the concerns of contemporary artists like Cindy Sherman, who was born the year Cahun died. Cahun was born in France and was an avid participant in the cultural avant garde of Montparnasse in the 1920s and 30s mingling with many of the leading artists of her day, she eventually moved to Jersey, in the Channel Isles where she was imprisoned during the Nazi occupation. Exhibition organised in collaboration with Jersey Heritage Trust]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[150]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Art Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7293]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Museums & Galleries]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[6 Jun 2014 - 7 Sep 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10107.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10107.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[6218]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Gotterdammerung]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Twilight of the Gods

Opera North's four-year traversal of Der Ring des Nibelungen reaches the cycle's overwhelming conclusion. The all-consuming love of Siegfried and Bruunhilde is broken in bitter betrayal; the machinations of Hagen, son of Alberich, seal Siegfried's doom; and Bruunhilde's self-immolation precipitates the end of the old world order and the beginning of a new era.

The musical and dramatic power of Gotterdammerung is awe-inspiring - from Siegfried's Rhine Journey, to the mighty chorus of the Gibichung vassals, in which the Chorus of Opera North is joined by the internationally renowned Huddersfield Choral Society, to Siegfried's Funeral March, and - above all - to Brunnhilde's immolation and the work's titanic orchestral climax.

Alwyn Mellor, widely praised for her radiant portrayal of Sieglinde in Opera North's Die Walkre in 2012, sings the role of Brunnhilde in these performances. She is joined by a cast that also includes the American tenor Daniel Brenna as Siegfried and Susan Bickley as Waltraute. All are under the guidance of Opera North's Music Director Richard Farnes, whose conducting of the previous instalments of this cycle has been universally acclaimed.

Lasts approximately 6 hours 15 mins.

Please note: performance time includes two intervals, one of 30 mins, and one of 1 hour 15 mins.

Sung in German with English titles

A collaboration with The Sage Gateshead and Symphony Hall, Birmingham.

Financially supported by the Opera North Future Fund and The Ring Fellowship.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[313]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Town Hall]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1027]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Opera North]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[14 Jun 2014 - 12 Jul 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/6218.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/6218.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10507]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Beeston Festival]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Beeston Festival is a celebration of everything that's good in our diverse and vibrant community.

As usual  you will find:

Entertainment across four stages
Food from around the world
A bazaar full of games, clothes, jewellery, plants and information
Sports, games and activities for children and young people
A fun fair

Plus this year we have a cycling theme to tie in with the Grand Depart of the Tour de France. You will find bike activities, bike maintenance, bike inspired art and bike inspired food!

So come on, Let's Go Cycling! Let's Go Beeston Festival!

Image: Paul Bullivant/Beeston Festival]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[302]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Cross Flatts Park]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[6516]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Beeston Festival Committee]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[14 Jun 2014 12:00pm - 5:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10507.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10507.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10110]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Tour De Cinema]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The Tour de Cinema, working with National Trust, Cine Yorkshire and many other partners, will unveil thirty super-high-definition screens in unusual locations across Yorkshire for an unrivalled programme of fiction and non-fiction films about cycling.

The programme includes a brand new commission teaming up award-winning director Daisy Asquith with composer Bill Nelson and drawing on rare BFI film and music archives to chart the journey of the bicycle from new technology to familiar household transport.

It also highlights forgotten treasures like Alan Bennett's rarely seen BBC film from the 1970s - A Day Out, about a Halifax cycling club, and is a chance to see The Big Melt, paying homage to a century of steel-making with a blazing soundtrack compiled by Sheffield's Jarvis Cocker.

Alongside these gems, The Yorkshire Film Archive introduces a newly compiled film drawn from cine club and home movie collections to show cycling in all its forms, from childhood to adulthood.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[295]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Millennium Square]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10108]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Festival Yorkshire]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[15 Jun 2014 ]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10110.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10110.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10209]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Mango Tree]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The Mango Tree is a new ambitious production by Musical ARC which promises to break new ground in combining shadow theatre, traditional and contemporary dance and music. 

Musical Arc, a charity for disabled musicians, has commissioned shadow theatre artist Rebekah Caputo to devise a shadow show of a traditional indian folk story; The Mango Tree. Rebekah is also working with Indian Kathak dancer Jyoti Manral and contemporary dancer Amy Manancourt to bring to life this magical tale of princesses, demons, lotis flowers and managos! An original soundtrack devised and played by Musical Arc will accompany the performance led by Lorraine Cowburn as artistic director. Using ground breaking techniques and a multiscreen set, the production will merge shadow and dance; dancers will become shadow puppets, puppets will become dancers in a seamless fusion between what is in front, and, behind the screens. 
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[312]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Venue, Leeds College of Music]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[20 Jun 2014 7:00pm - 8:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10209.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10209.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10115]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Bicyclism ]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Bicyclism is a new exhibition about people in and around Leeds who inhabit cycling, its history and popular culture. A collaboration between photographer Casey Orr, writer/musician Boff Whalley and curator Jenny Harris, Bicyclism includes a series of new portraits of (extra) ordinary Leeds cyclists, from stunt bikers in skate parks to local men and women who pedal daily well into old age, alongside crowd-sourced and archive images of Leeds people on their bikes.

The exhibition will unearth stories and histories of the area's cycling past, from the socialist Clarion Clubs to the role played by bicycles in the suffrage movement, from cycling cafe culture to the role of the many cycling clubs (and the cyclists) in Leeds' social history, geography and landscape.

A new soundtrack composed using bicycles will accompany the exhibition. Watch the live at the Museum on Thursday 26th June. 

Be Part Of It: If you have a photo in your album of you or a family member on their bike that you would like to submit for inclusion in the exhibition visit www.bicyclism.co.uk for more information.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[385]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds City Museum]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7293]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Museums & Galleries]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[24 Jun 2014 - 7 Jul 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10115.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10115.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10113]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Electronic Gears]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Berlyn Trilogy, Black Planet, Palmeres

Yorkshire has a long established history of electronic music spanning back to the late 70's. Acts like Human League, Cabaret Voltaire and Heaven 17 paved the way. Sheffield being the central hub during the early years but Leeds also gave birth to Soft Cell and the Sisters of Mercy.

The Dance music scene of the late 80's and 90's carried on this tradition with clubs The Orbit and Back to basics bring through a new breed of producer/artist. LFO and The Utah Saints hit the big time along side Sheffield's seminal label Warp.

To this day the region has been a hot bed for all things electronic. Electronic Gears aim in one night to show the rich pioneering musical heritage that Yorkshire has to offer.

A line up of Live bands, Producers and DJs will perform and show why Yorkshire is still at the cutting edge of the electronic music scene.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[10112]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Musiquarium Unit ]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10108]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Festival Yorkshire]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[28 Jun 2014 ]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10113.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10113.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9545]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Beryl]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Written by Maxine Peake Beryl celebrates the extraordinary sporting achievements of Morley cyclist Beryl Burton.

It was 1954 when Beryl Charnock met keen cyclist Charlie Burton.  In those days they cycled in clubs and once Beryl started she was smitten, not only with Charlie but by the thrill and freedom found on two wheels. Beryl was better than good, she was the best and she was determined to stay that way.

Five times world champion, thirteen times national champion, twice road-racing world champion and twelve times national champion. Her accolades include time trials, former world record holder, former British record holder, numerous sports awards an MBE and an OBE. BerylBurtonwas one of the most astonishing sports people ever to have lived - but with her down to earth, no-nonsense approach to life and to success, she remains a mystery.

To celebrate Yorkshire's role in this year's Tour de France, this is a specially commissioned adaptation from Maxine Peake's acclaimed 2012 Radio 4 play and marks her stage writing debut. ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[395]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[West Yorkshire Playhouse]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[829]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[West Yorkshire Playhouse]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[30 Jun 2014 - 19 Jul 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9545_1.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9545_1.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10415]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Yorkshire Bicycle Show]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The second Yorkshire Bicycle Show will take place in Leeds this summer.  Held within the majestic rooms of Leeds Town Hall 4-6 July 2014, it will coincide with the Tour de France Grand Depart in the city centre and be right at the heart of this great Yorkshire cycling weekend.

The Show will present cycling at its best. With a wide array of bicycles and accessories, from handmade frames, to top-end road and mountain bikes, visitors of all ages will find something to excite them. There'll be demonstrations of craftsmanship, dare-devil displays of cycling skill, as well as a packed programme of talks from some of Britain's most intrepid cyclists. Proud to be an independent project, the Show is organised by local businesses to celebrate and promote the region. 
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[313]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Town Hall]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10414]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Yorkshire Bicycle Show]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[4 Jul 2014 - 6 Jul 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10415_0.png]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10415_0.png]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[8554]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Grand Depart 2014]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[It is official: The world's greatest cycle race - the Tour de France - will start in the world's greatest county on 5th & 6th July 2014 bringing millions of fans to the Yorkshire roadside to cheer on the champions of the sport.

It will be the first time Le Tour has visited the north of England having previously only made visits to the south coast and the capital. We guarantee it will be a festival and a spectacle for fans and first timers alike and are sure Yorkshire will rise to occasion and give the riders, the teams and the race organisers a Grand Depart to remember. Yorkshire is a world class county and it will deliver a world class event.

The official route of the 2014 race including road-by-road details of the route the legendary cycle race will take through Leeds when the Grand Depart begins in the city on the morning of Saturday 5 July can be seen at the website - www.letouryorkshire.com.

After completing the official signing-in ceremony in front of Leeds Town Hall, the world's leading riders will then line up on The Headrow for the ceremonial start of the Tour de France. The initial non-racing rollout will see the peloton ride along The Headrow to Eastgate before turning left onto Regent Street and following the A61 out of town towards Harewood. 

For those keen to view the race as it journeys through Leeds, there will be spectator 'hubs' including family-focused activities at Scott Hall playing fields and Harewood House with other locations also being discussed.

The route of stage one is to start to be permanently waymarked so cyclists and motorists can follow the stage themselves in the build-up and following the Grand Depart.

Routes of the Grand Depart including interactive maps are available on www.letouryorkshire.com]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[313]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Town Hall]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[5 Jul 2014 11:00am]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/8554.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/8554.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10284]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Joe's Bakery Grand Depart Presents Vidal Benjamin & Alexis Le Tan (Paris)]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Joe's Bakery and Outlaws Yacht Club celebrate the Tour de France Grand Depart in Leeds with two of their favorite DJs from Paris.  Vidal Benjamin and Alexis Le Tan have earned a wolrld wide reputation for digging deep into left-field cosmic disco, funk and balearic sounds and creating inspiring mixtapes and dj sets.

Hosted in the relaxed environment of Outlaws Yacht Club, Music starts at 2pm with Joe's Bakery residents, Craig Christon, Moonboots & Joe Gill playing records before Vidal & Alexis.  Combined with live art, locally sourced food and a great selection of drinks

The event will run until 11pm followed by secret after party.  For more info contact us on info@joesbakery.org]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3679]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Outlaws Yacht Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7768]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Outlaws Yacht Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[5 Jul 2014 2:00pm - 11:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10284_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10284_0.jpg]]></image_original></item></objects></response>