<?xml version="1.0"?><response><status><![CDATA[200]]></status><status_message><![CDATA[OK]]></status_message><message><![CDATA[OK]]></message><objects><item><event_id><![CDATA[8847]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Rembrandt: Portraits & People]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Etchings from the Collection of Leeds Art Gallery.

This season's Winter/Spring exhibition at Temple Newsam House offers the rare chance to see a selection of prints made by the greatest printmaker the world has ever seen - Rembrandt Harmensz van Rijn (1606 - 1665).  The exhibition will run for nine months and will consist of two displays; the first will examine Rembrandt's portraits and figure studies and the second, will showcase a selection of Rembrandt's biblical prints.

Rembrandt's career as a printmaker ran parallel with his painting, but he rarely treated the same subject in both medium and only on a few occasions did he reproduce his paintings in print.  Indeed for Rembrandt, print was a distinct art form which he pursued as actively as he did his painting; quickly learning the technical skills involved in etching Rembrandt virtually recreated this technique.  His impact and contribution to printmaking is unprecedented and is so significant that it is still reflected in etchings produced today.

Portraits and People brings together Rembrandt's prints of people the first half to this exhibition will focus on his early experimental prints in which Rembrandt developed both his technique and his interest in showing emotion and thought through detailed observations of facial expressions. Highlights include a selection of Rembrandt's iconic self-portraits, etchings of his mother and wife Saskia, a group of Rembrandt's prints of beggars, and a selection of his later and more ambitious prints including 'Faust'. 

Image: Cropped self-portrait in cap and scarf with the face dark: bust, signed and dated Rembrandt f. 1633, Haarlem.  Second state of two, B17. Copyright: Leeds Museums and Galleries and licensed under Creative Commons BY NC SA.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[155]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Temple Newsam House and Estate]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7293]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Museums & Galleries]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[19 Nov 2013 - 30 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/8847.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/8847.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9729]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[A Snapshot of Yorkshire]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Discover a new exhibition celebrating Yorkshire past and present.

We all know that Yorkshire is the biggest county in England.
Famous for its beautiful green spaces and sprawling landscapes it is also home to the longest steam operated railway in the UK, Britain's highest pub and the oldest registered visitor attraction in the country.

To celebrate this, Abbey House Museum has a fantastic new
exhibition all about Yorkshire and the traditions which make
it what it is today.

Discover which beauty spots were voted as the favourite place to visit in our Yorkshire survey, find out which famous brands originate from this county, learn about Yorkshire people and culture, and take a closer look at iconic and quirky Yorkshire objects from our collections.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[152]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Abbey House Museum]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7293]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Museums & Galleries]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[25 Jan 2014 - 31 Dec 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9729.PNG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9729.PNG]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9016]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Playground]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Come and enjoy exciting multisensory art events inspired by a different Gallery artwork each month.

Suitable for under five's and their carers to gain confidence in themselves as learners, explorers, discoverers and thinkers. 

Drop in event. Please wear suitable clothes. ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[150]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Art Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7293]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Museums & Galleries]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[15 Nov 2013 - 25 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9016.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9016.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10538]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Knights: Myths & Magic]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[What better way to spend the Easter break than delving into the world of knights, myths and magic and exploring the history behind one of the world's largest collections of arms and armour? 

This Easter, Royal Armouries Museum in Leeds is presenting a packed programme of events from 5 - 21 April, around the life of a medieval knight, from heraldry to the tournament. 

Activities include:
Camelot Kids
Magic Shows
Falconry (Wed & Sat)
Stunt-riding Show (Fri & Sat)

As always, there will be plenty of opportunities to get up close to history with handling sessions, tours, dramatic presentations and lively talks by our enthusiastic and knowledgeable Visitor Experience team.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[393]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Royal Armouries]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[2613]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Royal Armouries]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[5 Apr 2014 - 21 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10538.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10538.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[7406]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Gruesome Newsam House Tour ]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[All the ghastly and ghostly secrets of Temple Newsam will be revealed in this guided tour of the house. ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[155]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Temple Newsam House and Estate]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[19 Feb 2014 - 16 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/7406.JPG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/7406.JPG]]></image_original></item></objects></response>