<?xml version="1.0"?><response><status><![CDATA[200]]></status><status_message><![CDATA[OK]]></status_message><message><![CDATA[OK]]></message><objects><item><event_id><![CDATA[10198]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[PAN Berlin Record Label]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Leeds College of Art welcomes an exhibition from PAN, a critically acclaimed platform for experimental sound and art, based between Berlin and New York. This exhibition showcases a range of artwork produced by the label for PAN artists' records.  
 
Founded in 2008 by artist Bill Kouligas, PAN represents a community of artists united by their singular contributions to the electronic vanguard. PAN has released records by some of the world's most acclaimed electronic and experimental artists over its four year lifespan. The beautiful artwork is a critical part of its success, and, for Bill and label partner Kathryn Politis, a crucial part of the business, conceived as a visual project as much as a musical one.
 
The PAN label boss Bill Kouligas says, "The design of the label has a cohesive aesthetic that the musicians/artists we work with are aware of. There is no fixed process in regards to working with them on the artwork, PAN strive to make something within the concept of their album as far as possible, and we both approve the final artwork. Some artists are more involved than others; some may suggest images they want to use, or drawings of theirs they would like translated into the PVC design. With others we discuss influences that they would like to see incorporated into the design on a more abstract level. In any case, with each release, comes an exchange of ideas. The label was conceived initially as a platform for our artwork and interests. We are trying to not limit ourselves to being a record label in the traditional sense; there have been numerous shows, events, showcases and festivals etc. to date as part of the label, and there are some non-music related projects in the works."

This exhibition is free and open to all members of the public. ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[5496]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds College of Art, Blenheim Walk Building]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10124]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds College of Art]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[14 Feb 2014 - 16 May 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10198_1.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10198_1.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9484]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Toby Greenwood's "We Free Kings"]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[feat Toby Greenwood sax and leader, Kevin Holbrough trombone, Jim Corry  baritone sax, Jamil Sheriff on piano, Garry Jackson string bass and Chris Sykes drums

Original music composed and arranged by this gifted Leeds saxman.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2558]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Seven Jazz@Seven Arts Leeds]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1352]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Seven Jazz at Seven Arts Leeds]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[9 Mar 2014 1:00pm - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9484.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9484.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10496]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Twelve Twelve Hundreds]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[A celebratory series of iconic Technics SL1200/1210mk2 turntables, re-imagined by artist/designer Dan Axon.  Plus Dj set from Photographer Grant Fleming and the Launch of Outlaws Record Shop.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3679]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Outlaws Yacht Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7768]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Outlaws Yacht Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[9 Mar 2014 1:00pm - 11:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10496.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10496.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10395]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Nadine Carina]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Nadine Carina is the electronic-folk songstress born in Switzerland but currently residing in Liverpool, Nadine graduated from the renowned Liverpool Institute of Performing Arts. Nadine live show brings an experiment with looping vintage toys, small percussive instruments and electronic drum beats. Her vocals have previously lent Nadine fans from some of music's favourite outlets including The 405, Artrocker and Bido Lito Magazine as well as support slots for Coco Rosie, MS MR and How To Dress Well in the last year.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[9073]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Belgrave Music Hall and Canteen]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[9660]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Belgrave Music Hall]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[9 Mar 2014 7:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10395.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10395.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10020]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[365 Leeds Stories Choir]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Would you like to sing songs about Leeds?

We are looking for people who enjoy singing to take part in a 10 week choir project. No experience is necessary but enthusiasm is essential!

There are many things we take for granted about the place we live in - and what is familiar to one person may be surprising to someone else. 365 Leeds Stories is a way of sharing our experience of the city in a creative and informal way.

Since September 2013, Leeds-based artists Matthew Bellwood and Alison Andrews have been working together with a range of people who live, work or seek residence in Leeds on the creation of series of maps of the city; maps that tell stories and make connections between the people who live there. They have been rendered in different forms - expressed in textiles, written in stories, floated down the river or rendered as conventional cartographic representations, albeit with a twist.

In November and December, we ran two day-long workshops with composer James Redwood. These were open to anyone in the city who wanted to come along and join in. We spent the first day getting to know each other and sharing ideas, thoughts, feelings and impressions of the city, before settling down to write some lyrics that we felt summed up our experiences of living in Leeds. The material we created was quite diverse - quirky, poetic and sometimes slightly sinister. By the end of the first day, we felt we had the basis for three different songs.

The following week, we worked with James to set the songs to music. James led us in a series of warm-ups, which got us on our feet and singing together and then helped us to find our way into the songs, deciding on a tone and mood for each one, pulling out melodies and rhythms from the group and shaping the resultant material. He then took the pieces away with him to polish up and score.

From 24th February onwards, we'll be working with vocal animateur Caroline Challis to bring these songs to life, with a view to singing them at the opening of the project exhibition in Leeds Central Library on 3rd May.

Rehearsals will be at the Central Library on Monday evenings (6.15pm - 7.45pm) from 24th February.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[476]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Central Library]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10019]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[365 Leeds Stories]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[24 Feb 2014 - 28 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10020.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10020.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9287]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Hy Brasil]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The isle is full of noises

'In the world of wildlife sound recording, Chris Watson is the daddy' The Guardian


Hy Brasil is a mysterious, enchanted island, hidden in fog somewhere off the coast of Ireland. It reveals itself to human eye and ear just one day every seven years. This specially commissioned work by sound artist Chris Watson (BBC TV's award-winning Frozen Planet), brings that day on Hy Brasil to life in an immersive sound installation.

Hy Brasil is composed of compelling wildlife sounds from around the world, drawing visitors deep into the haunting song of seals and the awe-inspiring shrieks of thousands of Manx shearwaters. With glorious ambi-sonic sound and beautiful lighting, lose yourself in the strange and magical world of Hy Brasil.

Supported by the Opera North Future Fund, The Emerald Foundation and Esmee Fairbairn Foundation]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1026]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4191]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[28 Feb 2014 - 15 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9287.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9287.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10274]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Gwilym Simcock Quintet]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Gwilym Simcock is one of the most gifted pianists and imaginative composers on the British scene.  Able to move effortlessly between jazz and classical music, he can, at times, inhabit both worlds and has been described as stylistically reminiscent of Keith Jarrett, complete with 'harmonic sophistication and subtle dovetailing of musical traditions' as well as being a pianist of 'exceptional', 'brilliant' and 'dazzling' ability.  His music has been widely acclaimed as 'engaging, exciting, often unexpected, melodically enthralling, complex and wonderfully optimistic'.

Gwilym Simcock, Piano
Ruth Palmer, Violin
Yuri Goloubev, Bass
Gabriella Swallow, Cello
Martin France, Drums]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[8991]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Venue]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[8992]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds College of Music]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[11 Mar 2014 7:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10274_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10274_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10236]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Rambling Irishman: Brendan Shine]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Brendan Shine started his band with school pal Johnny Dawson as a drummer and singer over 30 years ago. In that time Brendan has appeared at renowned venues such as Carnegie Hall in New York and the Royal Albert Hall in London. He has also appeared on TV shows in Ireland and the UK including Breakfast TV. In Ireland he has had 34 hit singles, 15 of which were Irish no 1s. His biggest hit single was Do You Want Your Old Lobby Washed Down (no 1 in Ireland for 12 weeks), spending several weeks in the top 75 in the UK. Brendans other hits include O'Brien Has No Where To Go, Catch me if you Can My Son, Carrots Galway Girl and Rose Of Castlerea. Brendans new single Where Did He Meet Her is from the album of the same name.
 
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1043]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1252]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[11 Mar 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10236.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10236.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9196]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Stiff Little Fingers]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Using the band's rich musical legacy as a building block, the time has come to bring the newest chapter of the band's music to the world. The new songs, penned over the last decade, show a definite musical growth in the band. Plans are to record and release the new material in 2014.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1790]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[O2 Academy ]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4176]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[O2 Academy Leeds]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[12 Mar 2014 7:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9196.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9196.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10174]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Martin Harley Band]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Martin Harley is a phenomenally talented guitarist, singer and songwriter he fronts the highly praised UK-based acoustic trio; The Martin Harley Band. Martin's latest album MOJO FIX which was recorded in Texas, comes on the heels of four critically celebrated albums, years of touring and countless festivals that have built Martin a strong and solid fan-base spanning the globe.

Martin is a deeply important and respected voice in the evolution of popular blues and folk oriented guitar and vocals. He is now expanding on his international success with recent time spent in the US recording and touring.

A life long devotee of acoustic guitar music, especially the ageless blues/roots sounds, Martin has travelled the globe absorbing a plethora of diverse influences and honing his craft into the classic song-writing style he possesses today.

Renowned for his prowess as a slide guitarist, he is almost unique in the UK in his playing lap slide. In other areas and styles, however, he has proved himself a master guitarist and a consistently astounding songwriter. Look for Martin's videos "Winter Coat", "Love In the Afternoon", and "Mojo Fix" taken from the album of the same name.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1529]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Brudenell Social Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4204]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Brudenell Social Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[12 Mar 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10174.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10174.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10175]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Grails]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[With support from Lilacs and Champagne.

Originally conceived as a casual side-project in 2000, Portland, Oregon's Grails have patiently developed into a rather radical study in tension and meditation, inhabiting a netherworld where virtually all earthly and otherwordly sounds are equally explored to reflect the disparate influences of its four members. After releasing their first two albums on the Neurosis imprint Neurot Recordings, Grails followed up with 'Black Tar Prophecies Vol's 1,2 &, 3' on Important Records before ultimately finding their home at Temporary Residence Ltd.

MEMBERS: Emil Amos, Alex John Hall, Wm. Zakary Riles, William Slater]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1529]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Brudenell Social Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4204]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Brudenell Social Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Mar 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10175.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10175.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10276]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Nonclassical Club Night With Gabriel Prokofiev]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Gabriel Prokofiev is a London-based composer, producer, DJ and founder of the NONCLASSICAL record label & club night.

Composing music that both embraces and challenges western classical traditions, Gabriel has emerged at the forefront of a new approach to classical music in the UK at the beginning of the 21st century.

His Concerto for Turntables was performed at the BBC Proms in August 2011 to critical acclaim, conducted by Vladimir Jurowski with world champion DJ Switch as soloist, and broadcast on BBC2 television.

Other recent works include a poly-stylistic 'orchestral remix' of Beethoven's Ninth Symphony commissioned by John Axelrod and the Orchestre National des Pays de la Loire, France, performed sold-out concert halls in Angers and Nantes in June 2011; a 3rd String Quartet premiered by the Ruysdael Kwartet at the Wigmore Hall in 2010; 'import/export/ a percussion suite for Global Junk, toured in UK & USA by Joby Burgess's Powerplant; and a book for Solo Piano recorded by Russian virtuoso GeNIA.

Prokofiev's own distinctive sound is informed by his background as a producer of hip-hop, grime, and electro records, as well as his earlier involvement in electroacoustic music at York and Birmingham universities, which saw him win a Residency prize at the prestigious Bourges International Electroacoustic Music Competition in 1998.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1364]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Cockpit]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[8992]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds College of Music]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Mar 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10276.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10276.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10527]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Republic Of Fentonia]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The Republic of Fentonia presents:

THE CADAVERS (hardcore punk from Sheffield)

This is hardcore punk the way it should be...dark, brooding, powerful, usually fast, tuneful, and with proper singing (non of that screamo nonsense or winey metal bollocks).

https://soundcloud.com/cadaverssheffield
https://www.facebook.com/cadaverssheffield


CHAPTER 13 (post-punk band from Brighouse)

Their punk roots are obvious, but they've evolved into something a little different. 

http://soundcloud.com/chapter13


RADIO PARTIZAN (old-skool punk/folk)

Stalwarts of the Leeds punk/post-punk scene, a three piece into sharp songs, great guitar riffs and radical politics, including members of The Monkeywrenchers, so its should be no surprise that a bit of folk-punk creeps into their old-skool punk sets. Great tunes, great performers, lovely people!

https://www.facebook.com/pages/Radio-Partizan/341398845676
https://soundcloud.com/radio-partizan


DEAD SEA STRATEGY (hardcore folk-punk)

"We formed mid 2013, rising from the ashes of previous line ups and are now ready to take over the world. We'll never be folk to the folkies and we'll never be punk to the punks and we really couldn't care less, we play what we think sounds good and make friends along the way."

Sounds punk to me! 

http://www.myspace.com/deadseastrategy
https://www.facebook.com/deadseastrategy
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[5360]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Fenton]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[8821]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Fred Bloggs]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Mar 2014 8:00pm - 11:15pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10527.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10527.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10393]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Unsung Heroes]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[A Together Women International Women's Day celebration.

Together Women (TWP) is a Leeds charity supporting women experiencing multiple needs and social exclusion with women's centres across Yorkshire and Humberside and one in Leeds City Centre. 

The theme of the day is Unsung Heroes: A celebration of the women in Leeds and those who support them.
 
An afternoon of music, a photography display and an opportunity to showcase groups, campaigns, organisations and individuals who are working actively to engage women, promote the equality of women or give women a voice in Leeds and around the world.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[440]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Civic Hall]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10392]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Together Women]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[14 Mar 2014 11:00am - 3:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10393_0.png]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10393_0.png]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10237]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Good Old Days]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The Legendary Music Hall Experience.

Ladies and Gentlemen... take your seats for a trip back to The Good Old Days of the Music Halls, sit back and enjoy an unrivalled bill filled with the cream of Variety entertainers from across the globe!

With your worthy Chairman Mr Johnny Dennis and Barney's Players plus The City Varieties Orchestra under the direction of Mr David Smith.

Acts include, Barry & Josh Benson, Goroway Thom, Caroline Fields and Maurice Kachuk. Headlining is British Comedy Ventriloquist Steve Hewlett. 

]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1043]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1252]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[14 Mar 2014 - 29 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10237_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10237_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9176]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Metronomy]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Metronomy live shows are known for their charming dance routines and light shows, most notably the push lights stuck to their chests! Remix after remix established them as a big underground dance act but 2nd album Nights Out took it into the stratosphere. Now a fully fledged 3-piece live outfit check them out later this year on tour.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1790]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[O2 Academy ]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4176]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[O2 Academy Leeds]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[14 Mar 2014 7:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9176.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9176.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10275]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Scanner]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Robin Rimbaud, a.k.a. Scanner, traverses the experimental terrain between sound and form, creating absorbing, multi-layered sound pieces that twist technology in unconventional ways. His albums Mass Observation (1994), Delivery (1997), and The Garden is Full of Metal (1998) are hailed by critics as innovative and inspirational works of contemporary electronic music.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[9073]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Belgrave Music Hall and Canteen]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[8992]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds College of Music]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[14 Mar 2014 8:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10275.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10275.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10391]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Caddy Cooper]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Caddy Cooper is an exhilarating acoustic country, blues, folk singer who entices her audience with tales of life, love, loss and the fragility of the human condition. Hailing from Western Australia, Caddy is currently touring the UK to promote her debut album 'Snapshot'. Her live shows have been receiving rave reviews and Caddy will be backed on the night by her band.
"...an utterly beguiling and inspired musician. The real deal." ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[956]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Headingley Enterprise and Arts Centre (HEART)   ]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[14 Mar 2014 8:00pm - 10:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10391.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10391.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9668]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[City Of Leeds Youth Orchestra]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Dougie Scarfe leads the orchestra in performances of Verdi Nabucco: Overture, Puccini Manon Lescaut: Intermezzo, Tchaikovsky Francesca da Rimini and Elgar Enigma Variations.

Verdi Nabucco: Overture
Puccini Manon Lescaut: Intermezzo
Tchaikovsky Francesca da Rimini
Elgar Enigma Variations

The City of Leeds Youth Orchestra's performances in recent years are one of the great success stories of music making in the region. The orchestra now numbers nearly 100 young musicians and this programme is perfect to show off these wonderful young talents.

The orchestra will be touring to Perugia in July 2014 and the concert's first half is full of Italian inspiration - Verdi's dramatic overture to Nabucco followed by the most beautiful orchestral intermezzo in all Puccini operas and Tchaikovsky's finest tone poem, which was inspired by the tragic tale of Francesca in Dante's Divine Comedy.

Always keen to perform the great English Orchestral works, the orchestra is proud to be performing Elgar's Enigma Variations both in their home city but
also when they represent Leeds in Italy.

 ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[313]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Town Hall]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[801]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds International Concert Season]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[15 Mar 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9668.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9668.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9593]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Saturday Night Live]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Every Saturday join us for Live Music or DJ from 8pm.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[9587]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Inkwell Bar]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[28 Dec 2013 - 3 Jan 2015]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9593.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9593.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9485]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Jamil Sherrif Trio]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Supported by Jazz North - local pianist composer and educator Jamil Sheriff with his all-star trio.

Jami Sheriff piano, Dave Walsh drums and Gary Jackson bass


]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1614]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Inkwell]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7935]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Seven Jazz Leeds]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[16 Mar 2014 1:00pm - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9485_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9485_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10049]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Telescopes]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[PLUS SUPPORT

Formed in 1987 by Stephen Lawrie, The Telescopes are an English noise, space rock, dream pop and psychedelic band, drawing influence from artists such as Suicide, The Velvet Underground and The 13th Floor Elevators. They have a total of six released albums since their debut, Taste, released in 1989.

http://thetelescopes.bandcamp.com/
https://www.facebook.com/thetelescopesuk]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[9073]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Belgrave Music Hall and Canteen]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[9660]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Belgrave Music Hall]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[16 Mar 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10049.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10049.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10499]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Squeeze]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Sunday Night Blues Dance Lesson and Social Dance.

Join us for the start of a brand new blues experience in Leeds!

The Squeeze is a monthly blues dance event where you can learn authentic blues and blues fusion dance, and move to some of the most sultry and smoking tunes north of Memphis - music from Nina Simone to Nora Jones, Ray Charles to James Blake.

Low lights glisten, shimmering images of projected dancers glide overhead.  The sound of Delta blues, cool jazz and current soul fills the air as pairs of dancers shimmy, shake and slide across the dancefloor with seemingly effortless abandon.  This is the cutting edge of contemporary blues dance, this is The Squeeze.

Beginners Blues Class 8pm - 9pm 
Social Blues Dance 9pm - midnight
No experience necessary or partner required 

Cosy venue, delicious food and drinks!

FAQs

What is Blues Dance? 
Blues dance is a distinctive style of dancing which developed alongside blues music more than 100 years ago and is still developing today, with a huge revival in many cities all over the world. 

I've never danced (anything!) before, can I still join?
Absolutely, the class at 8pm will be aimed at absolute beginners, but there will enough content to satisfy those who have previously danced blues too.

Do I need to buy a ticket?
It's strongly recommended that you buy a ticket beforehand as similar events have sold out, and due to the cosy nature of the venue, once we get to capacity, to ensure our dancers' comfort and safety, we will not be allowing any more participants.  The only way to guarantee your place at the dance is to buy a ticket beforehand.

What do I need to bring?
Just your ticket (otherwise it's &pound;5 on the door, if we still have space).  Wear comfortable clothes and shoes. You're welcome to come along with a partner or group of friends, but many people come on their own, and as long as there's space, we will accommodate you, whatever group size you are.

What kind of music do you play?
We play everything from traditional blues and swing jazz from the 1920s onwards, right up to blues-friendly tunes from the last few years, including a sprinkling of soul, r&b and torch songs.

Why the Squeeze?
Blues dancing is best suited to cosy, informal venues, and as Upstairs at LS6 has a maximum capacity of 60 people, the name just seemed to fit!]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[10497]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Upstairs at LS6 Cafe]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10498]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[James F Clark]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[16 Mar 2014 8:00pm - 11:45pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10499.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10499.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10056]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Leeds College Of Music Jazz Ensemble]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Tim Garland is one of the UKs best travelled jazz soloists, not only having been a regular with Chick Corea for fourteen years, but also creating repertoires for the trios Lighthouse, Acoustic Triangle and Storms/Nocturnes. His Grammy-winning orchestral arranging as well as his world class playing have earned him an international reputation as a powerful yet lyrical artist. He formed The Underground Orchestra (10 piece big band) in London's Soho 13 years ago and now gives advanced students the opportunity of sharing in this repertoire.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[8991]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Venue]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[8992]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds College of Music]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[17 Mar 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10056.png]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10056.png]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10509]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Rothwell Competitive Music Festival]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Rothwell Competitive Music Festival is held annually in March, and the committee also organises other fundraising concerts.

The Showcase concert on Friday 28th March 7pm at Rothwell Methodist Church will include performances by selected competitors from several classes accompanied by David Wilks. ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[10508]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Rothwell Methodist Church]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[19 Mar 2014 - 22 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10509_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10509_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9285]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Bassekou Kouyate & Ngoni Ba]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Jama Ko

'defiant, angry new music from Mali by the world's greatest exponent of the ngoni, the ancient West African lute ... Magnificent.' The Guardian on Jama Ko
Grammy Award nominated Bassekou Kouyate is the ambassador of the ngoni, one of the oldest string instruments in Africa. Kouyate's re-working of his musical heritage to embrace blues, jazz and rock has seen him hailed as a visionary who has completely changed the perception of his ancient instrument.

His latest album Jama Ko, recorded during the 2012 coup in Mali, documents a musician determined to carry his message out amid a climate of oppression.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1026]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4191]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[19 Mar 2014 7:45pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9285.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9285.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9197]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[OneRepublic]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Since reaching number 1 in the official singles chart with Counting Stars; OneRepublic have announced a full UK tour for March 2014. Counting Stars has gone top ten around the world and is taken from OneRepublic's third studio album Native which was released in 2013.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1790]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[O2 Academy ]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4176]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[O2 Academy Leeds]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[20 Mar 2014 7:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9197.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9197.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9470]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Jean Toussaint Quartet]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Jean Toussaint tenor sax, Andrew McCormack piano, Larry Bartley bass and Troy Miller drums 

Top UK based Saxophone player - and ex-member of Art Blakey's Jazz Messengers, Jean Toussaint is back at Seven Arts leading his own quartet.  Born in the Caribbean, Jean Toussaint studied in New York and joined Art Blakey's Jazz Messengers, playing alongside Terence Blanchard and Mulgrew Miller.  He also worked with Gil Evans, Wynton Marsalis and McCoy Tyner.  In 1987 he moved to London where his playing and teaching have been a major influence on young musicians.

"We haven't had anything like this in New York for over twenty years". Wynton Marsalis

]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2558]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Seven Jazz@Seven Arts Leeds]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1352]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Seven Jazz at Seven Arts Leeds]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[20 Mar 2014 8:00pm - 11:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9470.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9470.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10231]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Orb]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The Orb is celebrating its unique position as one of the few names to emerge from the 1988 acid house revolution still creating vital new music with a series of special 25th anniversary UK shows. With founder Alex Paterson joined by various collaborators over the years, The Orb has released a string of best-selling singles, including 'Little Fluffy Clouds', 'Blue Room' and 'Toxygene', and groundbreaking albums, including the chart-topping 'U.F. Orb', 'Orblivion', 'Metallic Spheres' [with Pink Floyd's Dave Gilmour] and, most recently, two collaborations with reggae legend Lee Perry.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1529]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Brudenell Social Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4204]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Brudenell Social Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[21 Mar 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10231.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10231.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10435]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Hit and Run: Kahn + Neek]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Arguably the best of the new wave of Grime Producers come through to test the perfectly weighted system at Beat Bar, hosted by 2 of the LEVELZ crew SKITTLES and T-MAN.

We also welcome Brotherhood Sounds Leeds Djs Silas and Snare Surgeon, fresh from smashing our room at Fabric London.

KAHN b2b NEEK

ASA b2b SORROW

RICH REASON

SILAS b2b SNARE SURGEON

Hosted by T-MAN and SKITTLES.

Artists / Speakers: KAHN b2b NEEK, ASA b2b SORROW, Rich Reason, SILAS b2b SNARE SURGEON, T-MAN and SKITTLES.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[10325]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Beat Bar]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10326]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Juke Box PR]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[21 Mar 2014 11:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10435_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10435_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9297]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Commission & Cafe Kafka]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[A double bill of adventurous new opera

A selection of Franz Kafka's darkly surreal short stories and characters are interwoven in Cafe Kafka, while The Commission explores the inner world of an artist contemplating murder.

Directed by Annabel Arden, co-founder of Theatre de Complicite, this evening combines potent music with gripping drama and dark humour.

Commissioned by Aldeburgh Music, Royal Opera House and Opera North: giving opportunities to emerging opera writers.
Cafe Kafka by Francisco Coll (music) and Meredith Oakes (words).

The Commission by Elspeth Brooke (music) and Jack Underwood (words).

The Commission is based on a poem by Michael Donaghy, and was originally devised with Ellie Rees.

Supported by Arts Council England's Britten Centenary Fund. Leeds performance supported by the Opera North Future Fund.

Annabel Arden director
Richard Baker conductor
Free pre show talk with Annabel Arden at 6.30pm]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1026]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4191]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[22 Mar 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9297.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9297.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10176]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Selecter]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[featuring Pauline Black and Gaps Hendrickson | plus guest support Talisman.

"Too Much Pressure" released by this important and influential platinum selling band in Feb 1980 remains a classic touchstone for a generation of Ska lovers and the band are excited to announce they will be playing the album in its entirety plus a selection of other much loved Selecter tracks and some new surprises at concerts throughout 2011.

Mixing punk, ska and reggae, 'Too Much Pressure' successfully reflected the social and political issues of the early Thatcher years in Britain and gave a voice to disaffected youth across the racial divide.

The Selecter fronted by the original singing duo of the female icon of the 2-tone era Pauline Black & Arthur 'Gaps' Hendrickson deliver classic hits like 'Three Minute Hero', 'Missing Words', 'On My Radio', 'James Bond' and of course 'Too Much Pressure'.

2011 saw the return of one of the most vital, visceral and important Ska acts ever. Queen of 2- Tone, Pauline Black featured prominently in BBC4's "Reggae Britannia" series, contributing to a 90 mins documentary and a live concert broadcast from The Barbican in London.

The Selecter's new 10 track album 'Made In Britain', featuring covers of Amy Winehouse's 'Back To Black' & a hugely popular anti-racist ska/reggae re-working of Woody Guthrie's 'All You Fascists Bound To Lose'- re-invented as 'Big In The Body- Small In The Mind', which was released in September 2011.

2012 saw The Selecter embark on a 32 date tour of the UK throughout the year, with many venues selling out in advance. Dec 2012 saw the band do their first ever tour of Australia which was a huge success.

2013 saw the band play another 20 dates in the UK in March and then in April the band went back to the USA for the first time in many years culminating in an appearance at the influential Coachella Festival. The band have plans to go back to the USA two more times in 2013 and plans for the Far East and South America in 2014.

Pauline Black has also written a well-received 2-Tone memoir, 'Black By Design' which has been published by 'Serpent's Tail' and released in July 2011. She made an appearance at the Edinburgh International Book Festival in August 2011. The book is released in the US in June 2012.

"'Multiculturalism rules', The Selecter's® Pauline Black says pointedly, hours after David Cameron has declared it dead. In a Midlands rude-girl suit of sharp straight lines, she brings 2-Tone's faster, jerky punk beat and the needling New Wave aggro of 'On My Radio', to which a platoon of fans jog along. - Nick Hasted, The Independent

"...a slick, attacking set from Pauline Black" - Robin Denselow, The Guardian]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1529]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Brudenell Social Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4204]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Brudenell Social Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[22 Mar 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10176.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10176.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10426]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Expansions: Jay Daniel]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[If any of you have heard his mixes or caught him on the Boiler Room, you'll know that Jay throws it down right. He's a passionate, energetic and intuitive DJ who won't be caught standing still behind the turntables.

Making waves in production too, Daniel's debut 12" recently landed on Theo Parrish's Sound Signature: It's four tracks displaying that signature motor city rawness, combined with a depth of musical knowledge well beyond his years. We can't wait to hear more.

Artists / Speakers: Jay Daniel.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[10325]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Beat Bar]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10326]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Juke Box PR]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[22 Mar 2014 11:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10426_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10426_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9483]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Krzysztof Urbanski's "Urban Jazz Society"]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Krzysztof Urbanski -tenor sax , Stuart McCallum- guitar, Martin Longhawn- keyboards, Sam Vicary- bass, Sam Gardner- drums

Award winning Polish saxman who is now making a name for himself worldwide


]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2558]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Seven Jazz@Seven Arts Leeds]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1352]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Seven Jazz at Seven Arts Leeds]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[23 Mar 2014 1:00pm - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9483_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9483_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10551]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Leeds No Borders Monthly Social]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Come along for a celebratory night of food, music, dancing, short films, poetry and talks with a Zimbabwean theme.

All welcome, bring friends and family. Bring along your favourite tunes and let's dance!

Delicious food - bring something to share if you can.

It's 'open mic' so if you want to perform, just step up!]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1603]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Wharf Chambers]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10545]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds No Borders]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[23 Mar 2014 3:00pm - 8:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10551_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10551_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10370]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Bearfoot Beware | United Fruit]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Big Spaceship, Destroy All Monsters, The Gig Barons and Bearfoot Bewarepresent an evening of noise rock and post-hardcore.

BEARFOOT BEWARE
Heading the bill and helping curate the evening are Leeds' finest exponent of post-hardcore people, Bearfoot Beware. I am sure you all know who they are and what they do but if not, they sound like something in between Faraquet, hoovers and fishing and now are evolving to more of a darker blend of early nineties post something like Unwound. Minus all the ludicrous references, they are really good and sound very nice at a gig with a beer or a glass of fine wine. 
There are loads of things on the internet about them. Find it....]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1529]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Brudenell Social Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4204]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Brudenell Social Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[23 Mar 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10370.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10370.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9679]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Little Voices, Opera North]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Little Voices is a series of fun, 45 minute workshops, where adults, tots and babies can be creative together in a friendly environment.  You'll have the chance to sing songs, explore instruments, play games and generally have fun with music.   It's also a great opportunity for socialising and making new friends!  

Sessions aim to introduce music, drama and movement at the earliest stages of a child's development to spark a life-long connection with the arts.  They also provide the ideal environment in which adults and infants can bond through creative play.

Little Voices takes place every Monday during term time at the Howard Assembly Room, Leeds.  There are two sessions each week, at 10am and 11:15am.  Both sessions will share a refreshment break from 10.45-11.15am which you are invited to join before/after your session.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1026]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[8506]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Opera North]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Jan 2014 - 31 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9679.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9679.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10232]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Johnny Marr]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The early 1980s weren't the best of times to be an aspiring guitar player. Twenty years earlier, the head of Decca records, Dick Rowe, had made the biggest A&R gaff in pop history with the legendary clanger "Guitar groups are on their way out, Mr Epstein". But in 1982, Rowe's apocalyptic prophecy suddenly sounded frighteningly real. After the initial roar and storm of punk, British pop music had succumbed to a synthesizer-driven pursuit of new waves and new romanticisms. In an age of Vienna's, Tainted Love's and Too Shy's, the pure sound of six-stringed, melodic pop - be it as amorous as The Beatles, as lascivious as The Stones or as giddy as T.Rex - was fast becoming a lost cause with few willing to fight its corner.

That all changed with Johnny Marr.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1529]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Brudenell Social Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4204]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Brudenell Social Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[24 Mar 2014 - 25 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10232.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10232.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9947]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The King's Men]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Gala Concert by Choral Scholars of King's College Cambridge
includes former Minster Chorister & Choral Scholar Toby Ward from Bramhope in the line-up

Event generously sponsored by Mr Albert Andrews
Special Concert in aid of the Minster Choir Fund

Toby Ward of Bramhope, Leeds, was a boy chorister and choral scholar in the choir of Leeds Parish Church (now Leeds Minster). After completing his A level examinations at Fulneck School, Toby was awarded the tenor Choral Scholarship at Gloucester Cathedral, for the academic year 2013/14. In October 2014, Toby took up a tenor choral scholarship in the choir of King's College, Cambridge.

Toby's musical talent was spotted early, at Bramhope Primary School, and he received piano lessons from the late Michael Sykes of Pool-in-Wharfedale. After a short period at Abbey Grange Church of England High School, Toby was awarded a music scholarship to Fulneck School.

Toby, in his first year at King's reading music, is one of fifteen choral scholars who comprise the back row of the famous King's College Choir, formed in 1516. Following a long tradition, the scholars form a touring group now known as The King's Men, performing regularly around Britain, and recently as far afield as North America, Australia and Hong Kong.

Toby said:
It will be a huge pleasure to return to Leeds Minster, the scene of my early musical education. It was a concert by The King's Men at the minster which inspired me to apply to King's in the first place, so I hope we can help inspire the next generation of the Minster's young musicians, while delivering an entertaining program of music from 500 years ago to the present day.

Dr Simon Lindley, Master of the Music at Leeds Minster said:
We have welcomed the King's choral scholars to Leeds on a number of occasions in the recent past and the students have been of great assistance in raising the profile of choral music here at the Minster. It's obviously particularly special having Toby return this year as a current King's alumnus. Minster Parishioners, along with staff, parents and students at Toby's schools have expressed considerable interest in attending, as have members and friends of Minster-based St Peter's Singers in which Toby sang for a number of years as a teenager, graduating eventually to the solo ranks.
The King's Men is the close harmony group formed from the Choral Scholars of the Choir of King's College, Cambridge. As Choral Scholars they follow the daily routine of Chapel services throughout term, as well as undertaking a busy concert and recording schedule in the vacations.

The Choir is, of course, most famous for the broadcast of the Festival of Nine Lessons and Carols on radio each Christmas, and its companion programme, Carols from King's, on BBC television.

The King's Men, however, functions separately from the main Choir, and is run entirely by the members of the group itself. It performs regularly around Britain, and has performed as far afield as North America, Australia and Hong Kong.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4897]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Minster]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5384]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Minster]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[25 Mar 2014 7:30pm - 9:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9947.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9947.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9680]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Leeds College Of Music New Music Collective]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The New Music Collective is an amplified cross-over ensemble of mixed instruments, often using electronics within live performance.

The ensemble explores mainly vivid, exciting recent repertoire alongside a strong focus on student composers. 

 For this event the New Music Collective will be premiering a selection of exciting new student pieces and playing a recent piece written by Damien Harron called 'So Macho'. They will also be including a version of the minimalist classic 'Coming Together' by the American composer Frederic Rzewski, a real tour de force.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[8991]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Venue]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[8992]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds College of Music]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[27 Mar 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9680.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9680.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10039]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Ring]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Ring is a sound journey in complete darkness and an antidote to choice. Wearing headphones that amplify every intimate detail, you are transported to another room very similar to the one you entered... But in this room you have been recognised.

At times seductive, at times unnerving, Ring places the audience at the heart of a thrilling attack on their own identity.

"I haven't been affected by a show as profoundly in a long time"  Wired
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[395]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[West Yorkshire Playhouse]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[829]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[West Yorkshire Playhouse]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[28 Mar 2014 - 30 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10039.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10039.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9071]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Manic Street Preachers]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Manic Street Preachers arrive at the first direct arena as part of a new UK tour, their first arena dates since a one off singles show in 2011.  

The band released their eleventh studio album which entered the album charts at number four and played a handful of sold out intimate shows after a lengthy break.  Rewind The Film received some of the best reviews of the band's releases to date and saw the single Show Me The Wonder and new release this month Anthem For A Lost Cause flooding the airwaves. They will be playing songs from this album and a selection from their previous ten studio albums, and previewing some tracks from their next album Futurology.

In their career, the Manics have had eight top ten albums, fifteen top ten singles and reached the top of the UK charts three times with album This Is My Truth Tell Me Yours hit singles If You Tolerate This Your Children Will Be Next and The Masses Against The Classes.

]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4063]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[first direct arena]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5131]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[first direct arena]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[28 Mar 2014 7:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9071_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9071_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9552]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Leeds College of Music Chamber Orchestra]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The Leeds College of Music Chamber Orchestra will be joined by the Chamber Choir and acclaimed pianist Wolfgang Manz for a performance of Beethoven's Choral Fantasy.

Peter Selwyn studied Modern Languages at Cambridge and piano accompaniment at the RAM.  He has conducted over 50 operas, including Peter Grimes, Rigoletto, La Traviata, La Boheme, Carmen, Hansel und Gretel, Iphigenie en Tauride, Orfeo and the major Mozart operas at the Staatstheater Nürnberg, where from 1999-2005 he was Head of Music and Kapellmeister. Other opera engagements abroad include Salome for the Singapore Lyric Opera and the Hungarian premiere of Rape of Lucretia for European Opera Centre. For UK companies he has conducted Carmen (WNO), Fidelio, Romeo et Juliette (Opera North), Jenufa, Cenerentola, Emperor of Atlantis (ETO), Hansel und Gretel, La Rondine (Opera Holland Park), Madam Butterfly, Die Zauberflote (European Chamber Opera), Treemonisha (Pegasus Opera) and Don Giovanni (Pimlico Opera). As symphonic conductor he has worked with the Wiener Symphoniker, Nürnberger Philharmoniker and the Orchestra dell' Teatro Comunale di Bologna, as well as with numerous UK orchestras including City of London Sinfonia, Orchestras of Opera North and WNO and Aurora. As assistant conductor he worked for three seasons on the millennial Ring Cycle at Bayreuth, on Death in Venice at the Aldeburgh and Bregenz Festivals, at Glyndebourne and at the Hamburg, Strasbourg and Oslo opera houses. He began his career on the music staff at ENO before moving to the ROH, where he continues to work as a guest. He is co-founder and an Artistic Director of the Internationales Kammermusikfestival Nürnberg for whom he has conducted Rape of Lucretia, Turn of the Screw, Owen Wingrave, Noye´s Fludde, Dido and Aeneas, Soldier´s Tale and two world premieres - das babylonexperiment by Matthew King and Schau nicht zurück, Orfeo by Stefan Hakenberg. He is also a Professor at the RCM. Future plans include conducting the first instalments of The Ring Saga (Wagner's Ring in Jonathan Dove's reduction) for Berwick Festival Opera.

Wolfgang Manz is a German pianist whose international concert career has spanned four decades. His achievements include prizes at international piano competitions in Leeds (1981) and Brussels Concours Reine Elisabeth, 1983). Manz is much in demand as a soloist with orchestras, in solo recitals and chamber music. In 2011, he was appointed as a visiting professor at Leeds College of Music.

Beethoven: Symphony No 5 in C minor, Op 67
Beethoven: Choral Fantasia, Op 80
Bernstein: Chichester Psalms
 
Peter Selwyn, Conductor
Wolfgang Manz, Piano]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[313]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Town Hall]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[8992]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds College of Music]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[28 Mar 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9552.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9552.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10103]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Dearly Noted's Lace And Leather]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Dearly Noted turns ONE YEAR OLD! Let's party!

Bands: Static Needles // Humans as Ornaments // Allusondrugs // Titan's Troubadours.

Within the gig our friend Louise will be fundraising for Childreach International Charity!

PARTY BAGS!

Cheap alcohol // Amazing bands!]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[6615]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Holbeck Working Men's Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[8143]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Dearly Noted]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[28 Mar 2014 8:00pm - 11:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10103.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10103.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9298]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Film With Live Score: New Babylon]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Shostakovish had a born dramatist's sense... The New Babylon score is full of moments in which the music directly, unambiguously accompanies the screen' NY Times
Trauberg and Kozintsev's great masterpiece of Soviet avant-garde cinema is a powerful story of the 1871 Paris commune told through the eyes of a shop-girl working in the New Babylon emporium.

Scored by the then 23 year old Dmitri Shostakovich, the film is accompanied live by the Orchestra of Opera North. Bursting with jazz and cabaret inspired music, this is Shostakovich at his most satirical. Together, the film and music reflect both on revolutionary Russia and the enduring Russian fascination with Paris.

Film courtesy of European Film Philharmonic Institute.
Music courtesy of Sikorski Musikverlage
Dir.Trauberg and Kozintsev; USSR; 1929; 96 mins]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1026]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4191]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[29 Mar 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9298.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9298.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9332]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Standing In Line]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Presented by Blaize with Hommel Arts.

Through song, poetry and narration, Standing In Line tells the story of the Great War, but specifically about Albert Scrimshaw, Lester Simpson's great uncle, who died at Passendale. Originally commissioned by 'Peace Concerts Passendale', it was premiered in Passendale Church, Belgium in 2003. The performance is centred around Lester's songs though includes songs from the time. The narration includes poems of Wilfred Owen, Siegfried Sassoon and Rudyard Kipling and is accompanied by a series of projected images.  Written by Lester Simpson and Piet Chielans]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2142]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Otley Courthouse]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[6542]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Otley Word Feast]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[29 Mar 2014 7:30pm - 9:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9332.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9332.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9768]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Madame Lucinda's Wonder Show]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[This show is for anyone who ever had a dream. Lose yourself in the thrilling world of spectacle and the macabre and wake up with fresh eyes.

Ever dreamt of running away with the circus?

With moments of high pathos, circus spectacle and powerful narrative Rogue Theatre tells the stories of three lost souls who sign up to run away with Madame Lucinda, mother, father, devil, angel, alter ego and ring master.

The show mixes the bright lights of the circus with moments of intimacy, to tell the stories of each of the characters and how they ended up at their crossroads where Madame Lucinda found them. As the play unfolds, the audience shares the secret moments between characters backstage, alone in the dressing rooms, gaining insight into their dreams, fears and heartache: 

Sirus, formerly Mr Johnson, the frustrated office clerk who lived in his imagination but failed to see the subtle beauty of the world around him

LoLo, circus orphan, whose father was killed in a tragically comic circus accident involving a flying pig

Svetlana, the dancing doll, destined to live a half-life with a broken heart trapped inside her wooden exterior.

With live music by the original musical director Ben Sutcliffe, mesmerising vocals, poetry and text by Annamaria Murphy (Kneehigh Theatre (Trystan and Yseult and Red Shoes), Radio 4, National Theatre), illusion, magic, side splitting comedy, ballet, whip cracking, explosive physical performance and powerful narrative.

Journey through the doors of the imagination into a world of mystery, spectacle and horror!

Marvel at the exquisite heartache, the torturous hilarity and breathtaking magic.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2119]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Holbeck Underground Ballroom (HUB)]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[29 Mar 2014 7:30pm - 9:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9768.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9768.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10177]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Black Moth]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[plus guest supports... Antlered Man and The Witch Hunt.

Black Moth are Harriet Bevan - vocals, Jim Swainston - guitar, Nico Carew - guitar, Dave Vachon - bass, and Dom McCready plays drums.

Formed in 2010 out of the ashes of a Leeds-based garage rock band, the band were seduced by the brutal and hypnotic lure of the riff, to emerge translucent skinned and bleary eyed from their cocoon as the ferocious kick-ass heavy rock outfit that is Black Moth.

Taking a powerful chunk of influence from proto-punk acts such as Iggy and the Stooges, Motorhead and early Alice Cooper as well as a sliver of 90s grunge and stoner rock, Black Moth draw out the darker elements and combine them with the heaving riffs of heavy metal giants, Pentagram and Black Sabbath, with hooks so sharp you could hang a corpse on them. They also look to more current acts such as the Melvins, Sleep and Electric Wizard for inspiration, though singer, Harriet Bevan, still maintains a vocal style that evokes the haunting psychedelia of Grace Slick and psych-Satanist, Jinx Dawson from Coven: the woman responsible for the "sign of the horns" in rock'n'roll.

Songs that the band have honed and crafted in the mighty maelstrom that is the Leeds heavy rock scene, have been rippin' 'em up live not only in Yorkshire but everywhere they've played. Now all they needed was to be brought to vivid screaming life on record.

Enter Mr Jim Sclavunos, the multi talented Grinderman and Bad Seed, not to mention the superbaaad connoisseur of the mixing console, fresh from producing the storming second Jim Jones Revue album.

One of their shows was all it took. "Black Moth reminds me of my misspent youth" he said.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1529]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Brudenell Social Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4204]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Brudenell Social Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[29 Mar 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10177.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10177.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10396]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Salsa Celtica]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[PLUS UK'S PREMIER SALSA DJS AND CALLE OCHO RESIDENTS LUBI, FABIO BAHIA AND DR SALSA

Salsa Celtica formed in the mid-1990s in Edinburgh and play a unique blend of Puerto Rican/Cuban salsa with traditional Scottish music. Brass and Latin percussion meets fiddles, banjo and bagpipes! They have become international stars on the world music scene, releasing  5 albums in the last 15 years. Number 6 "The Tall Islands" drops February 2014 just after they return from a Colombian tour. First Leeds gig in over 3 years!]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[9073]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Belgrave Music Hall and Canteen]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[9660]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Belgrave Music Hall]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[29 Mar 2014 9:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10396.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10396.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9482]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Seven Jazz Spring Cafe]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Much copied but never bettered! Our Seven Jazz spring jam session - come and play or just enjoy the fun!

]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[849]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Seven Arts Centre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1352]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Seven Jazz at Seven Arts Leeds]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[30 Mar 2014 1:00pm - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9482.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9482.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9728]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Passion Of Christ]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The Cantata The Passion of Christ was composed by Lake-District born composer Sir Arthur Somervell's exactly a century ago in 1914. The Passion follows very much in the traditions of Stainer [The Crucifixion of 1887] and Maunder [Olivet to Calvary of 1904]. 

The passion narrative unfolds mainly in recitative drawn from Gospel texts, while solo arias and "choral meditations", with words probably by Somervell himself, reflect on the action. As in the Stainer and Maunder pieces, there are hymns for all to sing. Somervell's music is throughout reflective and beautiful and at times exquisite.

"It is, truly, a forgotten masterpiece," said conductor Dr Simon Lindley, "I remember obtaining a copy some years ago from a colleague who was organist of Holy Trinity Church in Boar Lane, and have been wanting for decades to give the piece an airing. The centenary year of its first performance provides us with an excellent opportunity!"]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4897]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Minster]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[6327]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[St Peter's Singers]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[30 Mar 2014 6:30pm - 8:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9728.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9728.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9250]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Jack Bruce & His Big Brass Band]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Composer, singer and multi-instrumentalist Jack Bruce is best known as a member of Cream. The 1960s power trio sold 35,000,000 albums and were awarded the first ever platinum disc for Wheels of Fire. Jack was inducted into the Rock & Roll Hall of Fame as a member of Cream, and has been honoured with the Bass Player Lifetime Achievement Award.  In 2006 Cream were awarded a special Recording Academy Lifetime Achievement Award at the Grammy Awards.
 
Jack has also fronted many of his own bands and recorded numerous solo albums. He has also worked as session man with the likes of Lou Reed (Berlin) and Frank Zappa, with whom Jack co-wrote Apostrophe, which became Frank's biggest selling album. Jack is releasing an album of original material in Spring 2014; this studio album will be supported by a UK and US tour.
 
Jack Bruce will be supported by Nick Lowe, who is best known for his songs Cruel to Be Kind and I Love the Sound of Breaking Glass (a top 10 UK hit). Nick has also worked as a producer with artists such as Elvis Costello and Graham Parker. Lowe also wrote (What's So Funny 'Bout) Peace, Love, and Understanding, a hit for Costello. In his current 'second act' as a singer-songwriter Nick has produced a number of albums.
 
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[394]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Grand Theatre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1224]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Grand Theatre]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[30 Mar 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9250.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9250.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10372]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Men]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[After spending much of 2011 and 2012 on the road, including a trip upstate to write and record New Moon, their fourth full-length in as many years, The Men needed a break. They decided to take the winter of 2012 off to work on new material in Brooklyn. The converted founding member Mark Perro's bedroom in Bushwick into a practice space and rehearsed there nearly every day for three months, cutting more than 40 demos. By the end of that winter, the Men had pared that crop of songs down to 13. With their plans to take a break foiled by their own work ethic, they decided to record those songs before New Moon came out. They booked two days at Brooklyn's Strange Weather studios, clocked in, and tracked all 13 songs entirely live, even including a horn section.

Eight songs from those sessions made the final cut for The Men's new LP, Tomorrow's Hits. This is their first album recorded in a high-end studio and, appropriately, the result is their most high fidelity album to date. That being said, it is still an incredibly straightforward record. Tomorrow's Hits is a concise collection of songs that nonetheless expands the band's ever-evolving musical palette. It's full of genre-bending risks, but it reinforces the overarching theme that has come to define its makers: The Men are a great rock band.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1529]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Brudenell Social Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4204]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Brudenell Social Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[30 Mar 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10372.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10372.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10178]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[La Luz]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Seattle's La Luz recorded their debut EP, Damp Face, in a small trailer on a hot August day. But barring the inevitable "no-AC-in-the-van" summer tour calamity, La Luz runs cool. 

Their brand of coolness isn't about distance or affect; it's a mood, and-sue me, but I'm about to totally rip off Zelda Fitzgerald: Something about this music vibrates to the dusky, dreamy smell of dying moons and shadows. So yeah, that kind of cool.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1529]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Brudenell Social Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4204]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Brudenell Social Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[31 Mar 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10178.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10178.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10057]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Leeds College Of Music Big Band]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Ben Cottrell is a composer and saxophonist currently based in Manchester. He is best known as the director of the Beats & Pieces Big Band, which has received awards at home and abroad alongside consistent critical and audience acclaim. As an arranger, Ben has worked with a variety of artists including Manchester band Everything Everything as well as Fazer, Lady Leshurr and Maverick Sabre as part of the first ever Urban Prom during the 2013 BBC Proms season.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[8991]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Venue]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[8992]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds College of Music]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[1 Apr 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10057.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10057.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9198]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[UB40]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Reggae stars UB40 have announced they will play their biggest UK tour for over three years in Spring 2014. The announcement of the tour follows the success of the band's latest Top 30 album Getting Over The Storm, which was awarded BBC Radio 2's 'Album Of The Week' accolade and received 5-star reviews from the UK's music press on its release in 2013.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1790]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[O2 Academy ]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4176]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[O2 Academy Leeds]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[3 Apr 2014 7:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9198.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9198.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10179]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Bridie Jackson & The Arbour]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Sitting "somewhere between the lushness of Norah Jones and the quirkiness of Joanna Newsom", Bridie Jackson & The Arbour's music is simultaneously beautiful, ethereal, dark and powerful.

Revealed as winners of the 2013 Glastonbury Emerging Talent Competition, they are "the kind of beguiling, affable folk band whose sound feels so natural and inviting you wonder why your first listen wasn't so much sooner".

With their sparse instrumentation, intriguing vocal harmonies, and influences as diverse as gospel, Baroque and flamenco; the Newcastle-based quartet are frequently proclaimed to be completely unique. Enchanting, spellbinding, electrifying and magical, this is a live experience to be treasured.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1529]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Brudenell Social Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4204]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Brudenell Social Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[3 Apr 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10179.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10179.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10180]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Simone Felice]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[We are delighted to announce that our beloved songwriter Simone Felice is hitting the road this Spring in support of his brand new album 'Strangers'. Set for release through Team Love Records in the UK on March 24th, his new full-length album is a ten song collection recorded in the Catskills with guest artists The Felice Brothers, Leah Siegel, and Wesley Schultz & Jeremiah Fraites of The Lumineers. Here is an effort that truly captures Simone's rare gift as a poet, song-crafter and unique visionary.

Strangers first single "Molly-O!" was greeted to much fanfare at the end of 2013, featuring as it does the additional vocal talents of Wesley Schultz & Jeremiah Fraites of The Lumineers.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1529]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Brudenell Social Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4204]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Brudenell Social Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[3 Apr 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10180.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10180.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9333]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Miranda Sykes And Rex Preston]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Miranda Sykes is well known as the "3rd member" of Show of Hands, where her richly warm vocals and intuitive rhythm on double bass have brought a wealth of respect & admiration from folk audiences across the country. Rex Preston, on mandolin, is one of the leading lights in a new wave of British bluegrass musicians, with a dexterity which is by turns sensitive & flamboyant. The material they play together draws on folk, jazz and bluegrass traditions, in a performance that makes for a rewarding and deeply engaging show]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2142]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Otley Courthouse]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7150]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Otley Courthouse]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[3 Apr 2014 8:00pm - 10:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9333.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9333.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9471]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Brandon Allen Quartet]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Feat Brandon Allen-tenor sax, Ross Stanley- piano Mick Hutton- bass Chris Higginbottom-drums
Evening concert series @Seven Arts 8-11pm &pound;16/14 conc

Brandon's 2012 gig at Seven Arts was a tenor/trumpet/organ/drums affair. This time he returns with a new line up showcasing his exciting unashamedly emotional soaked- in- the-blues-tradition tenor style. Australian- born, London-resident, Brandon's playing is firmly in the hard bop tradition of Art Blakey and Horace Silver but he's no mere copyist.- Jack Massaryk in the Evening Standard praised his 'world-class performance, swing, invention and stunning instrumental technique.' He has a rich, powerful sound enabling him to steam through up-tempo numbers and channel tenderness through quieter ones. His new quartet features Ross Stanley on piano, the great Mick Hutton on bass and Chris Higginbottom on drums, a regular in the Ronnie Scott's All-Stars.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2558]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Seven Jazz@Seven Arts Leeds]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1352]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Seven Jazz at Seven Arts Leeds]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[3 Apr 2014 8:00pm - 11:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9471_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9471_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9669]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Don Black: From Hackney To Hollywood]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[An evening celebrating the life of one of our most versatile lyricists, the stories behind the songs and Don Black's journey from Hackney to Hollywood.

Special guest Gary Wilmot with further special guests to be announced.

Don Black is one of Britain's most successful and versatile lyricists. Songs like Born Free, Diamonds are Forever and musicals like Sunset Boulevard, Billy and Aspects of Love have helped define popular culture. He has written many of the greatest and most instantly recognizable songs of the last 50 years (including many James Bond themes) and his worldwide success has taken him from his roots in Hackney all the way to Hollywood.

The show pays tribute to Don's career, his journey from Hackney to Hollywood and tells the stories behind the songs with special guest artists performing some of his best loved songs.

In a career that has won him many glittering prizes (an Oscar for his song Born Free, five Academy Award nominations, four Broadway Tony Nominations and two Tony awards, a Golden Globe, six Ivor Novello Awards and many platinum, gold and silver discs), he has worked with some of the world's leading composers - Andrew Lloyd Webber, Jule Styne, Henry Mancini, Quincy Jones, Elmer Bernstein, Michel Legrand, Marvin Hamlisch, Charles Aznavour, A.R. Rahman, Ennio Morricone. 

Actor and singer Gary Wilmot, star of both stage and screen, has been announced as the first special guest artist to perform and to take to the stage for A Life In Song - Lyrics By Don Black concert series, From Hackney To Hollywood.

Wilmot, known for his performances in the West End productions of Oliver!, The Wizard Of Oz and Chicago, is known to millions as a TV favourite appearing on cult shows such as Showstoppers.

Having already performed and paid tribute to Black at the Royal Festival Hall premiere of A Life In Song - Lyrics By Don Black - Wilmot will bring his unique interpretation to some of Black's most famous and iconic songs, marking his 50th anniversary in the business to the backdrop of an orchestra, whilst also taking a narrative role telling the story of one of our greatest ever lyricists.

In 2007 Black was inducted into the Songwriters Hall Of Fame.

Programme to include:
Born Free
The Italian Job
Diamonds Are Forever
To Sir With Love
Ben
True Grit
Sunset Boulevard
Thunderball
Dances With Wolves
Aspect of Love
The Man With The Golden Gun
Tell Me On A Sunday
Bombay Dreams
The World Is Not Enough
Downton Abbey
Tomorrow Never Dies
Dances With Wolves
Pink Panther Strikes Again
Out of Africa
As If We Never Said Goodbye
With One Look
Love Changes Everything
Take That Look Off Your Face
Walk Away
If I Never Sing Another Song

 ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[313]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Town Hall]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[801]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds International Concert Season]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[4 Apr 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9669_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9669_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9902]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The New Mastersounds]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Since they formed in Leeds in 1999 The New Mastersounds have spread their wings and earned themselves a healthy following across the Pond but they tend to return once a year to play in their home town. This time they're back to launch a new album, "Therapy" (their ninth studio record!)

"The New Mastersounds, from the Yorkshire city of Leeds, are part of a vast British network tied together through their love of classic American R&B, funk and souljazz. What sets The New Mastersounds apart is their expertise: the keyboard-driven collective comes on like a juiced-up, highly kinetic New Orleans version of Booker T & the MGs and their jazzy style has earned them praise from their idols - Maceo Parker, The Neville Brothers, the JBs and The Meters among others." (Nick Dedina, Google Magnifier)]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1529]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Brudenell Social Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4204]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Brudenell Social Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[4 Apr 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9902.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9902.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[8877]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Lucy Ward Band, With Atlum Schema]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Making her third appearance at Live At All Hallows, but her first with a full band, is Derby songstress Lucy Ward. 

Performing both self-penned and traditional material, she won the Horizon Award at the 2012 BBC Radio 2 Folk Awards. Lucy's sophomore album "Single Flame" is LAAH founder Steve Thackray's album of 2013, and has garnered rave reviews, but it's her live performances that have made her one of the hottest acts in Britfolk, and why we're very excited to have her playing for us once more.

http://www.lucywardsings.com/

For her April 14 tour she has recruited a stellar collection of musicians for her band: O'Hooley and Tidow, Joy Gravestock (Orchestral fiddler), Sam Pegg (bassist) & Steve Maclachlan from The Willows on percussion.

Support comes from Atlum Schema: aka Andy Mort. Described as "electro-political folk" by the Guardian, Andy's another Live At All Hallows team favourite. His new album Year 0 is out in March 14, about which he says "Year 0 came together over just two weeks in the summer of 2013. It confronts themes of loss, the frailty of the human body, the potential strength of human spirit and the absurd attention and importance we collectively give to futile things. Initially intended as a stripped back, acoustic record, it grew through the recording process into an ambient spirited, reflective, electronic exploration of the human condition. It is about discovering in the past the inescapable clues to the mysteries of the future, and the idea that every moment that passes by is another opportunity to weave something new."

http://www.atlumschema.com/

Listen here http://music.sheepdressedlikewolves.com/

'F*** ME!! Passionate, gorgeous epic songwriting: a MAJOR new talent' - Tom Robinson (BBC 6 Music) 

'Atmospheric, sweeping soundscapes and haunting lyrics, fine contemporary music, we can't recommend it enough.' - Elegant Savages Magazine

'Andy's daring and innovative approach to creating and releasing modern music has proved him and his alter-ego Atlum Schema to be a bright beacon in the depths of British music today - watch out.' - Bearded Magazine]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1560]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[All Hallows Church]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1559]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Live At All Hallows]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[4 Apr 2014 7:45pm - 11:15pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/8877_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/8877_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9278]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Bill Frisell Trio]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Beautiful Dreamers

'Compelling, emotionally resonant, genrefree music... maybe Frisell deserves his own genre. How about 'friz'?' Financial Times

With 25 seminal albums and over 200 recordings, guitarist, composer, and bandleader Bill Frisell has firmly established himself as a visionary presence in American music. His trio plays music from his Beautiful Dreamers album, which traverses a broad terrain of American music, ranging from the visceral blues of Blind Willie Johnson's 'Nobody's Fault' to the iconic title track.

His trio is completed by viola player Eyvind Kang and Rudy Royston on drums, and together they create a sound characterised by its intimacy, quiet joy and constant sense of discovery.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1026]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4191]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[5 Apr 2014 7:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9278.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9278.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9478]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Laura Jurd Quartet]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Laura Jurd trumpet, Elliot Galvin on piano, Conor Chaplin on electric bass and Corrie Dick on drums. 

The Laura Jurd Quartet is an intriguing, creative outfit featuring Elliot Galvin on piano, Conor Chaplin on electric bass and Corrie Dick on drums. Drawing  upon original compositions and traditional melodies as a basis for improvisation, this classic quartet line-up fuses elements of European folk, jazz and classical traditions, creating a unique and distinctive sound world. Whether rocking out full steam or exploring captivating moments of stillness, this ensemble is sure to put a smile on your face.
 
"Jurd stretched critics and musicians' repertoire of superlatives with this sophisticated and technically awesome - session...delivered with the assurance of a budding trumpet original"
John Fordham, The Guardian
Tickets http://sevenjazzleeds.ticketsource.co.uk/
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1614]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Inkwell]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7935]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Seven Jazz Leeds]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[6 Apr 2014 1:00pm - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9478.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9478.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9806]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Solid Silver 60s]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Celebrating 29 years of the UK's original and premier 60s show

They say that if you remember the 60s you weren't there! Fill that gap in your memory with The Solid Silver 60s Show and relive the 60s with original artists singing their greatest hits!
 
Now in its 29th year the show reunites Brian Poole and The Tremeloes and features the unforgettable talents of Chris Farlowe, Chris Montez and Wayne Fontana , all backed by Vanity Fare .
 
HEAR THE CLASSIC HITS
 
PERFORMED BY THE ORIGINAL HITMAKERS!
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[394]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Grand Theatre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1224]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Grand Theatre]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[6 Apr 2014 ]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9806.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9806.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10181]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Matt Berry]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[& The Maypoles. Support from Pugwash.

"Equal Parts serious, beautiful, english and charming" - Josh Homme

"Like a good ale or a good friend 'Kill The Wolf' is a joy to spend time with" - The Times 4/5

Matt Berry is an English actor, writer, comedian and musician, best known for his appearances in The IT Crowd, Garth Marenghi's Darkplace, The Mighty Boosh, and Snuff Box.

As a musician, Berry composed all the music for Snuff Box as well the music for AD/BC: A Rock Opera, which he co-wrote with Richard Ayoade. AD/BC was broadcast in December 2004 and featured Fulcher and Mighty Boosh stars Julian Barratt and Noel Fielding. He also performed a song for an episode of Garth Marenghi's Darkplace entitled "One Track Lover", a spoof of cheesy romantic 80s songs. He also composed music for the BBC 2 Steve Coogan comedy Saxondale and appeared in the first and third episodes of the second series of the show.

Berry has released FOUR albums: Jackpot in 1995, Opium which was a limited edition self-released record in 2008 and Witchazel in 2009 as a download, later released on CD and vinyl by Acid Jazz Records in 2011, and in 2013 'Kill The Wolf'.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1529]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Brudenell Social Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4204]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Brudenell Social Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[6 Apr 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10181.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10181.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10182]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[True Widow]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[plus guest support... Broken DC.

On True Widow's highly anticipated third album 'Circumambulation', the Dallas heavy 'stonegaze' trio hone in on their trademark syrupy simplicity with absolute perfection. Equal parts drone, post-rock and shoegaze, 'Circumambaulation' is the band's most, controlled, concise and realized effort yet. Simultaneously True Widow's darkest and poppiest record, 'Circumambaulation' is a moody triumph of a record perfect for both super late nights, and early Sunday mornings. Rarely does a band capture the vibe of dreary haze together with sticky male/female harmonies so infectiously.

True Widow's 'Circumambulation' is an easy top contender for record of summer, if not all of 2013.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1529]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Brudenell Social Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4204]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Brudenell Social Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[7 Apr 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10182.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10182.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9294]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Hilary Mantel]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Shaking hands with Satan

'Mantel... instinctively grabs for the reachably real' The New Yorker

From rumours that Anne Boleyn sold her soul for her crown to the Faustian pacts of the technology age, Hilary Mantel investigates the history of the human relationship with the devil.

The double Man Booker Prize-winning author (Wolf Hall, Bring up the Bodies) says that whilst growing up, the devil was a vital presence in her own life and so it was only natural that he should feature in her novels. In this specially commissioned talk, she traces the footsteps of the devil in her life, her fiction and in today's world.

This talk has been rescheduled from Autumn 2012 and includes live music from violinist David le Page.

Commissioned by Opera North Projects]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1026]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4191]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[7 Apr 2014 7:45pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9294.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9294.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10183]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Marc O'Reilly]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Irish folk/blues troubadour Marc O'Reilly will release his new album 'Human Herdings' on 28th March'14.

Following the release of his critically acclaimed debut album 'My Friend Marx' in 2011, Marc O'Reilly has established himself as one of the most exciting artists within the folk/blues genre gaining comparisons with artists such as John Martyn and Bon Iver.

2013 saw Marc tour all over Europe including appearances at major festivals like Glastonbury, Electric Picnic and Boardmasters and squeezing in a trip to the US to appear at the Live in the Vineyard Festival in Napa, California.

His alter-ego side project with his brother Pierre, the electro-pop duo 'R', recently receieved excellent radio support for their debut single 'Change' from tastemakers such as Steve Lamacq (BBC 6music), Janice Long (BBC Radio 2) and Paul Mcloone (Today FM).

As if that wasn't enough to keep him busy, Marc has also provided vocals on 3 tracks for the new album by MOBO winning act Karios 4tet which was recorded at Peter Gabriel's Real World Studios, has received 4 star reviews from Mojo, The Independent and Guardian and has led to the recording of a live BBC Maida Vale session for the Jamie Cullum Show on Radio 2.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1529]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Brudenell Social Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4204]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Brudenell Social Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[9 Apr 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10183.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10183.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10186]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Jesca Hoop]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Jesca Hoop has lived all over the map, and her rich life experience is reflected in her distinctive voice and natural gift for inventive song craft.

Hoop learned to sing at an early age, harmonising with her musical Mormon family in northern California. She began writing highly idiosyncratic songs at the age of 14 to keep her company on her long walks to school. At 16, Hoop broke away from her strict upbringing and began what she calls her 'life as a racoon', off the grid & close to nature. Rambling through the high mountain deserts of the Southwest and along the coastlines of the Northwest, she worked as a wilderness survival guide and chalked up skills in farming, surveying, and carpentry. Her songwriting continued throughout, shared on porches, in deep river canyons and around campfires.

In 2004 the desire to share these songs on a broader scale set in. She settled in Los Angeles, where she honed her songwriting craft and developed a reputation as a unique and beguiling live performer of real substance. Though she now resides in Manchester, England, Hoop returned to Los Angeles to record her third album, The House That Jack Built.

Jesca has quite the growing collection of fans in high places: Tom Waits described her music as being "like a four sided coin. She is an old soul, like a black pearl, a good witch or red moon. Her music is like going swimming in a lake at night". Peter Gabriel took her to South America to sing with him, and in recent years she has been hand picked to play as support on tour for Eels, Andrew Bird, Punch Brothers and Elbow: Elbow's Guy Garvey even had her do a stint as guest presenter on his BBC radio show in early 2012, to great reception.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1529]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Brudenell Social Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4204]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Brudenell Social Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[10 Apr 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10186.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10186.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9300]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Pascal And Ami Roge]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Debussy & Ravel's music for four hands

'Spellbinding' The Sunday Telegraph

The Roges are dedicated ambassadors for French music. They have played across the world, sharing their love of Debussy, Ravel and the other great Gallic pioneers, and they continue to arrange French orchestral music for the special possibilities of four hands.

As Opera North prepares to open La Boheme, a vision of Paris dreamed by an Italian, this is the perfect moment to immerse ourselves in the music of the great French Impressionist composers.

The Roge's stunning rendition will include Ravel's Rhapsodie Espagnole and Sonatine, while Debussy's La Mer concludes our French evening.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1026]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4191]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[10 Apr 2014 7:45pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9300.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9300.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9472]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Tommy Smith And Brian Kellock]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Seven Arts is a lovely venue for small intimate music and so we are really looking forward to a sax and piano combination featuring two of Scotland's most famous jazz artists, saxophonist Tommy Smith and pianist Brian Kellock who will be teaming up to bring you a beautiful and imaginative jazz. They have had lots of positive press with phrases such as 'Bewitching layers of delicacy', full flight, spontaneous invention' 'sheer artistry'. They will be performing tracks from their two CDs on Spartacus records, 'Bezique' and 'Symbiosis' which feature tunes from the great American song book. 
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2558]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Seven Jazz@Seven Arts Leeds]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1352]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Seven Jazz at Seven Arts Leeds]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[10 Apr 2014 8:00pm - 11:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9472.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9472.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[8920]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Fureys]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Legends of Irish music & song The FUREYS & Davey Arthur, renowned for their hit songs 'I will love you', 'When you were sweet 16', 'The Green fields of France', 'The old man', 'Red rose cafe', 'From Clare to here', 'Her father didn't like me anyway', 'Leaving Nancy', 'Steal away' etc will make their 7th appearance here on Friday 11th April 2014. 
 
The FUREYS & Davey Arthur have been entertaining audiences worldwide for 36 years, audiences that have included former Australian Prime Minister John Howard, Former Irish President Mary McAleese and the late Pope John Paul while Tony Blair has publicly stated his favourite peace song of all time is the FUREYS "Green Fields of France". Recently Ireland President Michael D Higgins attended their concert in Dublin's National Concert Hall.
 
They are responsible for some of the most stirring music ever to capture the public imagination. Their folk / middle of the road based songs and music has received standing ovations in some of the biggest concert halls in the world. Their emotive songs stir many emotions....tears and laughter, sadness and joy. 
 
A FUREYS concert is always a night to remember.  
 
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1043]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1252]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[11 Apr 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/8920.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/8920.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10184]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Cud Playing... 'When In Rome, Kill Me']]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Emerging from the same art/design cauldron that produced fellow Leeds legends Soft Cell, Scritti Politti, and The Mekons, CUD were the pre-Britpop answer to doleful shoegazing bands - fun-loving, light-hearted, romantic and downright catchy.

Alternatively loved or loathed like a yeast extract, CUD are indie rock for the unpretentious pleasure seeker, boasting as they do the rich deep-lunged voice of Carl Puttnam, edgy guitars of Mike Dunphy and tight, funky rhythm section of William Potter, bass and Gogs Byrn, drums.

CUD were initially lauded for their quirky Peel session cover of 'You Sexy Thing' in 1987. They soon built up a huge live following and buffed up their repertoire with a string of unstraight pop beauties, best exemplified by the 1990 album 'Leggy Mambo'. This led to a major-label deal with A&M in 1991, front-page NME coverage, massive sellout gigs and proper Top 30 hits, 'Rich and Strange' and 'Purple Love Balloon'.

Misunderstood by record companies and press, CUD packed away their guitars and sticks in 1995 but, bolstered by a greatest hits anthology ('Rich and Strange') in 2006, they agreed to tread the boards again and found an army of 'Space CUDets' still eager to sing along, dance like fruitcakes and invade their stage.

In 2012, CUD reunited with their original guitarist and key songwriter, Mike Dunphy, and the result is their first new material in 18 years, the perky 7" and download single 'Louise' b/w 'Mexico'.

To top this, CUD are playing two of their most popular albums in their entirety over two spring nights in Leeds.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1529]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Brudenell Social Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4204]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Brudenell Social Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[11 Apr 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10184.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10184.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10397]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Paul Thomas Saunders]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[With influences such as Joe Meek and Leonard Cohen, Paul Thomas Saunders encapsulates both the psychedelic soundscape and intellectual sentimentality that the sixties graced us with, then wraps it up in a spiraling contemporary shell]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[9073]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Belgrave Music Hall and Canteen]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[9660]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Belgrave Music Hall]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[11 Apr 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10397.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10397.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9280]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Sam Amidon]]></event_title><description><![CDATA['A folk singer cast from an oldfashioned mould, Sam Amidon rearranges and repurposes songs from the ages' The Skinny
Sam Amidon has been recording for a decade and playing music for twenty years before that. Raised in Vermont he has collaborated with Beth Orton, toured with New York pianist Thomas Barlett (aka Doveman) and embarked on a series of live shows with guitarist Bill Frisell.

His album Bright Sunny South, which he describes as a 'lonesome record', is packed with classic folk songs, country ballads and shape-note hymns. A fearless singer and multi-instrumentalist, he also takes on pop hits, challenging what folk can be. First heard at the Howard Assembly Room supporting Nina Nastasia in 2011, we are delighted to welcome him back with his own show.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1026]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4191]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[11 Apr 2014 7:45pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9280.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9280.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10139]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Good Guys Orchestra:  In A Sentimental Mood]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[An evening of some of the greatest songs ever written by Cole Porter, George Gershwin and Duke Ellington. The show features 'Good Guys' vocalist Guy Garrett with one of the UK's top female vocalists, Leeds' own Cherie Gears, backed by the amazing 10-piece version of The Good Guys Orchestra. The evening includes classic songs such as Every Time We Say Goodbye, Don't Get Around Much Anymore, Someone To Watch Over Me, Night And Day and many more favourites.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1043]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1252]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[12 Apr 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10139.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10139.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10185]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Cud Playing... 'Leggy Mambo']]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Emerging from the same art/design cauldron that produced fellow Leeds legends Soft Cell, Scritti Politti, and The Mekons, CUD were the pre-Britpop answer to doleful shoegazing bands - fun-loving, light-hearted, romantic and downright catchy.

Alternatively loved or loathed like a yeast extract, CUD are indie rock for the unpretentious pleasure seeker, boasting as they do the rich deep-lunged voice of Carl Puttnam, edgy guitars of Mike Dunphy and tight, funky rhythm section of William Potter, bass and Gogs Byrn, drums.

CUD were initially lauded for their quirky Peel session cover of 'You Sexy Thing' in 1987. They soon built up a huge live following and buffed up their repertoire with a string of unstraight pop beauties, best exemplified by the 1990 album 'Leggy Mambo'. This led to a major-label deal with A&M in 1991, front-page NME coverage, massive sellout gigs and proper Top 30 hits, 'Rich and Strange' and 'Purple Love Balloon'.

Misunderstood by record companies and press, CUD packed away their guitars and sticks in 1995 but, bolstered by a greatest hits anthology ('Rich and Strange') in 2006, they agreed to tread the boards again and found an army of 'Space CUDets' still eager to sing along, dance like fruitcakes and invade their stage.

In 2012, CUD reunited with their original guitarist and key songwriter, Mike Dunphy, and the result is their first new material in 18 years, the perky 7" and download single 'Louise' b/w 'Mexico'.

To top this, CUD are playing two of their most popular albums in their entirety over two spring nights in Leeds.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1529]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Brudenell Social Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4204]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Brudenell Social Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[12 Apr 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10185.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10185.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9481]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Ben Lowman's "Django" project]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Ben Lowman - Tenor Sax, Jonny Faull - Soprano Sax, Andy Cox - Alto Sax, Sam Houghton - Bari Sax, Aron Kyne  - Accordion, Ben Danzig - Guitar, Jamie Taylor - Guitar, Sam Vicary - Upright Bass, Matt Davies - Kit.

Contemporary swing and "hot club" jazz from this mini big band of young Leeds musicians


]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1614]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Inkwell]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1352]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Seven Jazz at Seven Arts Leeds]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Apr 2014 1:00pm - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9481.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9481.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10211]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Forde / Knudsen Quartet]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The White Cloth Gallery plays host to the outstanding Forde/Knudsen Quartet. 

The quartet, consisting of Declan Forde (piano), Kenneth Dahl Knudsen (double bass), Will Howard (tenor sax) and Jay Davis (drums) represents a modern and innovative approach to a jazz quartet.This will be a great afternoon of live, stimulating and refreshing jazz by some of the genre's most exciting up and coming artists. ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1544]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[White Cloth Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10210]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Yorkshire Live Music Project]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Apr 2014 2:00pm - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10211_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10211_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9670]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Inspiration And The Orchestra Of Opera North: Show People]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[There's a special kind of people known as... Show People, and Inspiration show you how it's done.

The massed voices present the culmination of their exploration of the world of musical theatre, with epic medleys from Disney's The Lion King, The Hunchback of Notre Dame and many more of your favourite show tunes.

www.inspirationuk.com]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[313]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Town Hall]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[801]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds International Concert Season]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Apr 2014 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9670.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9670.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9409]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Chas & Dave ]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Following on from the release of their brand new album That's What Happens on Warner Brothers Records and their headlining performance at The Royal Variety Show 2013, Chas & Dave will be appearing at Leeds Grand Theatre next year.

 Chas & Dave began writing and performing songs together in 1972, having been friends since the early sixties. They are now celebrating their 50th Anniversary by recording their first original album in 27 years - a mixture of vintage rock & roll songs and new renditions of their own rockney classics. The album also features special guest stars such as Jools Holland and Hugh Laurie.

They reached the top twenty in 1979 with Gertcha, which became a nationwide catchphrase. This was followed by Rabbit, which reached No. 8 in the charts, and a No. 2 record Ain't No Pleasing You in 1982. In 1986 they had a top six record with Snooker Loopy.
 
They have also written title songs for TV shows Till Death Do Us Part and Only Fools & Horses.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[394]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Grand Theatre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1224]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Grand Theatre]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Apr 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9409.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9409.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9369]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Feast Of Fiddles]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[2014 marks the 21st year this group of musical friends have taken to the road to entertain their growing legion of fans with a show of huge dynamic range, passionate and joyful playing and a liberal dose of fun. What started as a daft idea for a folk club night has grown into a folk-rock institution with six CDs to their name, several festival appearances and sell out shows up and down the UK. 

Fiddlers Peter Knight (Steeleye Span), Chris Leslie (Fairport Convention), Phil Beer (Show of Hands), Brian McNeill (Battlefield Band), Ian Cutler (Bully Wee), Tom Leary (Zeus) and Garry Blakeley (Band of Two) add the large range of fiddle playing styles to the rock back-line of guitars, keyboards, sax and accordion - all held together by legendary drummer Dave Mattacks. It's a feast by nature and a feast by name which is guaranteed to be enjoyed even by the most doubting of friends dragged along! Be prepared for laughter, tears, dancing and an all round evening of fabulously entertaining live music guaranteed!
 
"Feast of Fiddles cranked up the tempo over the last two numbers and worked the audience into a frenzy, resulting in vigorous clapping and stomping of feet" - Mark Salter, Lowdham Press

"Absolutely awesome!" - Sue Marchant, BBC East
"The best fiddle players of a generation" - fRoots 
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1043]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1252]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[14 Apr 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9369.JPG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9369.JPG]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10187]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Mike Watt & The Missingmen]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Mike Watt is the legendary singer-songwriter and bass guitarist, best-known for co-founding the seminal punk rock bands Minutemen and fIREHOSE; as of 2003, he is also the bassist for the reunited Iggy Pop & The Stooges, and a member of the art rock/jazz/punk/improv group Banyan, the bass guitar duo Dos and the magnificent Il Sogno del Mariano.

Watt is often cited as a key figure in the development of American alternative rock; The Red Hot Chili Peppers dedicated their hugely successful Blood Sugar Sex Magik to Watt. Throughout his career he has been known for his inventive, melodic playing; and thoroughly distinctive basslines.

Watt is a cultural omnivore. Especially over the last decade, his openness (and eagerness) to devour new musical experience has become increasingly audible (and visible) in the dozens of projects and live performances he's participated in with artists as divergent as Yoko Ono, Black Moth Super Rainbow, Petra Haden, Kelly Clarkson, Thurston Moore, Porno For Pyros, Nels Cline, Stephen Hodges (Tom Waits), J Mascis, Tony Maimone (Pere Ubu), Yuko Araki and Hirotaka 'Shimmy' Shimizu (Cornelius), Dougie Bowne (Lounge Lizards) and many more.

As always, Watt persists in exceeding, defying and confounding musical (and other) expectations: the truly romantic embodiment of an authentic punk rocker.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1529]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Brudenell Social Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4204]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Brudenell Social Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[16 Apr 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10187.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10187.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10188]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Northside]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Northside followed the Hacienda heyday in 1991 with the release of their acclaimed UK Top 20 album 'Chicken Rhythms' on Factory Records. Despite being banned from daytime radio due to numerous drug references in their lyrics, the band still managed to recruit a large and loyal following.

Influenced by reggae, punk, and psychedelia, the band were invited to open the first night of the Great British Music Weekend in January 1991 at Wembley Arena, broadcast live over three nights on Radio One. Despite pleas from the station not to play their first single, Shall We Take A Trip? the band started with this number, causing the station to stop its live broadcast for several minutes. Opening for The Happy Mondays and The La's at Elland Road in Leeds on 1st June 1991, they were named by many, including the music monthlies, as the highlight of the day.

Now back together again the four original members of Northside (Paul Walsh - Drums, Tim Walsh- Guitar, Cliff Ogier - Bass and Warren Dermody - Vocals/Lyrics) have big plans for next year! For the first time in nearly twenty years, the band are rehearsing for a UK tour, festivals and overseas dates in 2014.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1529]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Brudenell Social Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4204]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Brudenell Social Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[17 Apr 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10188.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10188.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9737]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Good Friday Concert: Bach Mass In B Minor]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[St. Peter's Singers' traditional Good Friday concert in the choir's thirty-fifth anniversary year will be a performance of J.S.Bach's monumental B minor Mass. The acclaimed Leeds based chamber choir presents the work - one of the supreme achievements in classical music - in Leeds Minster on Friday 18 April 2014 at 7.00 pm. 

The Singers first presented Bach's masterpiece here at the Minster in 1985 as part of the celebrations of the Tercentenary of the great composer's birth, and has performed the work many times since, including, memorably at Leeds Town Hall in 1991 in celebration of the 150th anniversary of the consecration of Leeds Parish Church in 1841.

Kristina James - soprano
Helen Strange - soprano
Lucy Appleyard - mezzo soprano
Chris Trenholme - tenor
Quentin Brown - bass
David Houlder - organ

National Festival Orchestra
Sally Robinson - leader

Music Director of St Peter's Singers, Dr Simon Lindley, said:
'It can be said that no single musical work is greater than Bach's Mass in B minor; the glorious sonorities of the piece include wonderful settings of the sections of the Creed dealing with the suffering, death, burial and Resurrection of Jesus, making a performance on Good Friday an especially compelling experience.'
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4897]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Minster]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[6327]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[St Peter's Singers]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[18 Apr 2014 7:00pm - 9:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9737.png]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9737.png]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10189]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[King Khan And The Shrines]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Imagine Roky Erickson backed by the Sun Ra Arkestra or Wilson Pickett and The Velvet Underground, or picture the love child of Anubis and Kali. King Khan & The Shrines is more than a psychedelic soul band with a spectacle of a stage show. They are a cult musical phenomenon with more than 10 years of international touring, multiple studio records and a fan base of fervent punk, soul, free jazz and garage rock heads.

King Khan, the spiritual guru and front man, cobbled together a fierce line-up of musicians while in Berlin in between reading Tarot cards and raising a family. What he ended up with in 1999 is one of the most entertaining groups the world has seen and heard since the days of Ike & Tina. The line-up includes Chicago-born, Ron Streeter (veteran percussionist for Curtis Mayfield, Stevie Wonder), a horn section consisting of trumpeter Simon Wojan (member of Kranky Records recording artists Cloudland Canyon), tenor sax man Torben Wesche (Germany's John Coltrane), and famous French rockabilly baritone saxophonist Frederic Brissaud. The rhythm section of the Sensational Shrines has been called a German/French version of the Freak Brothers - Till Timm on guitar, organist Frederic Bourdil, Jens Redemann on bass and drummer Mirko Wenzl.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1529]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Brudenell Social Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4204]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Brudenell Social Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[18 Apr 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10189.png]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10189.png]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9480]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Porter Quartet]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Robin Porter- Tenor Saxophone, Jonathan Brown- Guitar, Sam Vicary- Double Bass, Tom Hawthorn- Drums

Our Easter Sunday gig is a treat. Following their recent appearance at the the BBC "Proms" now here in Chapel Allerton. Robin Porter is a young sax player going places!
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1614]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Inkwell]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7935]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Seven Jazz Leeds]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[20 Apr 2014 1:00pm - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9480_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9480_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10190]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Rezillos]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Plus guest support Spizzenergi.

The Rezillos burst forth upon the rock scene in 1976, having gathered together at Edinburgh College of Art. Through a shared love of Sixties Garage Rock and the Spectoresque Girl Group glam of The Ronettes and The Shangri-Las, The Rezillos found themselves inadvertently caught up in the Punk or New Wave movement. Their debut single, "I Can't Stand My Baby", shot them to underground fame initially via airings on John Peel's radio show. Their classic singles "My Baby Does Good Sculptures", "Top of the Pops" and "Destination Venus" signalled critically acclaimed milestones for the band.

Their landmark album of 1978 "Can't Stand the Rezillos" reached the top 10 in the UK album chart. They appeared twice on the legendary Old Grey Whistle Test and hit the Top Twenty with their hit single 'Top of the Pops', a satirical swipe at the UK pop music programme of the same name. Once the band had achieved chart success it was inevitable that they should appear on the same show! They followed up that same year with a live recording, "Mission Accomplished... But the Beat Goes On", and promptly broke up to the anguish of fans and music critics alike.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1529]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Brudenell Social Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4204]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Brudenell Social Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[20 Apr 2014 7:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10190.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10190.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9370]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Eddi Reader]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Eddi Reader was brought into the limelight with Fairground Attraction and their single Perfect and parent album First of a Million Kisses which both topped the British charts.  However, it has been her subsequent solo albums which signalled her increasing ability to assimilate different musical styles and make them all very much her own.  From the traditional to the contemporary, Eddi brings to joyous life all forms of song and what sets Reader apart is the depth and quality of the emotional performance;  her ability not only to move the listener but to connect her experience to that of her audience.  Her rare blend of meltingly true vocals and towering romanticism combine with an astute and pragmatic nature to make her a unique and powerful figure in contemporary British music.  She has effortlessly developed into one of popular music's most thrilling and affecting performers.

New Album Vagabond will be released on 3 February 2014, more info @ www.eddireader.co.uk.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1043]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1252]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[21 Apr 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9370.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9370.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9279]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Rene Marie]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Voice of My Beautiful Country

'a brilliantly conceived package of Americana, focusing on folkloric material' The Wall Street Journal on Voice of My Beautiful Country
Electrifying and life-enhancing, Rene Marie draws together jazz, soul, gospel and Americana to powerful effect. With her incredible range of vocal ability, emotional resonance and strong independent streak, she brings to life original songs, jazz standards and folk songs alike.
Her music both celebrates and interrogates American culture and her position within it. With a snowballing career that began only when she was in her 40s, Rene Marie is an artist of rare honesty and commitment and one of today's most individual voices.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1026]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4191]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[23 Apr 2014 7:45pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9279.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9279.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10191]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[School Of Language]]></event_title><description><![CDATA['The Brewis brothers are the anti-Gallaghers working class Northerners who challenge you with their sharp, bright, baroque pop'. - MOJO

The new School Of Language is called Old Fears and it's set for release on Memphis Industries on 7 April 2014.

Old Fears. It's a pop record. A place of clipped falsetto, melancholic funk, iridescent electro, shimmering post-punk, futurist prog. A self-contained sphere of strange sensations. Beguiling textures. Lengthening shadows. At times it is both liminal and minimal, at others emotive and external. Ambiguous and ambient. Tantalising and tempered. Modern. Unique. And funny too. "I wrote a lot of notes and they seemed to distinctly split into things to do with love and things to do with fear," says David Brewis. "A lot of it has ended up with me looking back at when I was 19, 20 - my formative years. So though I wouldn't want to call it a concept album it's definitely themed."]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1529]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Brudenell Social Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4204]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Brudenell Social Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[26 Apr 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10191.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10191.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10398]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Crispy Ambulance]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Alan Hempsall and Robert Davenport formed Crispy Ambulance in Manchester in 1977, originally as a two-man outfit, adding two further members, Keith Darbyshire and Gary Madeley, to the line-up in the following year. With original influences acknowledged as Magazine and Hawkwind, they co-wrote nearly all of their material and developed a distinctive style that has attracted a modest but international following.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[9073]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Belgrave Music Hall and Canteen]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[9660]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Belgrave Music Hall]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[26 Apr 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10398.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10398.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9479]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Kevin James Quartet]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Kevin James - vocals/piano, Tom Riviere- bass, Al Morrison - guitar, Joe Montague- drums

Swinging vocalist and sensitive pianist makes a welcome return to Chapel Allerton.

]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2558]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Seven Jazz@Seven Arts Leeds]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1352]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Seven Jazz at Seven Arts Leeds]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[27 Apr 2014 1:00pm - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9479.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9479.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9072]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[McBusted]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[McFly and Busted join forces to make pop rock supergroup!

Following the astonishing success of their brief reunion at the Royal Albert Hall on the occasion of McFly's tenth anniversary concert, Tom Fletcher, Danny Jones, Dougie Poynter and Harry Judd will join forces with James Bourne and Matt Willis to form supergroup McBusted for a full UK arena tour.

Fans have been clamouring for the guys to take the Busted/McFly reunion to the next level and now they're going to, under the moniker McBusted! They will perform in arenas to their legions of fans across the UK who can expect a shamelessly nostalgic set full of everyone's favourite Busted and McFly hits, with a few surprise gems thrown into the mix. 

Together Busted and McFly have sold 15 million records worldwide and chalked up 14 number ones, 20 top 3 singles and 27 top ten singles. ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4063]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[first direct arena]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5131]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[first direct arena]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[30 Apr 2014 ]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9072.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9072.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10248]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Shonen Knife]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[All female Japanese legends 'Shonen knife' return with their 20th album.

Formed in Osaka 33 years ago the trio rose from humble DIY beginnings to joining Nirvana on their 'Nevermind' tour and trailblazing a path for women in music and inspiring legions of bands. Favourites of Kurt Cobain, John Peel, Thurston Moore, Marc Riley, Gideon Coe, Radcliffe & Maconie, Jonathon Ross & Dan Hegarty the band are arguably the most influential and beloved Japanese rock export.

Live, they are a tight rock machine punching out fast, highly exciting sets of Punk, Pop, Rock & Metal hits coated with a unique life affirming quirky magic that as they fast approach their 1000th gig, shows no signs of fading. As Naoko says 'Let's Rock!'

"When I finally got to see them live, I was transformed into a hysterical nine-year-old girl at a Beatles concert."Kurt Cobain

Selected Press -

Uncut: "rocks like Motorhead designed by Hanna-Barbara" 

BBC Music: "The Osaka Ramones, you must concede, still have it." 

The Independent: 8/10 "There are two types of people: those who enjoy thrashy Japanese girl-punk, and those who have something wrong with them." 

Music OMH: 8/10 "For an incredible 31 years Shonen Knife have been pumping out prototype riot grrrl, thrashing together early punk sounds with pop melodies."

The Sunday Times: "irrepressible slice of bounce-along indie-pop. Beguiling." 

Stewart Lee BBC 6Music (Steve Lamacq): "Shonen Knife - they know how to rock - Japanese punk pop at its best."]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1529]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Brudenell Social Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4204]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Brudenell Social Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[1 May 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10248.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10248.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10273]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Sebastian Mueller And Nico De Villiers]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Mozart: Violin Sonata in G major, K301
Beethoven: Violin Sonata in C minor, Op 30 No 2
Milstein: Paganiniana
Franck: Violin Sonata in A major, M8

Sebastian Mueller, Violin
Nico de Villiers, Piano]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[5551]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds College of Music]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[8992]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds College of Music]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[1 May 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10273.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10273.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10249]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Sonics]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Since the beginning of garage rock, the northwest sound, grunge, or whatever anyone calls it, The Sonics set the precedence and the pace, and the sound that gave to every musician and band that followed the inalienable right to take rock to the edge of the universe, to explore the possibilities, to get out of the rut, experiment, and to scream your guts out, that you have arrived, and to continue that thought.

The Sonics have remained the most recognized sounds ever listened to by aspiring musicians and multitudes of fans around the world.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1529]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Brudenell Social Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4204]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Brudenell Social Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[7 May 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10249.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10249.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[8878]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Plumhall Live At All Hallows, With Jonny Walker]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Plumhall have been with Live At All Hallows since the event's birth.... but only now have their first album due out, Thundercloud, and to celebrate they are touring throughout 2014

http://www.plumhall.co.uk/

Michell Plum (Waking The Witch, Chumbawamba) and Nick Hall (The Hall Brothers) "draw inspiration from very eclectic sources including Nick Lowe, Scott Walker, Ian McNabb, Guy Clark, Kate Bush, Aimee Mann, Everly Brothers, Johnny Cash & June Carter, Chumbawamba and Show of Hands - and they bring all these influences into a sound that is clearly their own, based on powerfully-played acoustic instruments, perfect harmonies and meaningful songs." (bio) 

Whatever the analysis, they're fantastic live, so we jumped at the chance of a show on the album tour. Title track Thundercloud can be heard and downloaded on Bandcamp.

Support comes from Jonny Walker, who has been on the LAAH "to book list" since Mike attended one of his Citizens' Kazoo Orchestra protests in Camden last autumn. A professional busker who has only relatively recently started playing traditional gigs whilst continuing to perform on the streets across the UK and Europe, his 2012 debut EP 'This Is Not Me' was described as "Heartfelt, unpretentious and utterly charming" by Rocksucker and Jonny himself has been called mix of Dylan, Neil Young and the enigmatic Leonard Cohen. He is a natural storyteller with lyrics that challenge the depths.

http://www.jonnywalker.co.uk/

Alongside performing Jonny is an activist, founding grassroots advocacy body ASAP! (Association of Street Artists and Performers) and has been featured on BBC and ITV news, The Guardian and extensive local publications, for his ongoing campaign to overturn local and national government policies that place arbitrary restrictions on street music and damage the cultural lives of our towns and cities. He is the Founding Director of the Keep Streets Live Campaign for public spaces that are open to grassroots music and art. In Liverpool, York and Camden he has led public opposition to council policies that stifle street culture. The Live At All Hallows team are pleased to be able to do our bit to help support this important campaign.

"A modern day Ralph McTell as his ability to tell a story with conscience" ... Liverpool Sound and Vision

Tickets &pound;5 advance, &pound;6 on the door. From eventbrite and in due course from Jumbo Records, and Leeds MusicHub]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1560]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[All Hallows Church]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1559]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Live At All Hallows]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[9 May 2014 7:45pm - 11:15pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/8878_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/8878_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9410]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Miley Cyrus]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[In the UK, Miley has dominated the charts with a #1 album and #1 singles for "We Can't Stop" and "Wrecking Ball." Bangerz also debuted at #1 on both the Billboard Top 200 Album chart and the Digital Album Charts. Additionally, during release week, Bangerz hit #1 on iTunes in over 70 countries. Both singles, "Wrecking Ball" and "We Can't Stop", off Bangerz have already sold over 8 million copies worldwide.

Miley's music video for "Wrecking Ball" became the fastest music video ever to reach CERTIFIED status, VEVO's milestone for videos delivering 100 million views in only 6 days.

Cyrus shattered the previous record which she held for "We Can't Stop," which was CERTIFIED by VEVO just 37 days after it premiered.

Bangerz has been getting rave reviews including Entertainment Weekly calling it "...utterly fresh, a pop blitz from a hip-hop blueprint, and proof that Miley won't settle for just shocking us." US Weekly declared it "the year's most titillating pop explosion" awarding the album "4 stars (out of 4)."

]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4063]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[first direct arena]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5131]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[first direct arena]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[10 May 2014 7:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9410.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9410.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10375]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Blues Band In Concert]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Featuring: Paul Jones, Dave Kelly, Rob Townsend, Gary Fletcher, Tom McGuinness

The story of how The Blues Band formed in 1979 to play the music that was their passion, just for fun and a bit of beer money, and then found themselves with whole new careers on their hands, has been well documented in countless magazine articles and record company biographies.
 
In the past 35 years the band have played all around the world in venues ranging from intimate clubs through to civic halls and theatres, and have wowed festival audiences in many countries - including headline appearances at Glastonbury.
 
The band's passion and reverence for the music, their presentation and showmanship all combine to deliver the definitive good night out.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1043]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1252]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[10 May 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10375.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10375.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10252]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Hauschka]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Inspired by innovators from John Cage to Aphex Twin, Hauschka aka Volker Bertelmann is known for compelling live performances that re-imagine the possibilities of the piano by carrying out an array of imaginative 'preparations to reveal its internal mechanisms.

Recorded in a ten day burst of creative energy following the birth of his first son, his newly released album Abandoned City evokes the ghostly romance of the ruin via his trademark piano preparations and - for the first time -electronic processing. An array of delays, reverbs and pitch-shifting effects bend to his will to create a shimmering world of layers that emanate from the piano.

"Satie feather-drops, gorgeous string plucks, transfixing rattles. Stillness is the move." Rolling Stone

"The sounds that Volker Bertelmann creates with(in) a piano are nothing short of astonishing... a triumph" Mojo ****

"A rapturous exercise in acoustic 'electronica'" Uncut ****
"ingenious and exquisite" New York Times]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1026]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4191]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[10 May 2014 7:45pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10252.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10252.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9247]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Evita]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Telling the story of Eva Peron, wife of former Argentine dictator Juan Peron, EVITA follows Eva's journey from humble beginnings through to extraordinary wealth, power and iconic status which ultimately led her to be heralded as the 'spiritual leader of the nation' by the Argentine people. With more than 20 major awards to its credit, including the Oscar winning film version starring Madonna and Antonio Banderas, Evita features some of the most iconic songs in musical theatre, including Don't Cry For Me Argentina, On This Night of a Thousand Stars, You Must Love Me, and Another Suitcase in Another Hall.

Marti Pellow plays Che, a character who reflects the voice of the Argentine people; linked to Eva by destiny he brings conflict to the story of Eva's rise to fame.

As a solo-singer, recording artist, and at the beginning of his career with Wet Wet Wet, Marti Pellow has enjoyed virtually un-rivalled chart success, with over 25 hits and three of the UK's biggest number one singles, including the seminal Love Is All Around. He has performed all over the world, and his West End and Musical Theatre appearances include The Witches of Eastwick, Chess, Jekyll & Hyde, Chicago and Blood Brothers. He rejoins the cast of EVITA fresh from an arena tour with Wet Wet Wet.

This production introduces a new star, Madalena Alberto, bringing the role of Eva to life to incredible critical acclaim. Madalena's musical theatre credits include the role of Piaf at the Curve Theatre, Leicester, Fantine in the 25th Anniversary production of Les Miserables. Other roles include Lucy in Jekyll and Hyde (Union Theatre, London), Carmen Diaz in Fame (UK Tour), Sam in Over the Threshold (Edinburgh and London) and Sonia in Godspell (Union Theatre, London). The Portuguese singer-songwriter also released her album Heart Condition in 2012.

Image: Keith Pattison]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[394]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Grand Theatre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1224]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Grand Theatre]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[12 May 2014 - 17 May 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9247.JPG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9247.JPG]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9671]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Leeds Gilbert And Sullivan Society Gala Charity Performance: Trial by Jury]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[by W S Gilbert and Arthur Sullivan

It is exactly 150 years since Leeds became an assize town and the high court moved in. The TownHall re-opens its courtroom for a Charity Gala Performance of Trial By Jury.

Seating is on benches in the public gallery with limited access and you are invited to bring your own cushion.

Sponsored by The Rotary Club of Headingley, all proceeds to Leeds Foodbanks.

Gala Reception: 6.30pm
Performance: 7pm]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[313]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Town Hall]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[801]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds International Concert Season]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[16 May 2014 6:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9671.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9671.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9301]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[National Opera Studio At Opera North]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The National Opera Studio (NOS) ranks among Europe's finest opera training centres, producing singers who go on to enjoy an international career.

Every two years Opera North offers NOS students the opportunity to become a professional member of the company for a week. Past students have gone on to perform in Opera North productions, including Nicky Spence who was Lampwick in The Adventures of Pinocchio.

Join us for this semi-staged concert, bringing together the country's brightest young operatic talents to sing excerpts from Benjamin Britten's operas: The Rape of Lucretia, Albert Herring and The Turn of the Screw. Directed by Olivia Fuchs.
'a great opportunity to sample the ...UK's most advanced opera students.' The Stage]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1026]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4191]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[16 May 2014 7:15pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9301.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9301.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10376]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Rutles]]></event_title><description><![CDATA["Those songs are mine - I wrote them! Why can't we just go out and sing them?" complains Neil Innes, aka Ron Nasty of The Rutles. "Maybe we could call it "Rutalot", suggests John Halsey, aka Barry Wom, the "noisy one" of the so-called "Pre-Fab Four". BRAND ON THE RUN! It all began 35 years ago when Eric Idle of Monty Python persuaded Neil Innes, of the Bonzo Dog Doo Dah Band, to join him in a comedy series for BBC 2 called Rutland Weekend Television - all about a spoof TV station, the smallest in Britain, churning out really cheap programmes on a shoestring.
 
Low budget? More like No Budget!
 
Innes suggested to Idle that they could do a send-up of A Hard Day's Night, the Beatles first movie. "It's in Black and White, it's speeded up, and we could wear wigs and tight trousers and run around a field somewhere..." "Great!" Exclaimed Idle. "I've got a sketch about a man making a documentary who's so boring, the camera runs away from him..."
 
And so the name "Rutles" was born. But no one could have expected what happened next. A year later, such was the enormous pressure on the Beatles to get back together again, the one-off clip was shown in the USA - on NBC's flagship satire programme: "Saturday Night Live". It was a sensation. Thousands of people wrote in. Mailbags were bulging. So were the trousers! Everyone got the joke. Lorne Michaels, the producer, believed the whole Beatles story could now be told - as "The Rutles". NBC agreed and gave him the money. Eric Idle quickly came up with the title: "All You Need Is Cash - the story of the Pre-Fab Four". Bill Murray, John Belushi and Dan Ackroyd got involved - so did George Harrison, who brought in Mick Jagger and Paul Simon.
 
"Last time was just the last time. This time it really is the last time." Innes recalls: "I can clearly remember it all. I was sitting to one side, on a window sill in an executive office, high up in the Rockefeller Centre in New York, listening to all this when suddenly everyone started looking at me. Lorne asked if I could write 20 more Rutle songs by next Thursday lunchtime. I said I would try!" A second album, "Archaeology", with Mickey Simmonds (Keyboards) and "Rutle" Ricky Fataar (Stig O Hara) on drums, was released in 1996 - to even greater acclaim. Planned to coincide with the Beatles "Anthology" - by public demand - new songs like "Questionnaire" and "Don't Know Why" were more thoughtful and less of a parody - or as George Harrison sweetly put it - "all part of the soup". About 10 years ago, Neil, John and Mickey teamed up with Mark Griffiths on Bass and Ken Thornton on lead guitar, (Ken can almost replace the irreplaceable Ollie Halsall!) and played the Rutle songs live, on stage, in front of teabag throwing devotees, in village halls and at weddings, oh yes, and Glastonbury.
 
"It's not a career move," explains Innes, "but over the years we have become a "Brand" - and that makes some people very proprietorial."
"Pro what?" demands the man who was Barry Wom.
"Pro Prietor. You know - Legal Owner?" says Nasty the adjective.
"Oh. I'll keep quiet then."
"No, no - you can still hit the drums..."
 
 
"Making Rutle music is supposed to be fun, and it IS fun - but someone usually goes and spoils it all by saying something stupid like you can't do this or you can't say that and by laying down the law."
Innes continues with his beef, "with any luck by the time they get round to suing us we'll have disbanded again!"
"Why don't we just call it "Rutalot?" mutters the Noisy One...]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1043]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1252]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[16 May 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10376.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10376.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10250]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Stackridge]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Stackridge formed in the early '70s, touring the UK, building a fanatical following and released 3 albums on MCA, "Stackridge", "Friendliness" and in 1974 "The Man in the Bowler Hat", which was produced by George Martin. This triumphant masterpiece, regarded by many to be George Martin's finest creation outside of his Beatles canon, the band recorded two more critically acclaimed albums, "Extravaganza" and "Mr. Mick" for Elton John's Rocket label.

Going their separate ways in 1976, they continued to make music. James Warren and Andy Davies gained notable success as electro-pop balladeers, The Korgis with two hit singles including the massive "Everybody's Got To Learn Sometime".

In 2006 the still devoted followers of the band were delighted when a reformed Stackridge started played a series of gigs, that included classic songs from the large back catalogue and a body of outstanding new material.

As ever, Stackridge has brought its' effervescent mix of melodic tunes, playful and poignant lyrics and instrumental exploration to their first album release on Helium Records. "A Victory For Common Sense", produced by Chris Hughes sees original members Andy Davis, "Mutter" Slater, "Crun" Walter and James Warren back together again and in truly fine form.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1529]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Brudenell Social Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4204]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Brudenell Social Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[16 May 2014 7:45pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10250.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10250.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9255]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[West Side Story]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[No.1 'greatest musical of all time'
THE TIMES - Top 50 Musicals 2013
 
Direct from a sell-out season at London Sadler's Wells and following international critical acclaim West Side Story comes to Leeds. 
 
With ground breaking choreography by the legendary Jerome Robbins, book by Arthur Laurent's, an unforgettable score by Leonard Bernstein and lyrics by Stephen Sondheim, West Side Story changed the face of musical theatre for ever. Now Joey McKneely's vibrant stage production is thrilling audiences once again. 
 
Based on Shakespeare's Romeo and Juliet and packed with unforgettable songs including Maria, Tonight, Somewhere, America and I Feel Pretty , this production of West Side Story is 'still as gloriously fresh, relevant and thrilling as ever.' TIME OUT 2013
 
Be sure not to miss this production of the classic musical, 'there's nothing more exciting or engaging at the moment on stage.' TELEGRAPH 2013
 
***** 
SUNDAY EXPRESS 18.8.2013
 
'Go see this show and be stunned by genius' 
TELEGRAPH 09.08.2013        
 
**** 
'The brilliance is rediscovered' 
GUARDIAN 09.08.2013
 
**** 
'Dazzles anew' 
TIMES 14.08.2013
 
**** 
'ground-breaking choreography with exhilarating drive' ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[394]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Grand Theatre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1224]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Grand Theatre]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[20 May 2014 - 31 May 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9255.png]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9255.png]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10377]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Judie Tzuke - Woman Overboard Tour]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[This year Judie is touring the UK playing tracks from her new album, "Woman Overboard" as well as performing many of her wonderful classic's. Judie Tzuke is one of the UK's finest Singer/Songwriters and is known all over the world for her timeless song, 'Stay With Me Till Dawn', with many top 10 albums, including the revered classic, 'Welcome to the Cruise' and her exquisite live shows, Judie will be showing once again what an extraordinary artist she is!
 
'Much of the audience has been in love with her since Stay With Me Till Dawn echoed around their bedrooms the first time they got their hearts broken'
The Independent
 
'The voice has lost none of its cool, plaintive appeal; it's still an  instrument of icy allure' 
The Times
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1043]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1252]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[22 May 2014 8:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10377.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10377.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10379]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Albert Hammond: Songbook 2014]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Albert Hammond has been writing hit songs for over forty years. There has not been a single decade in which Albert has not written multiple hits songs since he scored his first hit with Little Arrows at the age of 24. His songs have been responsible for the sale of over 360 million records worldwide including over 30 chart-topping hits. Many of his most beloved songs, like The Air That I Breathe and When I Need You, have become hits multiple times with various artists, decade after decade.

Albert's songs have repeatedly topped the international pop, R&B, country, adult contemporary and Latin charts, sometimes simultaneously. Included among these are the #1 hits When I Need You, Nothing's Gonna Stop Us Now (nominated for an Oscar, Golden Globe and Grammy), One Moment in Time, and To All the Girls I've Loved Before.

Now after over 50 years of his successful career he recorded his first live album ever. Songbook 2013 was recorded in Wilhelmshaven, Germany during his recent SONGBOOK Tour, one very special night, a night that catches the hilarious moment between a stunning performer and his audience. Wilhelmshaven is a sleepy country town in Germany. Albert Hammond says "People who live on the country side really appreciate that I´m coming into town to perform for them, you can feel it and that makes it very special for me."

The Live Double CD with over 30 classical songs of Albert Hammond is a testament of an outstanding singer and performer, it proves his fantastic skills as an entertainer who collaborates with his audience.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1043]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1252]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[28 May 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10379.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10379.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9304]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[FILMusic: Grouper And Paul Clipson]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[American Routes

HYPNOSIS DISPLAY

'The music of Grouper creates a feeling that can only be defined as awe, an uncanny mixture of wonder and dread that nobody does better' Pitchfork

A new FILMusic commission by Opera North, HYPNOSIS DISPLAY is a meditation on contemporary America in sound and image. Portland based musician Grouper (Liz Harris) juxtaposes layers of processed field recording, choral vocal harmony and keyboard in a resonant framework that moves behind and through Paul Clipson's 16mm film. Clipson's densely rhythmical images in turn traverse Grouper's musical language to create startling, revelatory, and critical associations.

Together they invite the audience to participate in a collective mind's-eye trip through landscapes of American myth making, including: the west coast, the worker, the city and the street.
Commissioned by Opera North Projects
Supported by the Opera North Future Fund]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1026]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4191]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Howard Assembly Room]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[5 Jun 2014 7:45pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9304.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9304.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9101]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Robbie Williams: Swings Both Ways]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Robbie Williams will be coming to the first direct arena for two nights as part of the Swings Both Ways Live tour. The show will centre around the songs from the album of the same name.

The tour follows the ecstatic response to Robbie's one-off show last week at London's Palladium where he showcased material from his brand new album Swings Both Ways, which was released today.

"Riotously entertaining" - The Guardian

"The only thing missing from this entertaining extravaganza at the London Palladium was the kitchen sink"   -  Daily Telegraph

"Swinging success for Robbie... Williams has unashamed showbiz coursing through his blood"  - The Independent

Williams has seen huge success as a solo artist, where he has had his first seven albums reach number one in the UK. He has also had seven number one singles. In total, he has sold over 70 million records worldwide, making him one of the most successful music artists in the world.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4063]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[first direct arena]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5131]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[first direct arena]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[16 Jun 2014 - 17 Jun 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9101.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9101.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10209]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Mango Tree]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The Mango Tree is a new ambitious production by Musical ARC which promises to break new ground in combining shadow theatre, traditional and contemporary dance and music. 

Musical Arc, a charity for disabled musicians, has commissioned shadow theatre artist Rebekah Caputo to devise a shadow show of a traditional indian folk story; The Mango Tree. Rebekah is also working with Indian Kathak dancer Jyoti Manral and contemporary dancer Amy Manancourt to bring to life this magical tale of princesses, demons, lotis flowers and managos! An original soundtrack devised and played by Musical Arc will accompany the performance led by Lorraine Cowburn as artistic director. Using ground breaking techniques and a multiscreen set, the production will merge shadow and dance; dancers will become shadow puppets, puppets will become dancers in a seamless fusion between what is in front, and, behind the screens. 
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[312]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Venue, Leeds College of Music]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[20 Jun 2014 7:00pm - 8:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10209.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10209.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10251]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Angelic Upstarts]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Formed on a South Shields council estate in 1977, the Upstarts soon attracted notoriety due to their aggressive music and uncompromising attitude. Their debut single "The Murder Of Liddle Towers" was self-released in 1978 and then picked up by Rough Trade and went on to sell many thousands of copies. It told the story of a boxing coach who was killed while in police custody and is one of the most incendiary punk 45s ever released. Even today it sounds incredible, dripping with anger, and its less than polished production being perfect. The B-side "Police Oppression" was also a brilliant track and singer Thomas "Mensi" Mensforth still gets harrassed from the police who have never forgiven him for these tunes.

Critical acclaim led the band to sign a major label deal and the release of their second single "I'm An Upstart". Once again this was a blistering piece of UK punk that hasn't lost its intensity over thirty years later. The band eventually received mainstream success with their third effort "Teenage Warning", which got them on Top Of The Pops and was to be their biggest hit. Over thirty years after their greatest anthems were released, the songs of the Angelic Upstarts take on a new resonance in these times of global recession and rising unemployment, not to mention the UK continuing to be involved in imperial adventures overseas. These tunes are arguably far more relevant than anything The Clash or The Sex Pistols ever put out. The Upstarts might have lacked a certain level of finesse but their integrity was never in doubt.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1529]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Brudenell Social Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4204]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Brudenell Social Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[20 Jun 2014 7:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10251.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10251.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10380]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Joe Longthorne]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[This talented artist began his career over three decades ago with appearances on Junior Showtime, followed by a grounding on the tough Northern club circuit. 
 
His big break came in 1981 when he was a finalist on London Weekend Television's Search for a Star - this lead to appearances at the London Palladium with Bob Hope and The Talk of the Town. A short time later, Joe received the Variety Club of Britain award as Most Promising Artiste of the Year. Television specials in the UK and USA followed.
 
Joe's repertoire of voices is endless and includes hundreds of the world's top singers, however, he is perhaps best known for his impersonation of Shirley Bassey who has commented, "Joe can do me better than I can do myself".
 
During his career, Joe has received gold and platinum discs for his albums, enjoyed sell-out concerts at the Royal Albert Hall, as well as touring Australia several times. 
 
Now, Joe is looking forward to new challenges, new songs to sing and new audiences to thrill.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1043]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1252]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[20 Jun 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10380.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10380.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9983]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Eric Clapton]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Widely considered one of the world's all time greatest guitarists and recognized by his peers as a great collaborator, Eric Clapton will be coming to the first direct arena this June, as one of only two UK dates.

After joining the Yardbirds in 1963, Clapton began a career as a professional musician that has seen numerous bands, an abundance of albums, countless worldwide sold out shows, an impressive array of accolades, unwavering critical acclaim and his consistent display of legendary guitar work.  2013 saw the release of his first studio album since 2010, OLD SOCK, a collection of some of Clapton's favorite songs spanning from his childhood to present day.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4063]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[first direct arena]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5131]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[first direct arena]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[22 Jun 2014 12:00pm - 1:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9983.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9983.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[8990]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Eagles]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The Eagles are bringing their History of the Eagles concert tour to the first direct arena.

The Eagles - Glenn Frey, Don Henley, Joe Walsh, and Timothy B. Schmit - will perform classics spanning their career, including some that have never been performed live, as well as songs featured in History of the Eagles, the band's acclaimed, top-selling documentary.  History of the Eagles made its European premiere during the second Sundance London film and music festival on April 25, 2013 at The O2 in London.  The Eagles last performed in the United Kingdom in July 2009.

The Eagles have sold more than 120 million albums worldwide, earning five number one U.S. singles and six GRAMMY® Awards. Their Greatest Hits 1971-1975 is the best-selling album of all time, exceeding sales of 29 million units. The band's Hotel California and Their Greatest Hits Volume 2 have sold more than 16 and 11 million albums respectively. The Eagles were inducted into the Rock & Roll Hall of Fame in 1998. ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4063]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[first direct arena]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5131]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[first direct arena]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[23 Jun 2014 7:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/8990.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/8990.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10284]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Joe's Bakery Grand Depart Presents Vidal Benjamin & Alexis Le Tan (Paris)]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Joe's Bakery and Outlaws Yacht Club celebrate the Tour de France Grand Depart in Leeds with two of their favorite DJs from Paris.  Vidal Benjamin and Alexis Le Tan have earned a wolrld wide reputation for digging deep into left-field cosmic disco, funk and balearic sounds and creating inspiring mixtapes and dj sets.

Hosted in the relaxed environment of Outlaws Yacht Club, Music starts at 2pm with Joe's Bakery residents, Craig Christon, Moonboots & Joe Gill playing records before Vidal & Alexis.  Combined with live art, locally sourced food and a great selection of drinks

The event will run until 11pm followed by secret after party.  For more info contact us on info@joesbakery.org]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3679]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Outlaws Yacht Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7768]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Outlaws Yacht Club]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[5 Jul 2014 2:00pm - 11:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10284_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10284_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9503]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Pearl Jam]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Grunge legends Pearl Jam will come to the first direct arena  as one of only two UK dates in a European tour. This follows the release and success of their tenth studio album Lightening Bolt.

One of the key bands of the early 1990's grunge movement, Pearl Jam scored a massive hit with their debut album Ten. Featuring the hit singles Alive, Even Flow and Jeremy, Ten has become one of the highest-selling rock records of all time. 

To date, the band has sold over 31.5 million records in the U.S, and an estimated 60 million worldwide. Pearl Jam has outlasted and outsold many of their contemporaries from the grunge breakthrough, and are considered one of the most influential bands of the 1990's.

]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4063]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[first direct arena]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5131]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[first direct arena]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[8 Jul 2014 ]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9503.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9503.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10157]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Bramley Carnival]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Bramley Carnival 2014 is themed Tour de Carnival 

An established family community event that provides fun for all families.  2014 will see the return of Stuntworld Motorcycle Stunt Team with spectacular stunts.

Carnival Queen and Princesses Crowning, Trade Stalls, Punch and Judy, Large Funfair by Marshall Waddington.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1458]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Bramley Park]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[6741]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[bramley Carnival Committee]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[20 Jul 2014 12:00pm - 5:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10157.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10157.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10383]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Beverley Craven: Change Of Heart Tour]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[BRIT-Award winner Beverley Craven will be embarking on an extensive UK tour supporting the release of her brand new album, Change of Heart, being launched in summer 2014. Beverley is looking forward to performing her new songs live alongside timeless classics Promise Me, Holding On, Woman To Woman, Love Scenes and many more. With a witty narrative and unforgettable melodies, her poignant sentiments will leave you with a warm glow of nostalgia, or maybe even the odd tear.

 ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1043]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1252]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[24 Sep 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10383.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10383.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9319]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[James Taylor]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[US singer-songwriter James Taylor will be performing as part of his first UK arena tour in over three years.

Over the course of his career, Taylor has earned 40 gold, platinum and multi-platinum awards and five Grammy Awards for a catalogue running from 1970's Sweet Baby James to 2008's Covers. 

As a recording and touring artist, Taylor has set a precedent to which countless young musicians have aspired. His warm baritone is among the most recognized voices in popular music and his distinctive style of guitar-playing has been enormously influential. He has sold over 100 million albums throughout his career, beginning in 1968 when he was signed to The Beatles' Apple Records. In 1971, Taylor was featured on the cover of Time magazine, heralded as the harbinger of the singer-songwriter era. Forty years later, his voice has been a constant in a changing world for his first generation of fans and their children. ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4063]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[first direct arena]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5131]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[first direct arena]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[27 Sep 2014 ]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9319.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9319.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9676]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Ed Sheeran]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Pop folk star comes to Leeds as part of a UK tour by
Grammy-nominated, multi-platinum selling, Madison Square Garden conquering singer-songwriter Ed Sheeran.

Ed Sheeran has enjoyed a meteoric rise to fame in the music industry. The 22-year old's debut entered the U.K. Albums Chart at number one with the highest opening week figures for a debut male solo artist ever and is now certified 6x platinum in the UK. ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4063]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[first direct arena]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5131]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[first direct arena]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[11 Oct 2014 ]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9676.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9676.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10427]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[ Kiki Dee & Carmelo Luggeri: An Acoustic Journey]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[For almost two decades, Kiki and Carmelo have been touring their acoustic live show across the UK and Europe. 

Performing in this stripped back fashion allows each of their talents to shine through and create a warm sense of intimacy for the audience. 2013 marked Kiki's 50th year in the music industry and has cemented her status as one of the UK's finest and most revered vocalists. To celebrate, the duo released their critically acclaimed album A Place Where I Can Go which features 11 new tracks including the haunting duet Horses with Scottish singer Eddi Reader. This acoustic journey of stories and song includes unique covers of songs by artists such as Kate Bush and Frank Sinatra, and of course Kiki's own hits Don't Go Breaking My Heart, I Got the Music in Me and Amoureuse. ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1043]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1252]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[City Varieties]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[23 Oct 2014 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10427.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10427.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9092]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Il Divo]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Il Divo - the record-breaking classical crossover group who have sold more than 26 million albums worldwide - will perform their hit album Il Divo - A Musical Affair: The Greatest Songs of Broadway Live at the first direct arena.  

The world tour supports the group's sixth studio album A Musical Affair. It's their first compilation of songs inspired by Broadway shows such as Phantom of the Opera, Carousel and West Side Story and features stellar duet partners Barbra Streisand, Kristin Chenoweth, Nicole Scherzinger, Heather Headley and Michael Ball. 

The show will intertwine the most famous songs from Broadway musicals with the individual theatrical experiences of Carlos, David, Urs and Sebastien. 

Il Divo is the world's first and most successful classical crossover group. The foursome have sold over 26 million albums worldwide, achieved over 50 number one records, received 160 gold and platinum sales awards in over 33 countries and staged four groundbreaking world tours. The international quartet comprises of tenor Urs Buhler of Switzerland, baritone Carlos Marin of Spain, pop artist Sebastien Izambard of France and tenor David Miller from the United States. As Il Divo first came to fruition in 2003, this year's album and complementary concert series marks a milestone for the four singers as they commemorate the success of a 10-year career together.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4063]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[first direct arena]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5131]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[first direct arena]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[31 Oct 2014 ]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9092.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9092.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9094]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[War Of The Worlds]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Starring Westlife's Brian McFadden, Jason Donovan & Les Miserables' Carrie Hope Fletcher 

For the first and last time, one of the most ground-breaking tours of all time, Jeff Wayne's Musical Version of The War of The Worlds is to return for the sixth and final time in 2014.   

The show will again feature a stellar cast with Jeff Wayne returning to the Podium to conduct the 9-piece Black Smoke Band and 36-piece ULLAdubULLA Strings with the final two musical Guest Artistes to be announced. 

Liam Neeson's 3D holographic performance as The Journalist will also return but with enhanced technology. 

The Sung Thoughts of The Journalist will be performed by Brian McFadden, Jason Donovan is reprising his hugely popular role as Parson Nathaniel and Carrie Hope Fletcher featuring as Beth, Parson Nathaniel's Wife, direct from her current and widely acclaimed West End performance in Les Miserables, as Eponine. 

The production will be the sixth UK tour in eight years.  Jeff Wayne said: "Bringing The War of The Worlds to life in many of the world's finest arenas has been the most amazing experience for me over the last seven years. We've achieved more than we ever thought was possible both musically and technologically. 

However, the time is right to take The War of The Worlds in new directions after the 2014 tour. I am so very appreciative of the fantastic support over the years from so many established fans as well as numerous new ones we've attracted. Thank you all sincerely. 

All I can say for the future of TWOTW is - Watch this space!"]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4063]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[first direct arena]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5131]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[first direct arena]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[6 Dec 2014 12:00pm - 1:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9094_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9094_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10505]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Diversity]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[After wowing audiences last winter with their astounding Limitless arena tour, Diversity now bring us Limitless - The Reboot a fully improved and updated version of their critically acclaimed show, coming to the first direct arena this December for the first time.

Spurred on by the group's motto "Dream, Believe, Achieve", Diversity are a remarkable example of what can be accomplished with hard work, dedication and belief.  

Since winning Britain's Got Talent in 2009, Diversity have won numerous awards, been the first act to perform outside No. 10 Downing Street in front of the Prime Minister and have sold out three UK & Ireland tours.

Their previous tours have seen them travelling the length of the country performing for their legion of devoted fans, and delivering exceptional entertainment with some stand out reviews. Normally incorporating several genres of music from classical to hip-hop, their diverse eye-catching routines won the hearts of the nation. So far they've performed live to over 1 million people across the world.  ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4063]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[first direct arena]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5131]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[first direct arena]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[12 Dec 2014 ]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10505.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10505.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10132]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Andre Rieu]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Famous for conducting his Johann Strauss Orchestra, choir and soloists with his violin bow, Andre Rieu always brings a sense of extravagance to his live performances.

From famous Viennese operettas to film scores, spirituals to musicals, and from folk songs to marches; Rieu's concerts are a perfect mix of thrilling, romantic, festive and emotional melodies combined with surprises, balloons, beautiful soloists and of course Rieu's great sense of humor.

Speaking ahead of his first direct arena show, Andre said "The British and Irish are really a fantastic audience. Their sense of humour and enthusiasm are unmatched. For my orchestra and me it's like being amongst friends. Every year we welcome more and more British at our home concert in Maastricht. And even there they create this unforgettable atmosphere. So we are looking forward to coming back"
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4063]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[first direct arena]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Dec 2014 8:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10132.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10132.jpg]]></image_original></item></objects></response>