<?xml version="1.0"?><response><status><![CDATA[200]]></status><status_message><![CDATA[OK]]></status_message><message><![CDATA[OK]]></message><objects><item><event_id><![CDATA[3168]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Birdwatching For Beginners]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Would you like to be able to identify the birds you see in your garden or local nature reserve? Wondering what to do with your winter evenings? Join local birdwatcher, Linda Jenkinson at Hollybush Conservation Centre and learn all you need to know to get started with this exciting and rewarding hobby. Booking essential
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[7953]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Hollybush Conservation Centre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5487]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Start Birding]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[6 Jan 2014 - 2 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/3168.JPG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/3168.JPG]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10340]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Breaking Bad - The Pub Quiz]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Traditional pub quizzes are boring, so we're taking the concept to a new level and a far more important topic - BREAKING BAD. Put all that binge TV-watching to good use and test your knowledge of the hit TV show through six rounds for cash and booze prizes.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[9073]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Belgrave Music Hall and Canteen]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10339]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Geeks Inc]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[9 Mar 2014 6:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10340.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10340.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10278]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Sassy Divas Do Stampin Up Crafts]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Sassy Divas is a friendly welcoming womens group who meet in West Leeds, our meetings are on the 2nd Wednesday of every month in the Lower Hall at St Peters Church. 

Come along to a meeting and learn a new skill, or craft from our array of demonstrators, presenters and teachers, a guaranteed wonderful evening of fun. ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[10277]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Lower Hall St Peter's Church]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[6800]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Julie]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[12 Mar 2014 7:30pm - 9:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10278.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10278.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9591]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Quiz Night]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Every Thursday join join our Quiz Night with a Twist ;)]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[9587]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Inkwell Bar]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[26 Dec 2013 - 24 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9591.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9591.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10331]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Lore Of The North Book Launch]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[''The moor was still, poised at this hour as if this extraordinary event had dispelled time...'

The launch sees Lord Whitney's Lore of the North project presented in an exciting publication and exhibition, based on Yorkshire Folklore. 

Food, drink, and an Introductory talk by Stephen Sayers (6pm).

In association with Food&_ and The Social, with drinks to follow at newly opened The Social.

If you've missed the project, catch up here - http://loreofthenorth.tumblr.com/
www.lordwhitney.co.uk

Supported by Grants for the Arts and Leeds Inspired]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1782]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Munro House]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10330]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Lord Whitney]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Mar 2014 6:00pm - 9:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10331.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10331.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[7526]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Oblong Cinema]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Oblong Cinema is a monthly event to discover and showcase local filmmaking talent in Leeds & Yorkshire with a different theme each month - this March the theme is Documentary.

(Image is from 'Closure' a film about our fast-disappearing pubs)

Run by filmmakers for filmmakers, Oblong Cinema's schedule is an eclectic mix of programmed and submitted work and we are always looking for films by Yorkshire filmmakers.

Oblong Cinema showcases short films in the hall at Woodhouse Community Centre with an intimate and friendly screening, encouraging audience feedback and Q+A's with filmmakers. Join us for a fun night of films and networking - and free popcorn!

Oblong Cinema screens at Woodhouse Community Centre on the first Thursday of each month from 7pm - 8pm ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[184]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Woodhouse Community Centre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7525]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Oblong Cinema]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Mar 2014 7:00pm - 8:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/7526_10.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/7526_10.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[5430]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Green Team!]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[We run practical environmental volunteering days most Fridays (see our website for calendar of events), when there is a chance to join the 'Green Team' to help develop and maintain the wildlife area at Skelton Grange. You can come for a one-off day or every week - it's a great chance to get involved and learn new skills, and no previous experience is needed!

Get in touch to let us know if you're planning to come along to any of the events. Tea, coffee and biscuits will be provided but please bring a packed lunch. Wear old clothes that you don't mind getting mucky, and dress for the weather.

Directions to the Centre can be found on our website
.
- Under 18s must be accompanied by an adult for all events.
- Please arrive at nine thirty for a ten o'clock start.
- Generally sessions run until three thirty unless advertised otherwise.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[5420]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Skelton Grange Environment Centre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5423]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Skelton Grange]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[27 Sep 2013 - 26 Apr 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/5430.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/5430.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[3868]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Inkwell Arts Cafe: Eat, Drink, Create]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Every Saturday you can enjoy delicious, home-cooked vegetarian food, homemade cakes, fresh coffee and a variety of other drinks.  Each week we have a variety of craft workshops for you to try, including batik, jewellery, upcycled crafts, pottery. 

Sit and relax in our spacious gallery, surrounded by work from local artists, take advantage of free WiFi and, on sunnier days, enjoy our garden. We also have craft workshops and activities for children. 

Cafe opening times 10 - 4 every Saturday
Workshop times are 10.30 to 12.30 and then 1.30 to 3.30

We will be expanding this service, in the near future and hope to offer you all this on a Sunday too! 
More details can be found on our website http://www.inkwellarts.org.uk/saturday-cafe/ or if you have any enquiries, please get in touch! 

Reviews:
 http://www.aboutmyarea.co.uk/site/content.asp?area=398&type=3&story=241215
http://theculturevulture.co.uk/blog/reviews/food-and-drink-reviews/inkwellcafe/
http://www.veggieplaces.co.uk/list_reviews.php?place_id=3745

]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1614]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Inkwell]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[3657]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Inkwell Arts]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[6 Apr 2013 - 13 Dec 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/3868.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/3868.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9242]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Fish 'N' Reels]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Otley Film Society and Otley Action for Older People present two classic films from the '40s and '50s together with a fish and chip supper (or veggie) in the interval.

]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2142]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Otley Courthouse]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[9241]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Otley Film Society and otley Action for Older people]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[15 Mar 2014 3:00pm - 7:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9242.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9242.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10296]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Quiz Night]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Test your general knowledge in a relaxed atmosphere. A great way to end the weekend with friends. Free with prizes and raffle.

This week's quiz takes on an Irish theme.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[849]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Seven Arts Centre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[8529]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Seven Arts Centre ]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[16 Mar 2014 8:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10296.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10296.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10499]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Squeeze]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Sunday Night Blues Dance Lesson and Social Dance.

Join us for the start of a brand new blues experience in Leeds!

The Squeeze is a monthly blues dance event where you can learn authentic blues and blues fusion dance, and move to some of the most sultry and smoking tunes north of Memphis - music from Nina Simone to Nora Jones, Ray Charles to James Blake.

Low lights glisten, shimmering images of projected dancers glide overhead.  The sound of Delta blues, cool jazz and current soul fills the air as pairs of dancers shimmy, shake and slide across the dancefloor with seemingly effortless abandon.  This is the cutting edge of contemporary blues dance, this is The Squeeze.

Beginners Blues Class 8pm - 9pm 
Social Blues Dance 9pm - midnight
No experience necessary or partner required 

Cosy venue, delicious food and drinks!

FAQs

What is Blues Dance? 
Blues dance is a distinctive style of dancing which developed alongside blues music more than 100 years ago and is still developing today, with a huge revival in many cities all over the world. 

I've never danced (anything!) before, can I still join?
Absolutely, the class at 8pm will be aimed at absolute beginners, but there will enough content to satisfy those who have previously danced blues too.

Do I need to buy a ticket?
It's strongly recommended that you buy a ticket beforehand as similar events have sold out, and due to the cosy nature of the venue, once we get to capacity, to ensure our dancers' comfort and safety, we will not be allowing any more participants.  The only way to guarantee your place at the dance is to buy a ticket beforehand.

What do I need to bring?
Just your ticket (otherwise it's &pound;5 on the door, if we still have space).  Wear comfortable clothes and shoes. You're welcome to come along with a partner or group of friends, but many people come on their own, and as long as there's space, we will accommodate you, whatever group size you are.

What kind of music do you play?
We play everything from traditional blues and swing jazz from the 1920s onwards, right up to blues-friendly tunes from the last few years, including a sprinkling of soul, r&b and torch songs.

Why the Squeeze?
Blues dancing is best suited to cosy, informal venues, and as Upstairs at LS6 has a maximum capacity of 60 people, the name just seemed to fit!]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[10497]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Upstairs at LS6 Cafe]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10498]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[James F Clark]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[16 Mar 2014 8:00pm - 11:45pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10499.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10499.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9245]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Science Cafe]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Speakers set out their key idea in 10 - 15 minutes and 20 slides.  Then over to you to ask questions.  Watch the website for details of speakers once announced.

All welcome, whether you are a beginner, an expert, still at school.

www.otleysciencefestival.co.uk]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2142]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Otley Courthouse]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7150]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Otley Courthouse]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[20 Mar 2014 7:30pm - 9:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9245_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9245_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9945]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Create a Vision Board]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[... for the next chapter of your life.

Before you set out on a journey it helps to know where you're going. If not, you're going to end up SOMEWHERE . . . just not where you want to be.

What if your elusive dreams took shape before your eyes? What would you discover? What could you then bring into your life for real?

Vision boards are a fabulous technique for focussing our energy and commitment on what's important. Then we get to have more of it in our lives. Pictures, words, photos, lines from poems, colour - they all help to create a powerful reminder of what you want in your future.

Making them in a workshop is fun, playful, stress free and collaborative. You get to share ideas and tell other people about yours. That's the added extra of doing this with others - you get to say it out loud as well.

"I don't want to get to the end of my life and find that I lived just the length of it. I want to have lived the width of it as well." Diane Ackerman

This workshop will suit anyone who is
- Seeking a different way to approach the new year.
- Wanting to look at your life as a whole and create greater fulfilment and richness in it.
- Has an idea for a specific project you want to create (and maybe you keep putting it on the back burner).
- Planning something big like a wedding, new business idea or retirement.

This special workshop retreat is for a maximum of 6 people, book early to be sure you're one of them. How about booking a place with your partner and creating a shared vision for your future.

During the workshop you'll
- Plug into the power of your dreams.
- Get in contact with your wisest inner self and use that inner knowing to create your vision from.
- Be coached to explore that vision so it becomes richer and more vibrant.
- Create your own vision board using a collage of images, words and colour.
- Talk about the significance of the elements of your vision so you get to hear yourself claim it out loud.
- Plan how you're going to use your board to keep focussed on what's important to you.
- Spend a day in a warm, cosy home, eat well, share laughter and have some playful fun cutting out!

" My partner and I did this course with Tilla - this weekend we have a romantic retreat by the sea to complete our shared vision board!"   Helen Collier, Money Coach HarmoneyLife

All you need is comfy clothes, a desire to create your own life and an open mind. The desire to have that fun will also come in useful! This is Blue Peter for adults!

I'll provide all the materials, and if you want to bring along old magazines to share around that'll be great.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[7008]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[5 Wensley Grove]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4308]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Tilla Brook]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[23 Mar 2014 9:30am - 4:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9945.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9945.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10357]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Alternative Wedding Event]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Are you getting married but a white meringue and hotel wedding the last thing you want then come to our wedding fair

Whether you want a purple victorian coat, a red medieval dress or a tea party with a cake covered in cogs then our sellers should be able to accommodate

Then come along to our shop wedding event and chat with our sellers about all your needs.

We'll also have vintage hair and make up demos and wedding related craft sessions

If you are a wedding seller and want to be part of our team then get in touch asap]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[4404]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Fabrication Crafts Limited]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1430]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Fabrication Crafts Ltd]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[23 Mar 2014 11:00am - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10357.JPG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10357.JPG]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[6181]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Cafe Psychologique]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Cafe Psychologique is a space where people can talk about life over a drink from a psychological perspective. It builds on the philosophy of Cafe Scientifique to take ideas out of professional settings like universities, laboratories and clinics to make them accessible to people in their everyday life.

Like Cafe Scientifique there are trained professionals to provide a resource to the cafe, but no lectures or seminars. Instead ideas are dropped into to the group to stimulate thought and discussion and people are invited to bring along issues they want to talk about, discuss, explore or find help with.

Each month we tackle a different theme, listed on our website: www.spark.uk.net/cafe-psychologique ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[849]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Seven Arts Centre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5175]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Chris Powell]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[28 May 2013 - 31 Dec 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/6181.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/6181.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10549]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Minicine At The Mills: Zift]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The final film in our Modern Monochrome season, Javor Gardev's Bulgarian crime drama, ZIFT, tells the story of Moth - a petty criminal wrongfully convicted of murder.

Jailed shortly before the Bulgarian communist coup of 1944, he now finds himself in a new and alien world - the totalitarian Sofia of the 1960s. His first night of freedom draws the map of a diabolical city full of decaying neighbourhoods, gloomy streets and a bizarre parade of characters.

Like his namesake to a flame, it is not long before Moth is drawn back to his old habits. Part La Haine-part Chopper, Zift is both brutal and funny, romantic while packing one hell of a punch.

Our feature presentation will be preceded by a selection of short films plus a preview of our upcoming African season.

Tea, coffee and homemade cake will be available on arrival.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[151]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Armley Mills Leeds Industrial Museum]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[2938]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Minicine]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[27 Mar 2014 7:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10549.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10549.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10341]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Game Of Thrones - The Pub Quiz]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Traditional pub quizzes are boring, so we're taking the concept to a new level and a far more important topic - GAME OF THRONES. Put all that binge TV-watching to good use and test your knowledge of the hit TV show through six rounds for cash and booze prizes. ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[9073]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Belgrave Music Hall and Canteen]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10339]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Geeks Inc]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[13 Apr 2014 6:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10341.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10341.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10439]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Aim Social & Acess To Music Funding]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Part of the UnConference.

A jam packed evening! It all kicks off at 6pm, with a panel on music business funding including guest speakers; Chris Bye (Arts Council England), Laura Whitticase (PRS for Music Foundation) and Claire NcNeil (AIM), with Live At Leeds' own Whiskas chairing the session. 

Then the real fun starts with some really awesome bands performing live, The Horn Hunt and Post War Glamour Girls! As well as some super cool DJing from The Leaf Label's Tony Morley. AIM Socials are open to independent labels, self-releasing artists and the wider music industry, so get registered.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1529]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Brudenell Social Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[1024]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Live at Leeds]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[19 Apr 2014 6:00pm - 11:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10439.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10439.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9656]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Picture Lending Scheme: Selection Day]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Leeds Art Gallery's picture lending library was established in 1961 as a way for people to enjoy original art at home - come to the Gallery and choose high quality pictures from a large collection to borrow and take home. 

Over six hundred art works are available to borrow from oils, drawings, photographs and a variety of prints; whether you like landscapes or abstracts, Henri Matisse or Henry Moore, there is something to suit every taste.

How much does it cost?
There is no membership or joining fee, you pay for what you borrow. It costs just &pound;4 per month for one artwork and then &pound;2 per month for any additional works. All artworks are for a minimum period of three months (therefore a min payment of &pound;12 is applicable).]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[150]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Leeds Art Gallery]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[7293]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Museums & Galleries]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[26 Apr 2014 11:00am - 3:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9656.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9656.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10342]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Sherlock - The Pub Quiz]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Traditional pub quizzes are boring, so we're taking the concept to a new level and a far more important topic - SHERLOCK. Put all that binge TV-watching to good use and test your knowledge of the hit TV show through six rounds for cash and booze prizes. ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[9073]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Belgrave Music Hall and Canteen]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10339]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Geeks Inc]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[11 May 2014 6:00pm - 8:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10342.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10342.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9688]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Leeds Horticultural Society's Plant Sale And Coffee Morning]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[A variety of plants, garden accessories and cakes for sale.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[3729]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[St Chad's Parish Centre]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[17 May 2014 9:30am - 11:30am]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9688.JPG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9688.JPG]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9946]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Create A Vision Board ]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[... for the next chapter of your life.

Before you set out on a journey it helps to know where you're going. If not, you're going to end up SOMEWHERE . . . just not where you want to be.

What if your elusive dreams took shape before your eyes? What would you discover? What could you then bring into your life for real?

Vision boards are a fabulous technique for focussing our energy and commitment on what's important. Then we get to have more of it in our lives. Pictures, words, photos, lines from poems, colour - they all help to create a powerful reminder of what you want in your future.

Making them in a workshop is fun, playful, stress free and collaborative. You get to share ideas and tell other people about yours. That's the added extra of doing this with others - you get to say it out loud as well.

"I don't want to get to the end of my life and find that I lived just the length of it. I want to have lived the width of it as well." Diane Ackerman

This workshop will suit anyone who is
- Seeking a different way to approach the new year.
- Wanting to look at your life as a whole and create greater fulfilment and richness in it.
- Has an idea for a specific project you want to create (and maybe you keep putting it on the back burner).
- Planning something big like a wedding, new business idea or retirement.

This special workshop retreat is for a maximum of 6 people, book early to be sure you're one of them. How about booking a place with your partner and creating a shared vision for your future.

During the workshop you'll
- Plug into the power of your dreams.
- Get in contact with your wisest inner self and use that inner knowing to create your vision from.
- Be coached to explore that vision so it becomes richer and more vibrant.
- Create your own vision board using a collage of images, words and colour.
- Talk about the significance of the elements of your vision so you get to hear yourself claim it out loud.
- Plan how you're going to use your board to keep focussed on what's important to you.
- Spend a day in a warm, cosy home, eat well, share laughter and have some playful fun cutting out!

" My partner and I did this course with Tilla - this weekend we have a romantic retreat by the sea to complete our shared vision board!"   Helen Collier, Money Coach HarmoneyLife

All you need is comfy clothes, a desire to create your own life and an open mind. The desire to have that fun will also come in useful! This is Blue Peter for adults!

I'll provide all the materials, and if you want to bring along old magazines to share around that'll be great.
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[7008]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[5 Wensley Grove]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[4308]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Tilla Brook]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[7 Jun 2014 9:30am - 4:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9946.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9946.jpg]]></image_original></item></objects></response>