<?xml version="1.0"?><response><status><![CDATA[200]]></status><status_message><![CDATA[OK]]></status_message><message><![CDATA[OK]]></message><objects><item><event_id><![CDATA[10170]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[British Wildlife Festival]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The British Wildlife Festival takes place in March every year. 2014's festival takes place between the 7th - 9th March. What's so special about British Wildlife Festival is that it takes place at arguably one of the best independent venues in the UK The Brudenell Social Club and is a fully independently promoted event with a carefully curated lineup.

In a Nutshell
Loads of awesome bands on the Friday
Even more awesome bands on Saturday
and even more awesome bands on Sunday
I use the term 'band' broadly
Over 30 bands playing over the one weekend
Late curfew
Freedom to come and go as you please.
Respect to all.
No VIP areas or backstage passes.
No barriers infront of stages.
Chaos
Cake
Some of the greatest bands in the UK.
Surprises.
DJs handpicked to play some really interesting / fun tunes.

Friday 7th March 2014
CATTLE
ELECTRIC ELECTRIC
HILARY & THE HATE CRIMES
HOUSEWIVES
ICE, SEA, DEAD PEOPLE
P FOR PERSIA
SHATNER'S BASSOON

Saturday 8th March 2014
AEROPLANE FLIES HIGH
BAD GUYS
BLOODY MAMMALS
BLOOD SPORT
CASTROVALVA
EVIL BLIZZARD
FEMALE SMELL
GUM TAKES TOOTH
I'M BEING GOOD
LADYSCRAPER
MATTHEW BOURNE
MAYORS OF MIYAZAKI
SCREEN WIVESSHITWIFE
SUPER FAST GIRLIE SHOW
SWEET WILLIAMS
TRANS/HUMAN
TWO TRICK HORSE
USA NAILS
WARM WIDOW

Sunday 9th March 2014
ALPHA MALE TEA PARTY
CARER
COWTOWN
DARK BELLS
GHOLD
HENRY BLACKER
STEREO VIRGINS
TOKYO DOORBELLS
VODUN
THE WITCH HUNT

]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1529]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The Brudenell Social Club]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10169]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[British Wildlife Festival]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[7 Mar 2014 - 9 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10170.png]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10170.png]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10509]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Rothwell Competitive Music Festival]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Rothwell Competitive Music Festival is held annually in March, and the committee also organises other fundraising concerts.

The Showcase concert on Friday 28th March 7pm at Rothwell Methodist Church will include performances by selected competitors from several classes accompanied by David Wilks. ]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[10508]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Rothwell Methodist Church]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[19 Mar 2014 - 22 Mar 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10509_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10509_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10489]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[The Ig Nobel Prizes - Improbable Science Show]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Honouring bizarre and extraordinary achievements in science, medicine and technology, the Ig Nobel Prizes Show is coming from America to the University of Leeds to celebrate research stories that make people LAUGH then THINK. Join us to hear its founder, Marc Abrahams, reveal the stories behind the new Ig Nobel winners, as well as all-star dramatic readings from bizarre, genuine and utterly compelling research studies.

More information about the Ig Nobel Prizes can be found at: http://www.improbable.com/ig/ 

This event is part of the Leeds Festival of Science - to find out about our range of other public events, including sessions on the ethics of fracking, cancer research and self-led trails around the city, please visit http://www.stem.leeds.ac.uk/lfos-public/
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[10487]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Conference Auditorium]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10488]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[University of Leeds]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[20 Mar 2014 6:45pm - 8:30pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10489_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10489_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10491]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Black Holes, White Holes And Worm Holes]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Join astrophysicist Dame Jocelyn Bell Burnell to find out if there really are black holes in space.

How do we know? What are white holes? Is travel to another universe possible?

Learn the answers to these fascinating questions and more!

This is a free event brought to you by the Institute of Physics, suitable for all ages. Refreshments will be served from 6:30pm - if you would like to bring a group, please email m.e.ries@leeds.ac.uk otherwise please just turn up. Free parking is also available on university campus.

This event is part of the Leeds Festival of Science - to find out about our range of other public events, including sessions on the ethics of fracking, cancer research and self-led trails around the city, please visit http://www.stem.leeds.ac.uk/lfos-public/
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[10487]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Conference Auditorium]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10488]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[University of Leeds]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[26 Mar 2014 7:00pm - 8:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10491.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10491.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10490]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Engineering Experience]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Supported by the Royal Academy of Engineering, this free public event will demonstrate the importance of engineering disciplines. Come along to our 'market-place' of hands-on interactive activities suitable for adults and children of all ages, and see demonstrations from disciplines such as Medical Engineering, Civil Engineering, Electrical Engineering, and more! No booking required - just drop in!

This event is part of the Leeds Festival of Science - to find out about our range of other public events, including sessions on the ethics of fracking, cancer research and self-led trails around the city, please visit http://www.stem.leeds.ac.uk/lfos-public/
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[777]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Parkinson Court]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10488]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[University of Leeds]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[29 Mar 2014 10:00am - 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10490_1.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10490_1.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10282]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[2nd Calverley Folk Day]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Musicians, singers, supporters all welcome to join in the fun at the second Calverley Folk Day.

Open mics, floor spots as well as designated spots are all available.

Featured bands will also perform.

This year we have some more fun events Karifolky and the Best Beard Competition.

Calverley has other pubs - Thornhill Arms and Calverley Arms pubs (all serving food and drink) with real ale available at most of the venues.

Image: Martin Singleton]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[6094]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[The New Inn, Calverley]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[3332]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Creative Calverley]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[26 Apr 2014 1:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10282.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10282.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10197]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Rhubarbfest 2014]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Rhubarbfest is a community organised free live music event held in Carlton Village each year.

Fairground rides are located at the front of the Unicorn Inn and Carlton Social Club, and a live music stage is at the rear of the Inn. The road between is closed for safety.

In 2014 we are also hosting a second/acoustic stage within The Carlton Social Club.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[10195]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Carlton Village]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10196]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Carlton Village Residents Association]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[25 May 2014 1:00pm - 10:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10197_0.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10197_0.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10514]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Veg Out 2014]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[A vegetarian food & drink festival with music & art 

FOOD & DRINK

Bundobust http://bundobust.com/
Vegetarian Indian street food kitchen

The Grub & Grog Shop http://www.grubandgrog.co.uk/
Stews, sandwiches & salads in many shapes and forms

That Old Chestnut http://thatoldchestnutishere.com/
Irresistible vegan cakes, baked goods & savouries

The Wheely Nice Ice Cream Tricycle
A fun, vintage, environmentally friendly ice cream tricycle

Laynes Espresso http://www.laynesespresso.co.uk/
Serving the best coffee in Leeds since 2011

Leeds Bread Coop http://leedsbread.coop/
Leeds based artisan bakery

The Real Cider Company http://realcidercompany.co.uk/
Hand crafted ciders

MUSIC - SATURDAY

Bearfoot Beware http://bearfootbeware.co.uk/
Energetic & scrappy alternative rock band from Leeds

Juffage http://juffage.com/
a solo sound artist and multi-instrumentalist from Leeds UK, via Chicago, Illinois.

Magnapinna http://magnapinna.bandcamp.com/
A trio of handsomes who play jarring, groove-laden repeato rock

Douga http://douga.bandcamp.com/
A rich mix of warm psychedelia, Americana and more European experimental influences.

IMP http://impblogblog.blogspot.co.uk/
Habitual popsters practicing a riff heavy-pop chime with hi-deluxe vocal melodies

Plus Stuart Benjamin Briggs spinning funk, soul and disco vinyl in the bar room. http://tightenupleeds.tumblr.com/

AFTERPARTY DJS

Vessels DJs

Matt Woodward (Galaxians/Release Yourself)

MUSIC - SUNDAY (Hosted by Youth Anthems)

Middleman http://www.middlemanband.co.uk/Welcome!/Home.html
4-piece alternative rap rock band based in Leeds

Pifco http://pifco1.bandcamp.com/
Somewhere between the dry Nothern wit of The Fall and the party sounds of Bis or Devo

Zapiain http://zapiain.bandcamp.com/
Bombed Out Records finest are here to bring the 90's punk rock sound of Leeds to your ears

We Died at Sea http://wediedatsea.bandcamp.com/
Guitars, violins, double bass and even the odd kazoo

Just Another Warning http://justanotherwarning.bandcamp.com/
One man socio political acoustic punk rock!

ART

Hope House Prints
Live screen printing

PLUS MUCH MORE TBC]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1603]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Wharf Chambers]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[10255]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[The Grub & Grog Shop]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[31 May 2014 - 1 Jun 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10514.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10514.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10507]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Beeston Festival]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Beeston Festival is a celebration of everything that's good in our diverse and vibrant community.

As usual  you will find:

Entertainment across four stages
Food from around the world
A bazaar full of games, clothes, jewellery, plants and information
Sports, games and activities for children and young people
A fun fair

Plus this year we have a cycling theme to tie in with the Grand Depart of the Tour de France. You will find bike activities, bike maintenance, bike inspired art and bike inspired food!

So come on, Let's Go Cycling! Let's Go Beeston Festival!

Image: Paul Bullivant/Beeston Festival]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[302]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Cross Flatts Park]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[6516]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Beeston Festival Committee]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[14 Jun 2014 12:00pm - 5:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10507.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10507.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[8666]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Let's Rock Leeds]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The Family Friendly 80s Festival.

The first Let's Rock Leeds! has a fabulous line-up of artists to bring you the very best of the 80s, and an action packed day of general 80s madness, there is plenty to do for everyone!

Acts will include Bananarama, Kim Wilde, Howard Jones, ABC, Nik Kershaw, Alexander O'Neal, Nick Heyward, The Real Thing, Altered Images, Brother Beyond, Jaki Graham and Then Jerico.

Tons of attractions to keep the children happy, such as our free Bigtopmania circus, a super funfair including water rides and soft play areas, as well as children's entertainers from BBC/ITV, Let's Rock Leeds! offers the perfect day out for all the family.  Multiple bars and a wide range of quality food outlets, selling everything from hotdogs to award-winning Tandoori, means every taste is catered for.  Posh toilets will also be available for those that like a little bit of festival luxury plus a fantastic VIP package.  Enjoy our "Changeover Party" which includes an array of entertainment during those dull band changeovers, including our new "BigScreen Sing", 
DJ's from Absolute 80s, other entertainers and TV legends to keep the party going for the whole day!

Let's Rock! has been leading the way for quality, family-friendly 80s music festivals since 2009.  Don't miss out on this chance for a retro blast with the very best of the 80s
]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[155]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Temple Newsam House and Estate]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[8665]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Let's Rock]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[21 Jun 2014 ]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/8666.JPG]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/8666.JPG]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10157]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Bramley Carnival]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Bramley Carnival 2014 is themed Tour de Carnival 

An established family community event that provides fun for all families.  2014 will see the return of Stuntworld Motorcycle Stunt Team with spectacular stunts.

Carnival Queen and Princesses Crowning, Trade Stalls, Punch and Judy, Large Funfair by Marshall Waddington.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[1458]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Bramley Park]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[6741]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[bramley Carnival Committee]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[20 Jul 2014 12:00pm - 5:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10157.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10157.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[9675]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Leeds Ska And Mod Festival]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Leeds Ska and Mod Festival The Music that changed everything!

Playing for the first time together, Red Eagle Events brings you four of the biggest Mod and Ska Bands in the UK.
 
Featured bands

From the Jam, fronted by one of the original Modfathers Bruce Foxton, hits include: A Town Called Malice

The Beat fronted by Ranking Roger and Ranking Jr, hits include: Tears of a Clown

Bad Manners fronted by Buster bloodvessel, hits include: Special Brew

The Selecter fronted by Gaps Hendrickson and the one and only Pauline Black, hits include "On My Radio".

Ska is a music genre that originated in Jamaica in the late 1950s, and was the precursor to rocksteady and reggae. Ska combined elements of Caribbean mento and Calypso with American Jazz and Rhythm and Blues. It is characterised by a walking bass line accented with rhythms on the upbeat. In the early 1960s, Ska was the dominant music genre of Jamaica and was popular with British Mods. 

Music historians typically divide the history of Ska into three periods: the original Jamaican scene of the 1960s (First Wave); the English 2 Tone Ska revival of the late 1970s (Second Wave); and the third wave of the Ska movement which started in the 1980s (Third Wave) and rose to popularity in the US in the 1990s.

Mods, initially a small group of clothes-focused 1950s working class young men insisted on clothes and shoes tailored to their style, which emerged during the Jazz boom. Early mods watched French and Italian art films and read Italian magazines to look for style ideas. By the summer of 1966, the mod scene was in sharp decline but a Mod revival started in the late 1970s in the United Kingdom. Thousands of Mod revivalists attended scooter rallies in locations such as Scarborough and the Isle of Wight. This revival was partly inspired by the 1979 film Quadrophenia and by Mod-influenced bands such as The Jam, who drew on the energy of New Wave music.

The British Mod revival was followed by a revival in North America in the early 1980s, particularly in Southern California, led by bands such as The Untouchables. The mod scene in Los Angeles and Orange County was partly influenced by the 2 Tone Ska revival in England, and was unique in its racial diversity, with black, white, Hispanic and Asian participants. The 1990s Britpop scene featured noticeable Mod influences on bands such as Oasis, Blur, Ocean Colour Scene and The Verve.

From the Jam, The Beat, The Selecter & Bad Manners are all UK Ska & Mod bands who have seen decades in the music industry racking up many top 10 hits!

So join us and let's make history!]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[295]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Millennium Square]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[2 Aug 2014 4:00pm]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/9675.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/9675.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[5381]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Leeds Pride 2014]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[The 9th annual Leeds Gay Pride event in the city.

The Committee have chosen this years theme to reflect the ongoing push for change and equality and recognise the legalisation to allow same sex marriage in the United Kingdom. Love&Marriage will feature strongly in our campaign and shows as we celebrate this important milestone in LGB&T rights.

Its time to buy a hat!

This year, we are pleased to introduce Gay Leeds Legends Kira & Degsie as your Parade Stage hosts as well as inviting back the one and only Miss Orry on Main Stage - flying back from Gran Canaria to join her is Chelsea from Ricky's Cabaret Bar.

Starting in Millennium Square at midday, the parade stage officially kicks off Leeds Pride with speakers and a selection of performances. Then join the parade through Leeds as it winds its way down to Briggate or "Gay Leeds" where the party continues.

The main stage in the heart of the LGBT community will showcase even more local stars as well as popular LGBT scene performers, camp cabaret, a headliner and our ever popular dance session. 

We are the UK's fastest growing LGB&T pride and the biggest
annual street event in the City of Leeds. With your support we hope to continue delivering a top class pride for Leeds. Here is just a taster of what's to come...

Stooshe 
Your headline act for Main Stage at this years
LeedsPride. Since 2010, this UK trio have belted out top 20 hit after hit with single - "Slip" holding steady as a Summer 2013 anthem. MOBO & Brit Award nominated, get set for our BIGGEST headline act to date. 

Lonnie Gordon
3 UK top 40 hits // 3 US Number 1's. Philliadelphia (USA) born Lonnie Gordon is a 90's Dance legend working with names such as BlackBox. Her most memorable hits include "Gonna Catch you" & "Happenin all over again". Lonnie is about to release her new single "Horny". She will be joining the Main Stage line up at Leeds Pride 2014.

Katrina
(Katrina & the Waves) Katrina is an American musician, author and former lead singer of English pop rock band Katrina and The Waves. The hit song "Walking on Sunshine", billed in the top 10 of charts across the globe and is still the most played summer track on radio in the US, 28 years after its release. In 1997, Katrina restored British faith in the  Eurovision Song Contest- breaking through political & block voting with the anthem "Love Shine a Light", giving the United Kingdom its first win in Decades. Katrina will headline the Parade Stage at Millennium Square before this years big parade sets off! 

More acts will be confirmed in the run up to the event.

There's much more info on the website and facebook page which is constantly updated in the run up to Leeds Pride.

Image: Miss Orry]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[295]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Millennium Square]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[5380]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Leeds Pride]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[3 Aug 2014 ]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/5381_0.png]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/5381_0.png]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10140]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Leeds Festival]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[Headliners Arctic Monkeys with an exclusive Festival headline set in England and Wales join Courteeners, The 1975, You Me At Six, SBTRKT, Warpaint, Netsky, Annie Mac, Royal Blood, Hozier, Architects, Issues, Pusha T and Krept & Konan across the weekend.]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[2745]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Bramham Park]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[22 Aug 2014 - 26 Aug 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10140.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10140.jpg]]></image_original></item><item><event_id><![CDATA[10268]]></event_id><event_title><![CDATA[Thoughtbubble Festival]]></event_title><description><![CDATA[This year's festival runs from 9th - 16th November in association with the 28th Leeds International Film Festival, with our centre-piece convention taking place on 15th & 16th November....

We'll have further updates regarding ticket pre-sales opening, and exhibitor registration for the convention will be posted to Facebook as soon as all the details are confirmed.

The first wave of guests for the 2014 festival, include:

Natasha Allegri (creator of Bee & Puppycat, and writer/illustrator of the Adventure Time: Fionna & Cake comics);

Andy Belanger (creator of Black Church, and artist on IDW's hit series Kill Shakespeare);

Emily Carroll (award-winning webcomic creator, whose work has featured in Vertigo's The Witching Hour and Dark Horse's Creepy);

Becky Cloonan (artist on Dark Horse's The True Lives of the Fabulous Killjoys, and recently self-published Demeter);

Danielle Corsetto (creator of webcomic Girls With Slingshots, and the Adventure Time graphic novels Playing With Fire and Pixel Princesses);

Adam Hughes (award-winning cover artist for titles such as DC's Wonder Woman, Fairest, Catwoman, and Power Girl);

Jeff Lemire (creator of acclaimed series Essex County, The Underwater Welder, Sweet Tooth, and Trillium);

Matteo Scalera (artist on Image's Dead Body Road and Black Science, and Marvel's Secret Avengers and The Incredible Hulk);

Scott Snyder (creator of Vertigo's American Vampire and The Wake, and writer on DC's Batman and Superman Unchained);

Allison Sohn (artist on trading and sketch cards for Star Wars, LotR, Indiana Jones, and Women of Marvel, cover artist for Dynamite Comic's Red Sonja);

Jillian Tamaki (creator of webcomic Supermutant Magic Academy, graphic novels Gilded Lilies, Indoor Voice, and co-creator of Skim and This One Summer);

We'll have many more guests to announce in the coming months, so keep an eye on the website as the festival draws ever closer!

The official festival image for this year is by the awesome Annie Wu, and we love the 1920's vibe she's brought to it. Even ghostly apparitions reading over your shoulder can't spoil a good comic!

We're working hard to make this year's Thought Bubble even bigger and better than those that came before it, and we hope you'll join us in celebrating the best creative medium in the whole dang world come November!]]></description><place_id><![CDATA[797]]></place_id><place_title><![CDATA[Various Locations]]></place_title><organiser_id><![CDATA[2737]]></organiser_id><organiser_title><![CDATA[Thought Bubble Comic Art Festival]]></organiser_title><event_date><![CDATA[9 Nov 2014 - 16 Nov 2014]]></event_date><image_thumbnail><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/styles/190x190/public/images/events/10268.jpg]]></image_thumbnail><image_original><![CDATA[http://www.leedsinspired.co.uk/sites/default/files/images/events/10268.jpg]]></image_original></item></objects></response>